[音乐响起--字幕精校中--By Persisan]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVID J. MALAN：好的，这是CS50，这是第九周，
DAVID J. MALAN: All right, this is CS50, and this is week nine,
我们合成过去几周的那一周
the week where we synthesize the past several weeks
以及过去的几种语言，包括HTML，CSS和JavaScript
and the past several languages, including HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
最近，再加上一些SQL，再加上一些Python。
most recently, plus some SQL, plus some Python.
确实，本周的目标是合成所有这些材料
Indeed, the goal for this week is to synthesize all of those materials
进入一个被广泛描述为网络编程的主题。
into a topic that's broadly described as web programming.
为了公平起见，上周我们确实介绍了一些JavaScript，
Now to be fair, last week we did introduce a bit of JavaScript,
而且您确实可以通过JavaScript进行编程，
and via JavaScript can you indeed program,
但这完全是客户端，因为我们上周使用了JavaScript。
but it was entirely client side as we used JavaScript last week.
这周我们将重新介绍服务器端组件
This week we'll reintroduce a server side component
并最终将浏览器（即所谓的客户端）捆绑在一起，
and indeed end by tying together the browser, the so-called client,
和Web服务器，即任何Web应用程序的后端。
and the web server, the backend of any web application.
因此，要到达那里，让我们考虑一下我们来自哪里。
So to get there, let's consider where we came from.
上周，为了提供您的任何静态网页，
Last week in order to serve up any of your static web pages,
从某种意义上说，它们是静态的，一旦您编写它们，它们就不会改变
static in the sense that once you write them, they don't change
从根本上讲，他们不会特别接受用户输入
fundamentally, they don't particularly take user input
除非您添加一点JavaScript，
unless you add a little bit of JavaScript,
我们仅使用称为http-server的简单程序。
we use just this simple program called http-server.
现在在Mac和Windows上还有此命令的其他等效项
Now there are other equivalents of this command on Macs and Windows
和Linux等平台，但出于我们的目的，
and Linux and other platforms, but for our purposes,
http-server程序实际上只是运行Web服务器。
http-server the program literally just runs a web server.
网络服务器只是软件的一部分
And a web server is just a piece of software
就TCP调用而言，它一直在侦听端口80或端口443，
that's constantly listening on port 80 or port 443 in terms of TCP recall,
它只是在监听连接。
and it's just listening for connections.
每次您的浏览器连接时，它都会查看URL
And any time your browser connects it looks at the URL
您访问过的位置，也许还有一些参数
that you visited and maybe some parameters that you
可能是通过该URL提供的，或更普遍地是通过表单提供的，
may have provided via that URL, or more generally via a form,
然后提供网页，并提供某种输出。
and it then serves up a web page, optionally with some kind of output.
但是，当然，上周的一切实际上只是静态的。
But of course everything last week really was just static.
只是HTML文件，CSS文件，也许
It was just HTML files, CSS files, and maybe
一些JavaScript文件或其中的JavaScript。
some JavaScript files or JavaScript within.
但是在浏览器的要求范围内
But within the requests that your browsers
发送到该Web服务器，重新调用HTTP标头。
were sending to that web server, were recall HTTP headers like this.
因此，在http-server程序正在执行的操作中，
And so among the things that program http-server was doing,
在任何网络服务器正在做的事情中，
and among the things any web server was doing,
正在从上到下分析该虚拟信封的内容，
was analyzing the contents of that virtual envelope, top to bottom,
从左到右，试图了解您的浏览器或朋友是什么
left to right, trying to understand what is it your browser or your friend
或您的家人（如果您分享了您的）
or your family member if you shared your you
与他们的网址正在尝试请求。
URL with them was trying to request.
如果这些HTTP标头的第一行只是斜线，
And if the first line of those HTTP headers was just get slash,
那就意味着给我默认的网页。
that just means give me the default web page.
按照惯例，回想一下，通常意味着专门给我文件
And by convention, recall that typically means specifically give me the file
称为索引点HTML。
called index dot HTML.
如果您按字面意义输入索引，那可能已经很明确了
That might have been explicit if you literally typed index
点HTML到浏览器的URL栏中，这将更加明确地表明
dot HTML into the browser's URL bar, that would even more explicitly tell
服务器为您提供该文件。
the server to give you that file.
但是回想一下，我们也曾在google.com上玩过
But recall we also played with google.com
特别是其搜索功能。
and specifically its search functionality.
回想一下，我们上周手动构建了
And recall that we manually last week constructed
看起来像这样的网址，然后我们将其复制
a URL that looked like this, and then we replicated it
带有实际的HTML表单，提交时的结果使我们
with an actual HTML form, the result of which when submitting it brought us
URL的形式为HTTPS冒号斜杠，www.google.com斜杠搜索，
to a URL of the form HTTPS colon slash slash, www.google.com slash search,
问号q等于猫。
question mark q equals cats.
而上周的http服务器相当简单。
And last week http-server is fairly simplistic.
它仅提供静态内容。
It only served static content.
因此，它几乎忽略了诸如这些URL参数之类的东西。
So it was pretty much ignoring things like these URL parameters.
但是，如果您实际上想编写一个后端Web服务器，
But if you actually want to write a backend web server,
像google.com本身这样的网络应用程序，您
a web application like google.com itself, you
需要能够分析该虚拟信封的内容，
need to be able to analyze the contents of this virtual envelope,
可以这么说，找出用户想要的路径或路线。
figure out what path the user wants, or route, so to speak.
斜线搜索将是此处的路线。
Slash search would be the route here in question.
然后，您必须确定确切的HTTP参数是什么。
And then you have to figure out what the exact HTTP parameters are.
Q，在这种情况下，其值为“ cats”。
Q, in this case, whose value is "cats."
因此，某个地方的某人必须编写解析该字符串的代码，从而弄清楚
So someone somewhere has to write code that parses that string, figuring out
您想进行斜线搜索，然后，让我们忽略问号。
that you want slash search and then, OK, let's ignore the question mark.
让我们声明一个名为q的变量，并给它一个值“ cats”。
Let's declare a variable called q, and let's give it a value of "cats."
就像图片中的某处一样，需要有代码来执行此操作。
Like somewhere in the picture there needs to be code that does that.
今天，我们向您介绍该代码。
And today we introduce you to that very code.
我们将向您介绍一个名为Flask的库。
And we're going to introduce you to a library called Flask.
从技术上讲，Flask也称为框架。
And technically speaking, Flask is also called a framework.
框架是一种做事的方式。
A framework is a way of doing things.
这是组织代码的一种方式，这是一种方式
It's a way of organizing your code, it's a way
编写代码的过程更具体地是
of writing your code that more specifically is
以及您应该如何使用该库。
just how you should use this library.
现在为什么Flask存在？
Now why does Flask exist?
还有其他选择。
And there are alternatives.
好吧，Flask的存在只是为了诚实地简化许多任务
Well, Flask exists just to honestly simplify a lot of tasks
对你和我来说，很快就会变得很无聊。
that for you and me would just get pretty boring pretty quickly.
想象一下，如果您想要的话，那会是多么烦人
Imagine how annoying it would be if you wanted
为此实施一些新的网站或一些新的移动应用程序，
to implement some new website or some new mobile application for that matter,
而且您每次都必须编写代码来分析此类文本
and you had to write code that analyzed text like this every time
只是弄清楚用户的输入是什么。
just to figure out what the user's input is.
如果您可以只调用一个函数，那不是很好吗？
Wouldn't it be nice if you can just call a function, the equivalent
获取字符串或获取int，并编写其他函数
of get string or get int, and let some other function written
别人看那个文本，弄清楚参数是什么
by someone else look at that text, figure out what the parameters are
以及它们的价值是什么，只需将它们以易于使用的方式交给您
and what their values are, and just hand them to you in nice easy to use
变量。
variables.
这就是Flask为您做的事情之一。
So that is one of the things that Flask does for you.
它分析了这些虚拟信封的内部，
It analyzes the insides of these virtual envelopes,
弄清楚用户输入是什么，弄清楚
figures out what the user input is, figures out
路线是什么，例如斜杠搜索或斜杠索引点HTML
what the route is, like slash search or slash index dot HTML
用户想要的，并使其更容易
that the user wants, and makes it more easily
可供您使用的程序员。
available to you, the programmer.
从某种意义上说，这是一个框架，通常
And it's a framework now in the sense that typically when
您将像今天一样创建基于Flask的网络应用程序，
you create, as we will today, a Flask based web application,
您通常将以这种方式组织文件和文件夹。
you're going to typically organize your files and folders in this way.
这就是我所说的框架。
And this is what I mean by framework.
框架不仅仅是具有可调用功能的库。
Frameworks are not just libraries where they have functions that you can call.
他们通常有说明要使用这些功能的文档，
They typically have documentation that says, to use these functions,
您还应该以这种方式组织文件和文件夹。
you should additionally organize your files and folders in this way.
也许最简单的Flask应用程序将具有以下文件：
And perhaps the simplest Flask application would have these files:
应用程序py，这是我们所做的全部工作
application dot py, which is where really all of our effort
将要编写代码，在这种情况下是在Python中，
is going to go in writing code, in this case in Python,
要求点文本，它只是一个枚举的简单文本文件，
requirements dot text, which is just a simple text file that enumerates,
从上到下，每行一个，您还需要其他哪些库
top to bottom, one per line, what are the other libraries that you
想要在您的应用程序中使用静态
want to use in your application, static, which
将会是一个包含字面意义的文件夹
is going to be a folder that literally contains
静态文件，例如gif，jpeg，ping，CSS
static files like your gifs, your jpegs, your pings, your CSS
文件，您的JavaScript文件，您上周编写的任何文件，
files, your JavaScript files, any of the files you wrote this past week,
现在，他们将进入该静态文件夹，最后进入模板。
now they're going to go into this static folder, and lastly templates.
模板将成为您更多HTML的去向。
And templates is going to be where more of your HTML goes.
我们将看到与上周的区别。
And we'll see what the distinction is there versus last week.
简而言之，如果您想制作一个Web应用程序，
So in short if you want to make a web application,
不是网站，而是需要用户输入的Web应用程序，
not a website, a web application that takes user input,
产生用户输出，也许与数据库对话，
produces user output, maybe talks to a database,
可能会发送电子邮件，可能还会进行其他任何事情，
maybe sends emails, maybe does any number of other things,
以编程方式您有一个Web应用程序
programmatically you have a web application
并将在此处使用称为Flask的框架。
and will use this framework here called Flask.
还有其他选择。
And there are alternatives.
在Python世界中，有一个名为Django的框架，
In the world of Python there is a framework called Django,
在PHP的世界中，有一些框架，例如Symfony和Laravel等。
in the world of PHP there are frameworks like Symfony and Laravel and the like.
在Java，C Sharp和其他语言中，也有类似的框架。
In Java, in C sharp, and other languages there are similar frameworks.
因此，这只是现有框架类型的代表。
So this is just representative of the types of frameworks that are out there.
但是，在深入研究一些实际代码之前，可能会有所帮助
But it's perhaps helpful to know before we dive into some actual code
这些框架倾向于实现某些设计模式。
that these frameworks tend to implement certain design patterns.
同样，设计模式只是描述方式的一种理想方式
A design pattern is, again, just a fancy way of describing ways
人类编写代码。
that humans write code.
可以说过去几十年来，
Suffice it to say over the past many decades,
很多人最初都是独立工作的
a lot of humans working initially independently
不断地解决相同的问题，
kept solving the same problems again and again,
他们意识到，哇，我注意到了模式
and they realized, wow, I'm noticing patterns
我如何解决这个项目的问题
in how I'm solving a problem for this project
对于这个项目和另一个。
and for this project and another.
一旦人类程序员注意到了这些模式，
And once human programmers noticed these patterns,
他们可以通过写书来形式化他们，
they might formalize them by writing a book,
通过写博客文章之类的，然后
by writing a blog post or the like, and then
给他们起一个名字，一个推荐给其他人采用的设计模式。
give them a name, a design pattern that they recommend that other people adopt.
为什么？
Why?
只是因为它可以帮助您组织代码
Just because it helps you organize your code instead
将所有代码放在一个大文件中，
of putting all your code in one massive file,
好吧，如果我们在这里放一些代码，在这里放一些代码，
well maybe if we put some code here, some code here,
我们可以更有效地与他人合作
we can collaborate more effectively with others
并在维护越来越大的项目时保持理智。
and just keep ourselves sane when maintaining bigger and bigger projects.
所以Flask实现了众所周知的
So Flask implements what's generally known
作为MVC设计模式或范例。
as an MVC design pattern or paradigm.
MVC仅指代表模型，视图，
MVC just refers to an acronym representing model, view,
和控制器。
and controller.
这些都是技术性的术语，最终
And these are sort of technical terms of art that at the end of the day
我们将看到相对简单。
we'll see are relatively simple.
控制器将成为您编写大多数Python代码的地方。
Controller is going to be where you write most of your Python code.
它是控制您的Web应用程序的一个或多个文件。
It is the file or files that control your web application.
因此，过去，无论何时我们编写C程序或Python程序，
So in the past, any time we've written a C program or a Python program,
您实际上一直在编写控制器代码。
you have in effect been writing controller code.
我们只是从未在上面贴上标签。
We just never slapped that label on it.
今天也将有一个我们称为视图的视图，即MVC中的V。
There's also going to be today what we'll call a view, the V in MVC.
而视图只是指人类可以看到的所有内容，例如HTML，CSS，
And view just refers to all of the stuff that a human views, the HTML, the CSS,
更一般而言，用户界面。
more generally the user interface.
任何涉及用户的内容都将被描述
Anything involving the user is going to be described
作为应用程序视图的一部分。
as part of your application's view.
但同样，您（程序员）编写的任何代码，
But again, any of the code that you, the programmer, write,
可以说，这是您控制器的一部分。
that's part of your controller, so to speak.
最后是所谓的模型，MVC中的M。
And then lastly is the so-called model, the M in MVC.
这通常指的是什么技术，什么服务，什么软件
And this generally refers to what technique, what service, what software
您正在使用的数据。
you're using for your data.
因此，也许这是一个SQL数据库，或者那是一个CSV文件。
So maybe that's a SQL database, maybe that's a CSV file.
该模型引用您的应用程序正在使用的数据。
The model refers to the data that your application is using.
再一次，这些术语都没有引入
So again, none of these terms are introducing
上周或前几周我们无法完成的事情。
things we couldn't have done last week or in weeks prior.
我们通过引入MVC作为首字母缩写词或设计模式来做的所有事情
All we're doing by introducing MVC as an acronym or a design pattern
只是在Flask的方法上打上标签，
is just to slap a label on the approach that Flask,
反过来，许多程序员，无论您是
and in turn many programmers, whether you're
在设计基于Web的应用程序时使用Python或其他语言。
using Python or other languages used when designing web based applications.
有其他选择，但这是最受欢迎的选择之一，也许
There are alternatives but this is among the most popular and perhaps
最简单的。
among the simplest.
就像我们用任何一种语言所做的一样，
So much like we've done with any language,
让我们看一下最简单的网络
let's take a look at the simplest possible web
您可以使用此库或称为Flask的框架编写的应用程序。
application you might write using this library or framework called Flask.
事实证明，如果您填充一个名为application dot py的文件
It turns out if you fill a file called application dot py
使用这些代码行，您刚刚制作了第一个Web应用程序。
with these lines of code, you have just made your very first web application.
正如我们将要看到的，现在它并不会引起太多兴趣，
Now it's not going to do much of interest, as we'll see,
但这几乎是您需要的最少代码量
but this is the minimal amount of code pretty much that you need in order
编写一个Web应用程序，该程序是您一旦开始
to write a web application that is a program that once you start
它只会不断地听着，听着，听着
it is going to just be constantly listening and listening and listening
用于使80或443端口上的TCP请求从人们的浏览器中传入，
for TCP requests on port 80 or 443 to come in from people's browsers,
包括您自己的。
your own included.
然后你就可以写
And then now you have the ability to write
响应这些用户的代码。
code that responds to those users.
那我是什么意思呢？
So what do I mean by this?
好吧，让我们继续前进，看看实际效果
Well, let's go ahead and see this in action
并开始编写一些我们自己的第一个程序。
and start writing some of our own very first programs.
我将切换到CS50 IDE，我们将在这里继续使用。
I'm going to switch over to CS50 IDE, which we'll continue using here.
我不会再运行http-server了。
I'm not going to run http-server anymore.
相反，我们将使用Flask代替该服务器。
Instead we're going to use Flask which will take the place of that server.
我将继续，让我们首先创建一个非常简单的文件。
And I'm going to go ahead and let's create a very simple file first.
我要继续，实际上，让我们这样做。
I'm going to go ahead and, actually let's do this.
我将首先创建一个目录。
I'm going to first create a directory.
因此，我将创建一个名为Hello的目录，
So I'm going to create a directory called Hello,
然后我将进入cd。
and I'm going to cd into Hello.
和往常一样，如果您打开文件浏览器
And as always, if you open your file browser
您会在左上角看到相同的内容，但总的来说，
you'll see the same thing at top left, but in general I'll
专注于命令行。
focus on the command line.
现在，我在Hello目录中，让我继续创建文件。
And now that I'm in the Hello directory, let me go ahead and create a file.
我将其保存在Hello中，糟糕，我将其保存在Hello中。
And I'll save this in Hello, whoops, I'll save this in Hello.
让我继续打这个电话，比如说，
And let me go ahead and call this, let's say,
应用程序点py，然后再次将其保存在Hello目录中。
application dot py, and again, saving it in the Hello directory.
好的，如果我输入ls，我会在那里看到它，并且它目前是空的。
All right if I type ls, I'll see it there and it's currently empty.
因此，让我继续一下，几乎复制了刚才的部分代码。
So let me go ahead and pretty much copy some of that code from a moment ago.
让我继续，从Flask库中导入一些内容
Let me go ahead and from the Flask library import something
在这种情况下，称为Flask（大写F），这只是他们的约定。
called Flask, capital F in this case, which is just their convention.
让我继续并导入一个称为render的东西。
And let me go ahead and also import something called render.
实际上，我们什至不这样做。
Actually let's not even do that yet.
首先让我们保持这种简约。
Let's keep this minimalist at first.
为了将此文件转换为成熟的Flask应用程序，
In order to turn this file into a full-fledged Flask application that
是我自己的服务器，我将继续定义一个名为
is my own server, I'm going to go ahead and define a variable called
按惯例的应用程序。
app by convention.
我要调用这个Flask函数，
I'm going to call this Flask function, and I'm
有点奇怪的是要使用下划线，下划线，名称，
a little weirdly going to pass an underscore, underscore, name,
下划线，下划线。
underscore, underscore.
现在，我们仅过去一次看到过该特殊变量。
Now we've only seen that special variable once in the past.
回想一下，当我说，嗯，您应该
And that, recall, was when I said, well, you should either
在Python文件底部调用main来调用您的main函数，
call main at the bottom of your Python file to call your main function,
或者您可以在您所说的话中做这件令人讨厌的事情，如果名字相等，
or you can do this annoying thing where you say, if name equals,
等于main然后调用main。
equals main then call main.
因此，无论我们过去为什么使用此特殊变量，
So no matter why we used that in the past, this special variable,
下划线，下划线，名称，下划线，下划线
underscore, underscore, name, underscore, underscore essentially
指当前文件的名称。
refers to the name of the current file.
所以这行代码说，Flask，打开当前文件
So this is a line of code that says, Flask, turn the current file
到一个应用程序中，即一个Web应用程序
into an application, that is a web application that
将监听浏览器的请求。
will listen for browsers' requests.
现在，在我的文件中，我必须告诉Flask我的路线是什么。
Now in my file I have to tell Flask what are my routes.
路由就是一个URL。
A route is simply a URL.
因此，斜杠或斜杠索引点HTML或斜杠
So slash, or slash index dot HTML, or slash
搜索或您今天在网址中看到的其他任意数量的路径
search, or any number of other paths that you see in today's URLs
在网站上。
on websites.
为了在Flask中做到这一点，我说了应用程序点路由，引用了反引号斜杠。
And to do this in Flask I say app dot route, quote unquote slash.
现在，这是我们之前在Python中从未见过的东西，
Now, this is something we've not seen in Python before,
但这实际上是Python功能。
but this is actually a Python feature.
每当您在这样的函数开头看到at符号时，
Any time you see an at sign at the beginning of a function like this,
这就是所谓的Python装饰器。
it's what's called a Python decorator.
对于我们今天的目的，这只是一种特殊的方式
And for our purposes today, this is just a special way
将一种功能应用于另一种功能。
of applying one function to another.
但是，让我暂时将其留在那
But let me leave it at that for now and just
说使用Flask的习惯是，一开始你
say that the convention when using Flask is that at first you
定义您的路线，例如斜线默认路线，
define your route like your slash default route,
然后定义一个函数。
then you define a function.
您可以随意调用该函数，
And the function can be called whatever you want,
但按照惯例，您应该打电话给
but by convention you should probably call
它适合所讨论的实际路线。
it something appropriate for the actual route in question.
同样，人们倾向于将默认路由称为索引。
And again, humans tend to call the default route your index.
因此，我将继续调用该函数索引。
So I'm going to go ahead and call this function index.
接下来，让我继续做一些愚蠢的事情，例如“ Hello，world，
And below that, let me just go ahead and do something silly like Hello, world,
从字面上返回该字符串。
literally returning that string.
接下来，让我们继续看看这里到底发生了什么。
And let's go ahead and see what exactly happens here after doing that.
现在，如果我输入ls，请继续进入我的Hello目录中，
Let me go ahead now and in my Hello directory if I type ls,
再次注意，我只有一个文件，应用程序点py。
notice that again, I only have one file, application dot py.
为了启动我的服务器，因为它是Flask应用程序，
In order to start my server today, because it's a Flask application,
我不想使用http服务器，而是
I do not want to use http-server, I instead
要运行命令Flask run。
want to run the command Flask run.
所以Flask是一个图书馆。
So Flask is, yes, a library.
但安装时它也附带一个程序
But it also comes with a program when you install it
在Mac或PC或IDE上也可以启动Flask应用程序。
on your Mac or PC or the IDE that lets you start a Flask application as well.
您将在此处看到一些神秘的输出。
And you'll see some cryptic output here.
但就像http-server一样，您会看到URL
But just like http-server, you'll see the URL
当前正在运行的应用程序。
of your currently running application.
如果我继续单击该URL并在另一个标签中打开它，瞧，
And if I go ahead and click this URL and open it in another tab, voila,
我看到了我的第一个动态Web应用程序。
I see my very first dynamic web application.
这只是打印Hello，世界。
It's only printing Hello, world.
实际上，如果我使用Chrome的查看页面源功能，
And in fact, if I go to Chrome's view page source feature,
请注意，它甚至不是完整的HTML。
notice that it's not even full-fledged HTML.
这是字面上的文字，但这是因为我没有
It's literally text, but that's because I didn't
麻烦返回任何实际的HTML了。
bother returning any actual HTML yet.
因此，让我们做到这一点。
So let's do that.
让我们实际上更正确地执行此操作，而不仅仅是返回
Let's actually do this more properly and not just return
一些任意的文本字符串。
some arbitrary string of text.
让我停止服务器，让我现在专注于此。
Let me stop the server and let me focus now on doing this.
默认情况下，我声称的称为slash的路由
By default the route called slash I've claimed
表示您应该返回一个称为索引点HTML的文件。
means that you should return a file called index dot HTML.
好吧，让我们暂时假设它存在。
Well let's assume for the moment it exists.
我该如何退货？
How do I go ahead and return it?
从技术上讲，我将继续进行渲染
Technically I'm going to go ahead and render
一个称为索引点HTML的模板。
a template called index dot HTML.
为了使用此功能渲染模板，
And in order to use this function render template,
我也需要从Flask库中导入它。
I need to import it from the Flask library as well.
因此Flask再次是一个库，具有很多功能。
So Flask again is a library, comes with a lot of functions.
其中第一个称为Flask本身。
The first one of which is called Flask itself.
这就是将其激活为Web应用程序的原因。
That's what activates this as a web application.
渲染模板是生活中的另一功能
Render template is another function whose purpose in life
是要找到一个称为索引点HTML的文件，抓取其内容，
is to go find a file called index dot HTML, grab its contents,
这样您就可以将其退回。
so that you can then return it.
因此，它的精神类似于几周前在Python中使用open和read。
So it's similar in spirit to using open and read in Python a few weeks ago.
但这也将为我们提供其他一些新颖的功能。
But it's going to give us some other fancy features as well.
但是让我现在进入命令行，输入
But let me go now into my command line, type
提醒我们，我们只有应用程序点py。
ls to remind us that we only have application dot py.
我不想在同一目录中创建索引点HTML。
I don't want to create index dot HTML in the same directory.
回想一下，烧瓶有一些组织上的建议
Flask, recall, has certain organizational recommendations
像这样在这里我实际上应该放置索引点
like this here whereby I should actually put index dot
HTML和我今天所有的HTML文件都在我的名为template的文件夹中。
HTML and all of my HTML files today onward in my folder called templates.
因此，让我们做到这一点。
So let's do that.
让我继续，使用make dir enter创建一个名为template的目录。
Let me go ahead and make a directory called templates with make dir enter.
如果现在输入ls，您将看到我有一个模板目录。
If I type ls now you'll see that I have a templates directory.
现在，让我继续创建一个称为索引点HTML的新实际文件。
Now let me go ahead and create a new actual file called index dot HTML.
让我将其存储在模板，目录中，然后继续
Let me store that in my templates, directory and now let me go ahead
和一些非常熟悉的东西。
and something pretty familiar.
在这一点上，我们已经做了很多次，
We've done this many times at this point whereby we just
弹出一个快速的HTML页面。
whip up a quick HTML page.
我将在此处给出HTML的文档类型。
I'll give my doc type of HTML up here.
让我有我的HTML标签。
Let me have my HTML tag.
我的语言默认为英语。我在这里
My language will be English by default. Down here I'm
将拥有我页面的头。
going to have the head of my page.
在头里面，我将有一个标题。
Inside the head I'll have a title.
我将其称为“ Hello”。
I'm going to call this Hello.
在这里，我将拥有自己的身体。
Down here I'll have my body.
在体内，我只想说你好，世界。
Inside the body I'm just going to say Hello, world instead.
因此，从上周开始实际上仍然没有任何进展。
So still no progress really from last week.
但是，现在让我回到应用程序点py，
But let me now go back to application dot py,
提醒我们，我们刚刚返回了函数调用，
remind us that we've just now returned the function call,
呈现索引点HTML的模板，再一次，此函数呈现模板，
render template of index dot HTML, and again, this function, render template,
将要打开该文件，抓住其中的所有字节
is going to go open that file, grab all of the bytes inside of it
并最终通过此行返回它们。
and return them ultimately via this line.
所以现在让我继续并再次运行Flask，让我继续
So now let me go ahead and run Flask run again, let me go ahead
并单击我的IDE的URL，瞧，同样的事情。
and click on my IDE's URL, voila, same thing.
但是现在，如果我打开Chrome的查看源功能，
But now if I open up Chrome's view source feature,
现在注意，我已经返回了完整的网页。
notice now that I've returned a full-fledged web page.
再说一遍，从根本上讲并不是那么有趣
So again, not really fundamentally that interesting,
但是我现在已经迈出了这一小步，以生成我想要的任何HTML。
but I've taken this baby step now toward generating any HTML that I want.
因此，让我们变得更加有趣。
So let's make this more interesting.
我一直声称，Web编程当然有这种方式
I've claimed all along that there is this way of course with web programming
通过URL接受用户输入。
to take user input via the URL.
那么我们如何去做呢？
So how can we go about doing that?
好吧，我继续提出这个建议。
Well, me go ahead and propose this.
让我继续在这里写另一行代码
Let me go ahead here and write an additional line of code
做这样的事情。
that does something like this.
让我声明一个名为的变量，实际上让我们这样做。
Let me declare a variable called, actually let's do this.
渲染模板之后，事实证明您可以传入0个或多个命名参数。
After render template, it turns out you can pass in 0 or more named arguments.
这些参数的名称完全取决于您，
And the names of these arguments are entirely up to you,
到目前为止我们还没有看到。
and we haven't seen that thus far.
到目前为止，任何时候我们使用别人的功能，
Thus far in the past, any time we've used someone else's function,
您必须检查文档或讲义
you had to check the documentation or the lecture notes
弄清楚你有哪些可用的参数
to figure out what were the available arguments you
可以传递给此功能。
could pass into this function.
但这与渲染模板不同。
But that's not true with render template.
功能更强大。
It's a little more powerful.
因此，如果我想从我的应用程序点py文件中传递用户名，
So if I want to pass a user's name from my application dot py file,
回想一下，我们将开始调用我的控制器，
which, recall we're going to start calling my controller,
我可以说，给我一个名为name的变量。
I can say, give me a variable called name.
我希望这个人的名字的价值是什么？
What do I want the value of this person's name to be?
好吧，我真正希望它是等效的
Well really what I want it to be is the equivalent
问号后面有什么，对不对？
of whatever is after that question mark, right?
从根本上说，从URL获取用户输入的唯一方法是，
The only way, fundamentally, to get user input from a URL, we've seen,
问号后面是什么。
is whatever is after the question mark.
而且我不想要q，我不想要猫，
And I don't want q, and I don't want cats,
我要姓名等于David或姓名等于Brian。
I want name equals David or name equals Brian.
那我该怎么办呢？
So how can I do that?
好吧，让我继续说一下：名字等于
Well, let me go ahead and say this: name equals
请求点args点get，引用不带引号的名称，
request dot args dot get, quote unquote name,
并让我另外在该文件的顶部添加请求。
and let me Additionally add request to the top of this file.
那我在做什么呢？
So what am I doing?
当我从Flask库中导入其他请求变量时，
When I import this other request variable from the Flask library,
这使我可以访问HTTP请求及其任何参数
this gives me access to the HTTP request and with it any parameters
可能已经在URL中了。
that might have been in the URL.
Flask为我做的是解析该URL。
And what Flask does for me is it parses that URL.
它计算出q是什么，猫是什么，名字是什么，大卫是什么。
It figures out what is q, what is cats, what is name, what is David.
问号后面有什么，Flask会为我解析
Whatever is after the question mark, Flask parses it for me
并将其作为变量返回给我，我就可以访问这些变量
and hands it back to me as variables, and I can get access to those variables
通过调用请求点参数作为参数，
by calling request dot args for arguments,
点get，然后是参数名称
dot get, and then the name of the parameter
我想从URL获得。
that I want to get from the URL.
现在，如果我保存此代码，让我回到索引点HTML，
So now if I save this, let me go back to index dot HTML,
这就是为什么今天以后将此文件称为模板的原因。
and here is why this file today onward is now called a template.
就像人类世界一样，
A template, just like in the human world,
是一种框架，您可以在其中插入其他值。
is kind of a framework into which you can plug other values.
它是一个模板，您可以根据自己的工作。
It's a template that you can base your own work on.
就像可以作为建筑物基础的蓝图。
It's like a blueprint that you can base a building on.
因此，模板通常具有特殊的语法
So templates typically have special syntax
通过它您可以插入一些值。
via which you can plug in some values.
而且恐怕语法与我们以前看到的相比还是有点新的，
And I'm afraid the syntax is slightly new versus past things we've seen,
但是如果您使用两个大括号，就好像不是
but if you use two curly braces, as though one weren't
在C和其他情况下足够糟糕，左右两个大括号，
bad enough in C and in other contexts, two curly braces, left and right,
您可以告诉Flask的渲染模板函数插入
you can tell Flask's render template function to plug
在右边，您可以看到的任何变量的值
in right there the value of any variable that you
已作为函数中的这些参数之一传递到渲染模板中
have passed into render template as one of these arguments in the function
称呼。
call.
因此，现在让我继续并再次运行Flask run以重新启动Web服务器。
So let me go ahead now and run Flask run again to restart my web server.
让我继续打开此URL，它现在看起来非常愚蠢。
Let me go ahead and open this URL, and it looks pretty stupid right now.
您好，没有。
Hello, None.
但是请记住，None在Python中是一个特殊的值。
But recall that None is a special value in Python.
这意味着没有任何价值。
It means something has no value.
所以你知道我能做什么？
So you know what I could do?
原来，让我回到这里，如果我回到我的网址，
It turns out that, let me go back over here, if I go back to my URL,
然后让我放大，以便您可以看到它，让我继续并添加一个斜线，
and let me zoom out so you can see it, let me go ahead and add a slash,
问号，而不是q等于猫，因为现在已经无关紧要了，
question mark, and not q equals cats because that's irrelevant now,
但是名字等于大卫。
but how about name equals David.
让我放大一下。
And let me zoom in on that.
我所添加的只是斜杠问号名称等于David。
All I've added is the slash question mark name equals David.
让我继续并按Enter键，瞧，现在我
Let me go ahead and hit Enter, and voila, now I
有一个网页，上面写着“ Hello David”。
have a web page that says Hello David.
实际上，如果我查看页面源代码，请注意HTML
And indeed if I view my page source, notice the HTML
已动态生成。
has been dynamically generated.
我的IDE上没有文件说“你好逗号大卫”，
There is no file on my IDE that says Hello comma David,
而是动态地插入了它。
rather it's been dynamically plugged in.
并请注意，这可能会改变。
And notice this can change.
如果我继续将名称更改为Brian，请输入，
If I go ahead and change the name to Brian, enter,
他的页面发生了变化，当然，如果我现在查看页面源
his page changes, and of course if I view the page source now
好像我有一个名为index dot HTML的文件
it's as though I had a file called index dot HTML
字面上有布莱恩（Brian）的名字。
that literally had Brian's name in it.
但是不，我的模板中只有那个占位符。
But no, there's just that placeholder within my template instead.
我可以清理这个。
And I can clean this up.
请注意，如果没有名称价值，这看起来很愚蠢，
Notice it looked pretty stupid if there was no value for name,
但结果是请求点args，点
but it turns out the request dot args, dot
get函数采用第二个可选参数。
get function takes a second optional argument.
如果我不知道是否有价值
If I don't know if there's going to be of value
我想给它一个默认参数，
and I want to give it a default argument,
我对get函数的第二个参数实际上可以是默认值。
my second argument to the get function can actually be the default value.
因此，如果我现在继续进行，让我继续进行，请重新运行Flask。
So if I go ahead now, and let me go ahead rerun Flask.
现在让我继续操作，并在不使用name参数的情况下重新加载。
And let me go ahead now and reload with no name argument.
现在您看到Hello逗号世界的默认值，但是如果我回到那里
Now you see a default value of Hello comma world, but if I go back up there
并重新输入我的名字，现在不需要默认名称了。
and put my name back in, now it doesn't need the default.
我看到了人类实际输入的内容。
I see what the human actually typed in.
那么，这里发生的事情，好吧，如果您考虑
So what's going on here, well, if you consider
当您输入cats并按Enter键时，google.com在做什么？
what google.com is doing when you type in cats and hit Enter,
该网址中的q等于猫这个词被传递给google.com，
that word q equals cats is being passed to google.com in the URL,
Google正在运行某些程序，也许是带有Flask的Python，
Google is running some program, maybe it's Python with Flask,
可能是其他某种语言正在分析网址，
maybe it's some other language that's analyzing the URL,
抓住q等于猫，然后他们实质上是在搜索数据库
grabbing q equals cats, and then they're searching their database essentially
为猫的关键字，然后它们是动态的
for a keyword of cats, and then they're dynamically
生成显示所有这些图片并进行搜索的HTML
generating the HTML that shows you all of those pictures and search
猫的结果。
results of cats.
没有网页，Google服务器上没有HTML文件
There is no web page, there's no HTML file on Google servers
经常有大量的猫。
that constantly has a big list of cats.
就像肯定没有人维护一个非常大的HTML
Like there's certainly no human maintaining a really big HTML
文件整天都充满了图像标签和猫。
file just filled with image tags and cats all day long.
可以说这都是动态生成的。
Suffice it to say that's all dynamically generated.
即使有了这个简单的例子，我们现在也可以看到
And even with this trivial example, we see now
也许我们正在抓紧这种能力的表面。
perhaps that we're scratching the surface of that very capability.
好吧，让我在这里暂停，看看是否有任何疑问或困惑，
All right, let me pause here and see if there are any questions or confusion,
因为任何框架都可以同时完成很多工作
because it's a lot all at once given that with any framework
您通常必须先学习约定
you typically have to learn the conventions first
然后您就可以开始工作了。
and then you can start to be productive.
布莱恩：是的，所以在您调用渲染模板函数时，
BRIAN: Yeah, so in your, when you called the render template function,
有人问为什么您不需要在模板中说斜杠索引点HTML，
someone asked why don't you need to say it's in templates slash index dot HTML,
为什么只说索引点HTML？
and why did you just say index dot HTML?
DAVID J. MALAN：好问题。
DAVID J. MALAN: Good question.
这是“仅因为”答案之一。
This is one of those "just because" answers.
渲染模板功能已经以这种方式实现
The render template function has been implemented in such a way
它假定您的文件位于模板目录中。
that it assumes that your files are in the templates directory.
从技术上讲，您可以通过重新配置应用程序来覆盖该设置，
You can technically override that by reconfiguring the application,
但是默认的，实际上是约定
but the default and indeed the convention
就是将这些文件放在模板中。
is to just put those files in templates.
好问题。
Good question.
圣地亚哥？
Santiago?
圣地亚哥：为什么当您声明应用程序，应用程序点路线，
SANTIAGO: Why when you declare the app, app dot route,
您必须将正斜杠作为对此的论点吗？
you have to include the forward slash as an argument to that?
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，那为什么还要加上正斜杠？
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so why do you have to include the forward slash?
在Flask中，这就是告诉Flask使用的方式
That is the way, in Flask, of telling Flask, use
此路线的以下功能。
the following function for this route.
而斜线也许是最简单，当然也是最基本的路线
And slash is perhaps the simplest, certainly most basic route
您可以定义。
that you could define.
有点没有其他字眼了。
It's sort of the absence of any other words.
因此，您必须在其中加斜杠，否则服务器将不会
So you have to put slash there because otherwise the server won't
知道如果您访问点com，斜杠之类的东西，仅此而已。
know what to do if you visit something dot com, slash, and that's it.
我们可以更改此通知。
We can change this notice.
我可以将其更改为我想要的任何内容。
I can change this to anything I want.
让我停止我的服务器，然后将其更改为斜杠，好像我在
Let me stop my server, and let me change this to slash secret, as though I'm
在我的网站上创建一个秘密URL。
creating a secret URL on my website.
让我继续并重新运行Flask run。
Let me go ahead and rerun Flask run.
让我打开此URL，然后注意会发生什么。
Let me open up this URL, and notice what happens.
什么都没发生。
Nothing happens.
找不到，我访问斜线时为404。
Not found, 404 when I visit slash.
Chrome只是令人讨厌。
And Chrome is just being annoying.
如今，为了简单起见，它一直隐藏着斜线，
It's hiding the slash just for simplicity these days,
但即使您没有将其视为人类，也可以使用斜线。
but the slash is there even though you're not seeing it as the human.
但是，如果我更改此设置并转为斜杠秘密，那么我们将再次看到该页面。
But if I change this and go to slash secret, then we see that page again.
因此，该应用程序仅在应用程序点路由处起作用
So that app at app dot route function just
让您定义应该与以下功能关联的路线。
lets you define what route should be associated with the following function.
还有其他问题吗？
Other questions?
是的，交给索菲娅。
Yeah, over to Sophia.
SOPHIA：模型，它现在是HTML文件的一部分吗？
SOPHIA: The model, is it a part of the HTML file now?
就像名字一样，我想是数据，它是用HTML文件编码的吗？
Like the name, I guess as the data, is it encoded with an HTML file?
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，目前我想
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, at the moment I would
认为我们还没有真正的模型。
argue we don't really have a model yet.
就像没有数据库一样，没有CSV文件，
Like there's no database, there's no CSV file,
所以现在我们只在使用C（控制器）和V（视图）视图。
so right now we're just playing with C, controller and V, view.
那完全没问题。
And that's totally fine.
只有当我们拥有成熟的应用程序，就像我们今天很快将要使用的那样
It's only when we have a full-fledged application like we soon will today
M确实发挥了作用。
that really the M comes into play.
但是，这又是一种合理的人可能会不同意的观点。
But again, this is sort of, reasonable people might disagree.
它们只是约定，不是硬性规定。
They're just conventions, they're not hard, fast rules.
好吧，这有点愚蠢，为了
All right, so this is a little silly, that in order
要被我的网站打招呼，您必须有足够的资金
to be greeted by my website you have to have the wherewithal
知道您必须在URL栏中键入自己的名字，对吗？
to know that you have to type your own name into the URL bar, right?
没有人这样做。
No one does that.
但这不是网络通常的工作方式。
That's just not how the web typically works.
相反，我们发现自己是人类填写表格。
We instead find ourselves as humans filling out forms.
因此，让我们更进一步，以这种方式进行实际改进
So let's take this one step further and actually improve things in such a way
我们实际上有一个表格。
that we actually have a form instead.
因此，让我继续执行此操作。
So let me go ahead and do this.
我将继续创建另一个文件。
I'm going to go ahead and create another file.
让我继续执行此操作。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我进入我当前所在的模板目录
Let me go into my templates directory where I currently
只有索引点HTML，让我复制这个文件，
only have index dot HTML, and let me just copy this file,
索引点HTML，现在又称为问候点HTML。
index dot HTML, into another one right now called greet dot HTML.
就是说，我想要我的问候文件，最终，让我继续
And that is to say I want my greet file, ultimately, let me go ahead
并在我的编辑器中打开它，最后打招呼
and open this in my editor, greet ultimately
将要完成索引之前的工作。
is going to do the job that index was a moment ago.
我将改变索引的行为
And I'm going to change the behavior of index
点HTML即可具有实际形式。
dot HTML to instead have an actual form.
所以我要继续删除它，我
So I'm going to go ahead and delete this and I'm
要做一个形式动作等于一条路线
going to do a form action equals, a route
叫做slash greet，尚不存在，但我很快就会下注。
called slash greet, which doesn't exist yet, but I wager it soon will.
我将先使用get，然后在此表单中使用
I'll use get initially, and then inside of this form
让我继续，给我自己输入一个名称，该名称实际上是
let me go ahead and give myself an input whose name is going to be literally
名字，因为我想要人类的名字。
name, because I want the human's name.
因此，红色名称是标签的名称。
So the red name is the tag's name.
此刻以绿色表示的名字是相关人员的名字，
Name in green at the moment is the name of the human in question,
虽然有点混乱。
although a little confusingly.
然后让我继续说这个字段的类型将是文本。
And then let me go ahead and say the type of this field will be text.
然后让我继续给自己输入类型，等于提交，
And then let me go ahead and give myself an input type, equals submit,
所以我有一个提交按钮，它的价值
so I have a submit button, and the value of that
将是默认值。
will be whatever the default is.
现在让我回到应用程序点py，
So now let me go back to application dot py,
让我回到我的Hello目录。
let me go back to my Hello directory.
确保您不在模板目录中运行Flask run。
Make sure you don't run Flask run in your templates directory.
确保只在应用程序点py文件所在的位置运行它。
Make sure you only ever run it where the application dot py file is.
让我运行这个文件。
Let me run this file.
让我继续打开它，瞧。
Let me go ahead and open it now, and voila.
我的斜线路线，默认路线通知，
My slash route, the default route notice,
已更改为此HTML表单。
has changed to be this HTML form.
而且，如果我查看Chrome中的视图源，
And if I look at the view source of that in Chrome,
您会确切地看到我刚刚输入的内容。
you'll see exactly what I just typed.
因此，表单没有任何动态。
So there's nothing dynamic about the form.
这确实是硬编码的。
That is indeed hard coded.
那里没有占位符。
There's no placeholders there.
但是请注意，此表格是我事先设计的，
But notice that this form has been designed in advance by me to go
使用get进入斜线欢迎路线。
to the slash greet route using get.
那么我该如何实现呢？
Well how do I implement that?
好吧，让我真正进入我的应用程序
Well let me actually go into my application
现在，因为您会注意到我是否键入我的名字David，然后单击Submit，
now, because you'll notice if I type in my name, David, and click Submit,
未找到。
not found.
因为请注意，斜杠打招呼不存在。
Because notice that slash greet does not exist.
那不是我的应用程序中定义的路由。
That is not a defined route in my application.
因此，让我回到服务器，再继续下面的操作，
So let me go back to my server, and let me go ahead down below,
让我们做类似的事情。
and let's just do something similar.
应用程式点路线，引用不加引号，斜线表示欢迎。
App dot route, quote unquote, slash greet.
因此，让我们给自己第二条路。
So let's give myself a second route.
让我继续定义功能
Let me go ahead and define the function that
用户访问斜线时打招呼。
should be called when a user visits slash greet.
再说一次，您可以随心所欲地调用它，但让我们保持自己，
And again, you can call it anything you want, but let's keep ourselves,
让我们保持简单，就称它为同一个东西
let's keep things simple and just call it the same thing
作为路线，尽管这不是必须的。
as the route, though again, that's not a requirement.
然后在我的问候功能中，我想做什么？
And then in my greet function, well what do I want to do?
让我继续说，返回“要做的事”。
Let me go ahead and say, return "to do."
我还没做
I haven't done it yet.
但是同样，像在C和Python中一样，采取一些小步骤，
But again, as in C and in Python, take baby steps,
并确保到目前为止，您的代码基础仍然有效。
and just make sure the basics of your code are working so far.
让我重新运行Flask运行。
Let me rerun Flask run.
让我打开我的URL。
Let me open my URL.
现在让我尝试再次填写此表格。
And now let me try filling out this same form again.
实际上，我有点烦恼自动完成功能弹出了，
And actually I'm a little annoyed that the autocomplete is popping up,
但我们可以稍后将其关闭。
but we can turn that off later.
让我继续，单击“提交”，然后瞧瞧。
Let me go ahead and click Submit, and voila.
现在招呼路线确实存在。
Now the greet route does exist.
请注意，斜杠问候语是功能齐全的。
Notice that slash greet is fully functional.
不再找不到它了，但是它当然没有做任何有用的事情，
It's not a not found anymore, but it's of course not doing anything useful,
因此，“要做”。
hence the "to do."
好吧，没关系。
Well that's OK.
让我回到这里停止服务器。
Let me go back here and stop the server.
让我改为招呼一个称为greet dot HTML的模板。
And let me instead have greet render a template called greet dot HTML.
但是请记住，问候点HTML是我开始的地方。
But recall that greet dot HTML is where I started.
现在是具有此占位符的文件。
It is the file now that has this placeholder.
所以我想我所能做的就是移动我以前使用的代码
So I think what I can do is just move the code that I was using earlier
对于不再需要的索引，因为索引
for index which no longer needs it, because index
点HTML只有硬编码的静态形式，让我继续
dot HTML has only a hardcoded static form, let me go ahead
然后只需将name参数移到我的问候路线即可。
and just move the name parameter to my greet route instead.
让我继续并重新启动服务器。
Let me go ahead and restart my server.
让我继续打开我的URL。
Let me go ahead and open my URL.
让我继续输入我的名字，然后点击Submit和voila。
Let me go ahead and type my name in and hit submit, and voila.
现在我们有了两条功能齐全的路线，斜线和斜线打招呼，
So now we have two fully functional routes, slash and slash greet,
第一个恰好只显示
the first of which just so happens to only display
静态形式，其中第二种实际上恰好是在做某事
the static form, the second of which actually happens to do something
更加有趣并向用户打招呼。
more interesting and greet the user.
我刚才提到，用户界面让我有点生气
And I mentioned a moment ago, I was kind of annoyed by the user interface
在这里，这是在记住谁之前输入过他们的名字的事实，
here, the fact that it's remembering who typed their name in before,
我只是以错误的方式摩擦我，从而泄漏了一点隐私。
I just, rubbing me the wrong way, leaks a little bit of privacy.
因此，让我实际进入索引并回想一下
So let me actually go into my index and recall
HTML中还有其他属性（例如自动完成功能）等于off。
that there's other attributes in HTML like autocomplete equals off.
我也可以进行自动对焦，使该文本字段闪烁的光标
I can also do autofocus to give that textfield the blinking cursor
默认情况下。现在让我继续并重新启动
by default. And now let me go ahead and restart
进行此更改后我的服务器。
my server after making this change.
让我继续并重新加载。
Let me go ahead and reload.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
我们可以做的更好。
We can do a little better.
我们还添加一个占位符，用引号引起来，
Let's also add one of those placeholder, quote unquote name,
只是为了让我的访客更清楚
just so that it's a little more clear to my visitors
哦，你要我在这里输入我的名字，大卫。
that, oh, you want me to type my name, David, here.
自动完成功能现已关闭。
Autocomplete is now off.
我单击提交，瞧。
I click Submit, voila.
现在，我们有了一个可以正常使用的Web应用程序。
We now have a working, if simple, web application.
好吧，那又有什么呢？
All right, so what were the additions there?
与以前相同的应用程序，但是我们增加了第二条路线
Same exact application as before, but we added a second route
和第二个模板，以便一个表单可以将数据提交到另一条路由
and a second template so that one form could submit data to the other route
反而。
instead.
所以让我在这里暂停一下，看看在我们之前是否有任何疑问或困惑
So let me pause here to see if there's any questions or confusion before we
继续对此进行迭代。
continue to iterate on this.
问题或困惑。
Questions or confusion.
说话者1：我想知道它如何等于双引号名称，
SPEAKER 1: I'm wondering how that came equals double quote name,
该名称等于您以后指定的名称吗？
is that equivalent to the name that you later specified?
DAVID J. MALAN：是的。
DAVID J. MALAN: It is.
我将通过现在更改来演示这一点。
And I'll demonstrate this by changing that now.
我之所以称它为“名字”，是因为我们确实在谈论人类的名字，
I called it name just because we're indeed talking about humans' names,
但我可以随便叫这个。
but I could call this anything I want.
因此，例如，以我的形式，我正在收集此人的名字。
So for instance in my form I'm collecting this as the person's name.
但是我可以将其更改为第一个下划线名称，例如，
But I could change it to first underscore name, for instance,
如果我只在乎他们的名字。
if I only care about their first name.
让我更改占位符以使其清楚
Let me change the placeholder to make clear
我只想要他们的名字。
that I only want their first name.
现在让我转到我的应用程序点py。
Let me now go to my application dot py.
让我获得第一个下划线名称HTTP参数，然后
Let me get the first underscore name HTTP parameter, and then
在我的模板中，迎接点HTML，让我将其更改为第一个下划线名称。
in my template, greet dot HTML, let me change this to first underscore name.
实际上，我需要再进行一次更改。
And actually I need to make one more change.
我还需要将其更改为第一个下划线名称。
I need to change this to first underscore name as well.
因此，您不得不在各处重复自己，这有点烦人，
So it's a little annoying that you have to repeat yourself all over the place,
但是它们的含义不同。
but they mean different things.
在应用程序点py的上下文中，这是一个参数
In the context of application dot py, this is a parameter
我正在传递我的模板。
that I'm passing into my template.
在此get函数的上下文中，这是HTTP参数
In the context of this get function, this is the HTTP parameter
我是从URL抓取的。
that I'm grabbing from the URL.
在我的模板中，这是指
And in the context of my template, this refers
到第一个，这是我的论点
to the first of those, which is the argument I'm
传入渲染模板。
passing into render template.
如果我重新加载服务器，然后让我继续并在此处重新加载表单。
And if I reload the server, and let me go ahead and reload the form here.
让我只输入我的名字。
Let me type in only my first name.
点击提交。
Click submit.
一大堆事情发生了变化，而不是输出方面的变化
A whole bunch of things changed, not in terms of output
但在功能方面。
but in terms of functionality.
您会看到，现在我使用的是第一个下划线名称，而不是名称本身。
And you'll see that now I'm using first underscore name instead of name itself.
有关路线或参数的其他问题或困惑
Other questions or confusion about routes or parameters
在网址，模板中还是其他？
in the URL, templates or otherwise?
不？
No?
好吧，那我就问我们一个问题。
All right, well let me ask a question then of us.
让我继续向下滚动一下以腾出空间。
Let me go ahead and scroll this down just a bit to make room.
再次，这是我的索引点HTML文件。
Here, again, is my index dot HTML file.
它包含一个表格。
It contains a form.
现在是我的问候点HTML文件，其中仅包含
Here now is my greet dot HTML file, which contains just,
你好，逗号等等。
hello comma so and so.
对此设计欠佳的是什么？
What looks poorly designed about this?
我将继续将我的短名字恢复为多一点
I'm going to go ahead and revert just to my shorter names just so a little more
可以立即安装到屏幕上。
fits onto the screen at once.
但是，对此有何设计欠佳？
But what looks poorly designed about this?
我声称这是正确的。
I claim that it's correct.
我们似乎有一个正常工作的Web应用程序。
We seem to have a working web application.
但是，什么是设计不当的争论呢？
But what is poorly designed arguably?
布莱恩：让我们听听彼得的声音。
BRIAN: Let's hear from Peter.
说话者2：嗯，我想你明白了，
SPEAKER 2: Well I guess you're getting it,
因此，URL会公开输入的个人数据，无论
so the URL is exposing the personal data of the input, whatever
他们可能已经放进去了，所以我想我们想用post代替它。
they might have put in, so I guess we'd want to use post instead to hide it.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的收获。
DAVID J. MALAN: Good catch.
所以这段时间我非常刻意，但有点令人担忧
So all this time I have very deliberately but a little worrisomely
在某种意义上一直在泄露URL中的信息
been leaking information in the URL in the sense
现在它可能会被我的浏览器保存，对吗？
that now it's probably going to be saved by my browser, right?
通常，当您在网址栏中输入内容时，
Often when you're typing something to your URL bar,
您可以查看之前搜索过的内容，
you can see what you've searched for before,
您以前去过哪些网站，这是一个很好的用户界面
what websites you've been to before, and that's a good user interface
它的功能在于它可以帮助您键入击键，因为您可以
feature in that it just helps you type your keystrokes because you can just
按Tab键，然后按Enter键以快速完成您的想法。
hit Tab and hit Enter to finish your thought quickly.
但是，如果您不希望别人知道您去了哪里，这是一种侵入性的行为
But it's a little invasive if you don't want people knowing where you went
或您搜索的内容，或者这是一台实验室计算机
or what you searched for or if it's a lab computer
或您的兄弟姐妹也在使用它。
or your siblings are using it too.
有很多原因导致您不希望输入的内容结束
There's a lot of reasons why you don't want your typed input ending up
在该网址栏中。
in that URL bar.
我上周提议，我们可以通过使用来避免这种情况，
And I proposed last week that we can avoid this by using,
你建议的是职位。
what you proposed is post.
确实，让我们做到这一点。
And indeed let's do this.
让我回到索引点HTML。
Let me go back to my index dot HTML.
让我在HTML文件中进行简单的更改，将发布方法更改为。
Let me make a simple change in my HTML file, changing the method to post.
发布将与get几乎相同，
Post is going to be almost the same as get,
但不要将我的参数放在网址中
but instead of putting my parameters in the URL
例如网址中的q等于猫或名字等于David，
like q equals cats or name equals David in the URL,
而是隐喻地将其降低，深化
it's going to instead metaphorically put it lower, deeper
在虚拟信封中。
inside the virtual envelope.
因此它仍然是从浏览器发送到服务器的，
So it's still being sent from the browser to server,
但浏览器不会在网址栏中记住它。
but it's not going to get remembered by the browser in the URL bar.
但是，如果执行此操作，则需要更改控制器。
But if I do this I need to change my controller.
我需要我的Python代码在稍微不同的位置查找
I need my Python code to look in a somewhat different location
做到这一点。
to get at that.
这是一个非常简单的更改。
And it's a pretty simple change.
相反，我必须这样做。
Instead I have to do this.
我必须告诉Flask，斜线打招呼，
I have to tell Flask that the route, slash greet,
实际上将支持一组不同的方法。
is actually going to support a different set of methods.
与其支持默认的get，
Rather than supporting get, which is the default,
我必须传递一个叫做方法的有点神秘的论点。
I have to pass in the somewhat cryptic argument called methods.
然后我必须从字面上传递方法的Python列表
And then I have to pass in literally a Python list of the methods
我希望该列表支持。
I want this list to support.
默认情况下，如果您不使用此参数，则全部
By default if you don't use this argument, all
在这些路线中，第一条和第二条
of these routes, the first and the second,
本质上具有此默认值，方法等于
have essentially this default value, methods equals,
quote unquote进入列表，因此是一个大小为1的列表。
quote unquote get in a list, so a list of size one.
如果您不得不在所有地方键入内容，那会有点烦人，
It would be a little annoying if you had to type that all over the place,
因此默认值仅允许您完全不输入任何内容。
so the default just allows you to just type nothing at all.
但是如果您想支持职位，您确实有
But if you want to support post, you do have
重写此方法，并将get default更改为显式发布。
to override this and change the get default to post explicitly.
而且，您必须从其他变量中获取参数。
And you have to get the parameters from a different variable.
与其使用引用URL中参数的请求点args代替，
Instead of using request dot args which refers to the arguments in the URL,
您必须将其更改为请求点格式。
you have to change it to request dot form.
这些都是可怕的名字。
These are horribly named.
在Flask中，这些全局变量，请求点参数和请求点形式
In Flask, these global variables, request dot args and request dot form
分别参考get和post。
refer to get and post respectively.
更好的名字可能是请求点获取和请求点发布，
Better names might have been request dot get and request dot post,
但这就是我们所拥有的。
but this is what we have.
因此request dot args是用于URL中的get请求。
So request dot args is for get requests in the URL.
请求点形式用于发布请求，其中相同信息被更深层地掩埋
Request dot form is for post requests where the same info is buried deeper
在虚拟信封中。
in the virtual envelope.
在完成这些更改之后，让我继续进行，
So after those changes, let me go ahead and make,
对不起，不要打错，语言错误，烧瓶运行。
sorry not make, wrong language, Flask run.
好吧，让我继续打开我的URL，瞧。
All right let me go ahead and open my URL, and voila.
我要输入David，单击Submit，然后注意其中的魔力。
I'm going to type in David, click Submit, and now notice the magic.
现在这条路还是斜线迎接，但没人
Now the route is still slash greet, but no one
以后使用我的笔记本电脑的人会知道我叫什么名字
who uses my laptop later is going to know what my name was
或我的Google搜索是什么，或我的信用卡号是
or what my Google search was or what my credit card number was
或其他任何我可能在此处输入过的表格（例如我的名字）。
or anything else that I might have typed into a form here like my name.
但是输出仍然可以正常运行。
But the output is still fully functional.
所以这确实是要清楚的是帖子是什么
So this indeed, to be clear, is post is what
每当您远程收集任何东西时，您都会使用
you would use whenever you're collecting anything remotely personal
例如人们的电子邮件地址或他们的信用额度
like people's email addresses, perhaps, or their credit
卡或密码，当然还有其他值，
card, or their passwords, certainly, and other values,
但您可以使用get，因为到目前为止我们一直在使用。
but you can otherwise use get as we've been using thus far.
好吧，让我问一个后续问题，因为我
Well let me ask a follow up question, because I
认为我们仍然可以做得更好。
think we can still do better than this.
从根本上讲索引点HTML的设计
There's something fundamentally about the design of index dot HTML
并迎接感觉不太理想的点HTML。
and greet dot HTML that feels a little suboptimal.
我敢说你们中的几个人在过去一周中注意到了同样的问题
And I dare say several of you noticed this same problem in this past week
当您自己创建一些HTML文件时。
when you were just creating a few HTML files on your own.
有点单调乏味，烦人，凌乱或设计不良
What was a little tedious or annoying or messy or poorly designed
尽你所能从创建这几个HTML中看出
as best you could tell from creating these several HTML
您自己的个人主页的文件？
files for your own personal home page?
布莱恩：聊天表明您在两个HTML之间重复了一些HTML
BRIAN: The chat is suggesting you've repeated some HTML between the two HTML
文件。
files.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，老天，我是说第二份文件，
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, my god, I mean honestly by the second file,
第三文件，第四文件，您可能只是复制和粘贴
third file, fourth file, you're probably just copying and pasting
您以前的文件，然后进行较小的更改，
your previous files and then making minor changes,
这就是您所能做的。
and that's all you could do.
单独使用HTML和CSS，甚至使用JavaScript，
With HTML and CSS alone and even JavaScript,
您不能跨多个页面共享HTML。
you can't share HTML across multiple pages.
过去一周提供静态内容时的唯一选择
Your only option this past week when serving static content
是多余地复制和粘贴该内容。
was to copy and paste that content redundantly.
看看这个。
And look at this.
在我的索引点HTML文件中，我刚刚从第1行到第7行突出显示的所有内容
In my index dot HTML file, everything I've just highlighted from line 1 to 7
恰好与第1行到第7行的所有内容完全相同
happens to be exactly the same as everything from line 1 to 7
在问候点HTML。
in greet dot HTML.
因此，这是Flask或任何Web编程框架提供的另一个功能。
So here's another feature you get with Flask or any web programming framework.
这些本身并不是Flask特有的。
These aren't specific to Flask, per se.
您可以排除常见内容。
You get the ability to factor out common content.
那么我们如何去做呢？
And so how do we go about doing this?
好吧，让我继续执行此操作。
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续创建第三个文件，按惯例在Flask中
Let me go ahead and create a third file that by convention in Flask
被称为布局点HTML。
is called layout dot HTML.
为了安全起见，我将其放入我的模板目录中
And to be safe, to be sure, I'm going to put this in my templates directory
因为它又是一个HTML文件。
because again it's an HTML file.
我将继续复制所有相同的样板，如果可以的话，
I'm going to go ahead and copy paste all of that same boilerplate, if you will,
所有共同点，并删除问候点HTML特有的内容。
all of the commonalities, and delete what was specific to greet dot HTML.
我认为我们正在看的是第1至10行，
And I think what we're looking at, lines 1 through 10,
现在就像是另外两个网页的布局的模板（如果您愿意）。
is now like a template for, if you will, the layout for my other two web pages.
所以您知道什么，让我继续进行。
So you know what, let me go ahead and do this.
让我使用一些特殊的语法并说出块体，然后，有点奇怪，
Let me use some special syntax and say block body, and then, a little weirdly,
在这里结束。
end block here.
所以这是Flask特定的语法或技术上
So this is Flask specific syntax or technically
Jinja特定的语法，这是Flask的一种语言
Jinja specific syntax, which is a language that Flask
正在使用别人写的，这是Flask中的特殊语法，
is using which someone else wrote, this is special syntax in Flask that
本质上说是在这里放置一个占位符。
essentially says put a placeholder here.
在此处放置一个占位符，这样我就可以插入其他HTML。
Put a placeholder here so I can plug in other HTML in just a bit.
那么，我现在该如何使用呢？
So how do I use this now?
好吧，让我转到我的索引点HTML文件，
Well let me go to my index dot HTML file,
让我摆脱所有的冗余，
and let me get rid of all of the redundancy,
沸腾索引点HTML的本质。
boiling down index dot HTML really into its essence.
索引点HTML唯一的特殊之处就是该表单。
The only thing that's special about index dot HTML was that form.
因此，如果我想使用刚创建的布局，请继续
So if I want to use the same layout that I just created, let me go ahead
然后在这里用特殊的语法说出来，扩展布局点HTML，
and say up here using that special syntax, extends layout dot HTML,
然后在这里让我说，如果您愿意，这是我的身体障碍。
and then down here let me say, here is my body block, if you will.
让我稍微缩进一点。
Let me un-indent that a bit.
然后让我在这里结束发言。
And then let me say down here end block.
同样，语法很奇怪，但是思想很相似。
So again, syntax is weird, but the ideas are pretty similar.
这在本质上与我们的头文件几乎相似
This is almost similar in spirit to our header files
在C中，您可以排除一些共同点
in C, where you could factor out some commonalities
并在多个地方重复使用它们。
and just reuse them in multiple places.
这里有点儿幻想，因为您可以
Here it's a little fancier because you can kind of
有这个蓝图，这个布局，从字面上看
have this blueprint, this layout, literally
然后您可以插入其他内容。
that you can then plug different content into.
所以第一行说，嘿Flask，以下文件，索引点HTML，
So this first line says, hey Flask, the following file, index dot HTML,
从本质上继承，它扩展了我的默认布局。
essentially inherits from, it extends my default layout.
那是什么布局？
Well what's that layout?
就是这个
It's this.
请注意，此布局定义了该占位符，任意称为body。
Notice that this layout defines this placeholder, arbitrarily called body.
我可以将其称为x或y或z，但我将其称为body。
I could have called it x or y or z, but I'm going to call it body.
为什么？
Why?
因为这真的就像我身体中100％的内容一样。
Because really it's like 100% of the contents of my body.
因此似乎是个好名字。
So seems like a good name.
然后在索引点HTML中，我现在需要告诉Flask，
And then in index dot HTML, I just now need to tell Flask,
这里有一些您应该插入该占位符的代码。
here comes some code that you should plug into that placeholder.
您可以在此处插入一行或多行HTML代码。
And you can plug one or more lines of HTML code in here.
所以，让我继续保存。
So let me go ahead and save this.
现在让我继续打招呼，类似地删除所有多余的内容，
Let me go ahead now and go to greet, similarly delete all that redundancy,
现在让我在这里再说一遍，扩展布局点HTML，
and now let me go up here and say again, extends layout dot HTML,
然后在这里，我说这是我的身体障碍。
and then down here let me say here is my body block.
让我略微缩进，然后让我说结束
Let me just un-indent this slightly, and then let me say end block
并保存该文件。
and save that file.
所以现在这些HTML文件很快看起来很奇怪。
So now these HTML files are quickly looking weird.
就像这里几乎没有HTML，
Like there's barely any HTML in here, it's
实际上只是文本和怪异的Flask语法，在索引点HTML中也是一样，
really just text and weird Flask syntax, same thing in index dot HTML,
但这又是Web应用程序的价值之一。
but again, this is one of the values of a web application.
如果您拥有Python之类的编程语言，
Where you have a programming language like Python,
您可以排除这些共同点，真正地
you can factor out those commonalities and really
开始像Google和Facebook一样动态地生成页面
start generating pages dynamically just like the Googles and Facebooks
和世界其他地方每天都在做。
and others of the world do every day.
现在让我继续并重新运行Flask run
So let me go ahead now and rerun Flask run
并一如既往地交叉手指，因为我在这里做了很多修改。
and cross my fingers as always because I made a whole bunch of changes here.
让我打开我的URL，到目前为止，看来效果还不错。
Let me open my URL, and voila, seems to be working OK so far.
让我继续，在提交此文件之前，让我向您展示页面源代码。
Let me go ahead and, before I submit this, let me show you the page source.
请注意，它在那里打印的不是很漂亮，
Notice that it's there it's not quite as pretty printed,
像缩进有点差，但是没关系。
like the indentation's a little off, but that's OK.
您的模板应具有良好的样式。
Your templates should be well styled.
模板中的所有内容都应精美缩进。
Everything should be beautifully indented in your templates.
但是如果您的模板是由Flask渲染的
But if your templates are then rendered by Flask
而且空格不是很漂亮，
and the whitespace isn't quite as pretty,
没关系，因为浏览器也不在乎。
that doesn't matter because again, the browser doesn't care.
但是确实，我有一个完整的完整网页。
But indeed, I have a full-fledged complete web page.
让我提交这张表格。
Let me submit this form.
它似乎仍然有效。
It seems to still work.
那是我的绝招。
That's my slash greet route.
我看到的是大卫你好，如果我在这里查看页面源代码，
I'm seeing Hello, David, and if I view page source here,
注意另一个确认表单提交。
notice another confirm form submission.
这实际上是一项安全功能。
This is actually a safety feature.
您不希望网站诱使您像退房一样
You don't want websites tricking you into like checking out
通过邮寄两次使用您的信用卡，所以我
twice with your credit card via post, so I'm
继续，然后单击手动重新加载
going to go ahead and click reload manually
这确认我要重新提交此表单，因为存在
which confirms that I want to resubmit this form because there's
没什么危险的。
nothing dangerous about it.
现在有我打招呼的路线。
There is now my greet route.
因此，这可能会为您节省很多头痛或乏味
So this probably would have saved you all a lot of headache or tedium
或复制粘贴，您上周在工具包中只是没有此工具。
or copy paste, you just didn't have this tool in the tool kit last week.
您不能仅在浏览器中使用HTML和CSS甚至JavaScript来做到这一点。
You cannot do it with HTML and CSS or even JavaScript alone in the browser.
所以这是您的模板真正闪耀的地方。
So this is where you have templates really shining.
您不仅可以让模板使用两个大括号
Not only can you have templates use two curly braces
要插入变量的值，可以使用大括号百分号
to plug in values of variables, you can use this curly brace percent sign
语法并插入其他文件的实际内容。
syntax and plug in actual contents of other files.
ew。
Whew.
有疑问或困惑吗？
Questions or confusion?
布莱恩：有一个澄清的问题。
BRIAN: There was a clarification question.
你能告诉我们什么是[吗？进子吗？]
Could you tell us what is [? Jinja? ?]
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，所以我略过了，因为我
DAVID J. MALAN: Yes, so I skirted over that because I
就像那里有多少个新名词一样让我感到烦恼
was getting annoyed at just like how many new terms there
是当今，坦率地说在Web编程世界中
are today and frankly in the web programming world
我们有点被困住了。
that we're sort of stuck with.
因此，这是代码重用的一个很好的例子。
So this is a good example of code reuse.
那里有很多聪明人
There's a lot of smart people out there, a lot
人解决不同的问题。
of people solving different problems.
如果我们所有人都有点烦人和自大
It would be a little annoying and a little arrogant if all of us
试图解决世界上所有的计算问题。
tried to solve all of the world's computing problems.
因此，Flask的作者决定使用其模板功能
And so the authors of Flask decided that for their template feature
他们不会重新发明轮子，而是想出自己的语法。
they would not reinvent the wheel and come up with their own syntax.
他们会使用别人现有的疯狂语法，如果您愿意的话，
They would use someone else's existing crazy syntax, if you will,
使用双大括号和大括号
that uses the double curly braces and the curly brace
和百分号，以便它们只是结合起来
and the percent signs so that they're just combining
一个人与另一人的语言。
one person's language with another.
这很常见。
And this is so common.
这是一件好事，因为从技术上讲，您
And this is a good thing because technically you
如果您出于某种原因真的是反金贾人，可以使用其他语言，
can plug in a different language if you really are anti-Jinja for some reason,
您只讨厌语法，实际上可以使用其他语法。
you just hate the syntax, you can actually use something else.
因此，这实际上是计算的演示
And so this is actually a demonstration in computing
真正基于组件的设计
of really a component based design where you
可以将不同的软件组合在一起，并具有
can plug different pieces of software together and have
他们仍然可以互操作。
them still interoperate.
我们将在课程的网站上添加指向Jinja文档的链接，
And we'll add to the course's website links to Jinja's documentation,
我们将在模板中看到一点点，您可以使用Jinja做更多的事情。
and we'll see in a little bit what more you can do with Jinja in the template.
再说一遍，Jinja只是真正地引用了双花括号语法
So again, Jinja just refers to really the double curly brace syntax
以及出现在我们模板文件中的大括号百分号语法。
and the curly brace percent sign syntax that appears in our templates files.
好的，打个招呼的最后一个功能。
All right, one last feature when it comes to saying hello.
到目前为止，在应用程序点py中，我一直
Thus far in application dot py, I've been
如果在语法上比较复杂，则在概念上保持一点简单
keeping things a little conceptually simple if complicated syntactically
在我的表单中，有两条不同的路线，一条路线为斜线，
by having two separate routes, one route, slash, for my form,
然后是我实际打招呼的另一条路线
and then another route for my actual greet route that
实际显示信息。
actually displays the information.
但严格来说我可以有点聪明
But strictly speaking I can be a little clever
并结合这些路线，如果只是因为
and combine these routes, if only because if you're
建立一个非常复杂的网站，其中包含很多路线，
building a pretty sophisticated website that's got lots of routes,
如果每条路线都需要两条路线（如果一种形式具有
it's kind of annoying if like every route needs two routes if one form has
提交给另一个。
to submit to another.
因此，让我建议我们加强实施
So let me just propose that we tighten up our implementation
并实际上重用了我们的一条路线。
and actually reuse our one route.
所以，让我继续删除我的问候路线，
So let me go ahead and delete my greet route,
只是因为我在那儿有点多余而感到困扰，
just because it's bothering me that I'm getting a little redundancy there,
让我继续说说我的默认路线，索引，
and let me go ahead and say that my default route, my index,
实际上将同时支持get和post这两种方法。
will actually support both methods, get and post.
因此，我将使用相同的路线，不仅要向用户显示表单，
So I'm going to use the same route, not only to show the user the form,
同时也要向用户问好。
but also to say hello to the user as well.
因此，我需要能够在同一条路线上同时支持get和post。
So I need to be able to support both get and post on the same route.
那我该怎么做呢？
So how am I going to do this?
好吧，让我继续执行此操作。
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
我可以做的是，如果请求点方法等于获取，
What I can do is if request dot method equals equals get,
那么我实际上可以继续在这里执行这一行代码。
then I can actually go ahead and execute this line of code here.
否则，如果请求点方法等于发布，那么我将要做的是
Else if request dot method equals equals post, then what I'm going to do
是这个，返回，渲染模板，打招呼HTML，
is this, return, render template, greet dot HTML,
我将以请求点名称的形式传递
and I'm going to pass in a name of request dot form
点获取，名称，然后是世界的默认值。
dot get, name, and then a default value of world.
没什么新鲜的。
So nothing new.
那只是我刚才删除的代码。
That's just the code that I deleted a moment ago.
但是请注意，我现在正在重复使用相同的路线，
But notice now I'm reusing the same route,
我只是在逻辑上检查我的控制器代码，
and I'm just checking logically in my controller code,
如果可以的话，如果该方法以get的形式出现，
if you will, well if the method came in as get,
继续，只显示表格。
go ahead and just display the form.
如果该方法是作为帖子发布的，请继续与用户打招呼。
If the method came in as post, go ahead and greet the user.
现在为什么要这样做？
Now why is this going to work?
事实证明，每当您访问Internet上的URL时，
Well it turns out, whenever you visit a URL on the internet,
例如HTTP冒号斜杠，www.harvard.edu或yale.edu
like HTTP colon slash slash, www.harvard.edu or yale.edu
或google.com，您一直都在进行获取请求。
or google.com, you have always been making get requests.
实际上，回想一下上周我们查看这些示例HTTP请求时，
In fact, recall last week when we looked at those sample HTTP requests,
和标题，我们上周所做的一切
and the headers, everything we did last week
默认情况下，信封中包含关键字get。
had the keyword get by default in the envelope.
因此，get与表单根本没有任何关系，
So get does not have anything fundamentally to do with forms,
这实际上是默认的HTTP动词
it's actually the default HTTP verb that's
每当您访问任何URL时都使用。
used whenever you just visit any URL.
每当您访问网络上的URL时，默认情况下都会使用get。
Any time you visit a URL on the web you are using get by default.
提交表单时，您可能会像我首先使用的那样使用get，
When you submit a form, you are potentially using get as I did first,
或者您像我第二次那样使用帖子。
or you are using post as I did second.
那么，这里的要点是什么？
So what's the takeaway here?
好吧，让我继续，对我的表格进行一次更改。
Well let me go ahead and make one change to my form.
我确实想通过邮寄方式提交。
I do want to submit via post.
我将提交，尽管不再斜杠打招呼
I'm going to submit though no longer to slash greet
但只是我的默认路线。
but just to my default route.
如果我在这里做了所有事情，让我继续进行Flask run，
And if I did everything right here, let me go ahead and run Flask run,
让我像以前一样打开我的URL，现在我处于斜线位置。
let me open up my URL as before, and I'm at my slash route.
请注意，如果我查看自己的页面源代码，该操作也将以斜线表示，
Notice if I view my page source, the action is going to be slash also,
所以我有点对两个不同的功能使用相同的路由。
so I'm sort of using the same route for two different pieces of functionality.
让我输入我的名字，单击“提交”，瞧，效果很好。
Let me type in my name, click Submit, and voila, amazingly, it worked.
您好，大卫，但我的路线没有改变。
Hello, David, but my route has not changed.
现在，为什么这为什么有用呢？
Now, why is this why is this useful?
可能会或可能不会。
It may or may not be.
这就是您现在拥有的能力，因为如果您可以表达自己
It's just the capability you now have because if you can express yourself
在Python中以编程方式可以区分两个动词
programmatically in Python, you can distinguish between the two verbs
获取和发布传入的HTTP请求中的内容，如果有的话
get and post that are inside of your incoming HTTP request, and if anything
这只是意味着您不需要一遍就通过多条路线
this just means you don't need twice as many routes just to have one thing pass
到另一个，事实证明还有
to another, and it turns out there's also
其他功能源自能够重用相同的路线。
other features that derive from just being able to reuse the same routes.
但是在此之后还有更多。
But more on that down the road.
好吧，关于打招呼，Flask或这些路线有什么疑问吗？
All right, any questions then on saying hello, Flask, or these routes?
不？
No?
好的。
All right.
就像这里的预告片一样，这是一个屏幕截图
Well just as a teaser here, here is a screenshot
几乎是我当时制作的第一个Web应用程序。
of pretty much the very first web application I made back in the day.
当我是一名本科生时，我参与了壁内运动，
When I was an undergraduate, I got involved in intramural sports,
不是运动意义上的，而是计算机科学意义上的。
not in an athletic sense but in a computer science sense.
我自愿为哈佛大学新生建立了第一个网站
I volunteered to actually build the very first website for Harvard's freshman
壁内运动程序，也称为Frosh IM。
intramural sports program, otherwise known as Frosh IMs.
当时我们用纸写下您的名字并通过电子邮件发送
At the time we were using paper to write your names down on and email
解决您的运动选择，
addresses down on, your choices of sports,
我们将走过哈佛中院（哈佛中部的草地），
we would walk across Harvard Yard, the grassy area in the middle of Harvard,
将其滑动到检察官或驻地顾问之一的门下，
slide it under the door of one of the proctors or resident advisors,
瞧，我们已经注册了体育比赛。
and voila, we were registered for sports.
但是没有网站。
But there was no website.
有一个互联网，但还没有网站。
There was an internet but there was no website yet.
所以这是90年代后期。
So this was late 90s.
所以我认为实施起来会很有趣
So I thought it would be fun to implement
相同的想法，用于注册
that same idea of a piece of paper for registering
在网络浏览器中进行体育运动。
for sports in a web browser.
现在，不幸的是，我当时只了解C，也许还了解一些C ++。
And now unfortunately I only knew C and maybe some C++ at the time and a couple
来自其他CS课程的其他语言。
of other languages from other CS courses.
我对网络编程一无所知。
I knew nothing about web programming.
所以我自学了如何在很多程序的帮助下进行网络编程
So I taught myself how to web program with the help of lots
来自朋友的问题和答案。
of questions and answers from friends.
我碰巧使用了一种叫做Perl的语言，最后结果
I happened to use a language called Perl, and the result at the end
这个令人恐惧的设计是这里有很多菜单选项
was this frightening design here with lots of menu options
在这里使用JavaScript和一些图片的顶部
up top that use JavaScript and some images here
和一些CSV文件，这些文件基本上在后端
and some CSV files essentially on the backend that
存储了所有注册数据。
stored all of the registration data.
我当时对数据库一无所知。
I knew nothing about databases at the time.
但这是我第一次涉足网络编程。
But it was my first foray into web programming.
我们第一次休息后会做些什么
And what we thought we'd do after our first break
这是使用HTML，CSS，
here is reimplement the idea of a registration system using HTML, CSS,
和Python以及最终的SQL重新实现相同的想法，
and Python and ultimately SQL to reimplement the same idea,
今天对美学的担心就更少了。
worrying even less today about the aesthetics.
但是，让我们继续前进，在这里休息我们的前五分钟。
But let's go ahead and take our first five minute break here.
当我们回到Frosh IM时。
And when we come back Frosh IMs.
好吧，我们回来了。
All right, we are back.
因此，当前的目标是实现最原始的功能
So the goal at hand is to implement the most primitive of features
是我首先通过此Frosh IM实施的
that I first implemented via this Frosh IMs
几年前的网站，允许学生注册体育比赛。
website years ago, that of allowing students to register for sports.
并注册一项运动，让我们收集每个人的名字，也许
And to register for a sport, let's collect everyone's name and maybe
他们想要注册的运动。
the sport for which they want to register.
那么我们该怎么做呢？
So how are we going to do this?
好吧，让我继续进行操作，仅复制我们之前的示例中的布局
Well, let me go ahead and copy just the layout from our previous hello examples
只是因为它是非常好的样板。
just because it's pretty good boilerplate.
而且我实际上将进行一种更改。
And I'm actually going to make one change.
事实证明，使您的网站非常适合移动设备非常容易
It turns out that it's very easy to make your website pretty mobile friendly
只需添加几行代码即可。
just by adding a couple of lines of code.
特别是在这里，我将继续添加一个名为meta的标签。
In particular in my head here I'm going to go ahead and add a tag called meta.
它会有一个视口的名称。
It's going to have a name of viewport.
视口是指矩形区域
Viewport refers to the rectangular region
定义了大多数Web浏览器的用户界面。
that defines most of your web browsers' user interface.
此meta标签的内容将是初始比例
The content of this meta tag is going to be initial scale
等于1，宽度等于设备宽度。
equals 1 and width equals device width.
最后一个关键字有点神奇。
And this last keyword is kind of the magic.
这个咒语在本质上告诉浏览器
This incantation here essentially tells the browser
无论用户是什么，用户设备的宽度如何
whatever the user's, whatever the width of the user's device
是，假设那是我网页的最大宽度，
is, assume that that's the maximum width for my web page,
它会自动缩放我的字体大小
and it's going to scale my font sizes automatically
根据您使用的是笔记本电脑，台式机还是iPhone，向上或向下
up or down based on whether you're using a laptop or desktop or iPhone
或Android手机或其他设备。
or Android phone or something else altogether.
您还需要做其他事情来使您的网站具有响应能力，
There's other things you need to do to make your websites responsive,
可以这么说，为此使用Bootstrap之类的库会很有帮助，
so to speak, and it's helpful to use libraries like Bootstrap for that,
但这至少可以帮助解决至少字体大小的问题。
But this minimally helps at least address issues of font size.
因此，我也将在这里开始进行介绍。
So I'll start including that here as well.
现在让我进入我的应用程序点py，不幸的是对于Frosh IM来说
Now let me go into my application dot py, which unfortunately for Frosh IMs
是空的。
is empty.
实际上，很明显，在我创建的中断中，应用程序点py为空，
And indeed to be clear, over the break I created, application dot py is empty,
模板目录，在我的模板目录中
a templates directory, and inside my templates directory
只是那个布局点HTML。
is just that layout dot HTML.
因此，我们需要在此处共同完成一些工作。
So we've got a little bit of work to do here together.
因此，让我们开始构建此应用程序。
So let's go ahead and start building out this application.
让我继续从Flask导入Flask函数本身
Let me go ahead and import from Flask the Flask function itself
加上我敢打赌我们需要的渲染模板，
plus render template which I bet we're going to need,
然后还要求我们可能也需要它。
and then also request which we're probably going to need as well.
让我使用以下Flask函数初始化应用程序
Let me initialize the application with this Flask function using
下划线下划线名称。
underscore underscore name.
再说一遍，这实际上就是我们更早开始的方式。
So again, that's literally how we began earlier.
让我们继续，开始定义我们的第一个路线。
And let's just go ahead and start defining our first route.
应用程式点路径，引用反引号斜线。
App dot route, quote unquote slash.
让我定义一个叫做index的函数，但是我可以再次调用它，
Let me define a function called index, but again I could call it anything,
但这是一个很好的约定，只是为了
but that's good convention, and just to get
我开始我真的可以很快地做到这一点，并说返回“要做的事”，
me started I could really do this quickly and say return "to do,"
但是我现在对自己的能力很有信心
but I'm kind of confident now in my ability
至少使用渲染模板。
to at least use render template.
因此，至少让我们渲染一个称为索引点HTML的模板
So let's at least render a template called index dot HTML
显然还不存在。
that admittedly does not yet exist.
因此，让它存在。
So let's make it exist.
让我继续创建一个名为索引点HTML的新文件。
Let me go ahead and create a new file called index dot HTML.
再说一次，我可以随便叫这个
And again I could call this whatever I want,
但是如果这是我的默认路线，
but if this is going to be my default route,
我不妨将我的默认页面称为最常见的默认页面
I might as well call my default page the most common default
名称，即索引点HTML。
name, which is index dot HTML.
让我将其存储在Frosh IMs文件夹和模板文件夹中
Let me store it in my Frosh IMs folder and my templates folder
以便将其放置在正确的位置。
so that it's in the proper place.
在这里，让我继续说，这扩展了我的布局点HTML。
In here, let me go ahead and say that this extends my layout dot HTML.
然后，在这里，我说我的身体将是这里的任何东西，
And then down here let me say my body block will be whatever's in here,
然后我的端块将其关闭。
and then my end block will close that.
在这里，我现在有点不舒服
In here, now I'm feeling a little uncomfortable
我已经写了多少代码，所以让我们在那里做一个“要做的事情”，
with how much code I've written so let's just put a "to do" there,
并确保整个过程都能正常进行。
and let's make sure this whole thing works.
因此，让我返回目录，进行Flask运行，然后输入。
So let me go back into my directory, do Flask run, enter.
好吧，继续并打开此浏览器选项卡，它只是说“要做”。
All right, go ahead and open up this browser tab, and it just says, "to do."
所以我认为我处在一个好地方，确实
So I think I'm in a good place, and indeed
如果我查看页面源代码，则会看到完整的网页，
if I view page source I see a full fledged web page,
包括我们刚刚添加的meta标签，但是在这里要做的事情很多。
including that meta tag we just added, but with just a big to do here.
现在我想做什么？
Now what do I want to do?
我想做的最大的事就是
The biggest thing I want to do is actually
让学生能够注册一项运动。
have students be able to register for a sport.
因此，让我们继续前进，并为自己定义一个HTML表单来执行此操作。
So let's go ahead and define ourselves an HTML form via which to do this.
因此，在索引点HTML模板的主体块内部。
So inside of my body block in my index dot HTML template.
让我们继续，首先将其称为带有H1标签的注册页面，
Let's go ahead and first just call this the registration page with an H1 tag,
然后让我继续，给自己一个表格。
and then let me go ahead and give myself a form.
我的意思是，行动就是极限，让我们保持简单
The action will be, I mean, the sky's the limit, let's keep it simple
只做斜线注册而不是使事情复杂化
and just do slash register rather than complicate things
再次使用相同的路线。
by using the same route again.
让我们将事情保密一些，让我们来发布一种方法
Let's keep things a little private, so let's do a method of post
这样我的室友不知道我正在注册什么运动
so that my roommates don't know what sports I'm registering for or not
正在注册。
registering for.
然后在这里让我们继续询问用户的姓名。
And then in here let's go ahead and ask the user for their name.
因此，让我们继续进行输入，名称等于名称，
So let's go ahead and do an input, name equals name,
此输入的名称将是人为的名称。
where the name of this input is going to be name in the human sense.
该框的类型将是文本，让我们添加一些幻想
The type of that box will be text, and let's add some of the fanciness
像之前一样。
as before.
自动完成功能等于关闭或关闭。
Autocomplete equals off, or oof.
自动对焦，喊声，自动对焦，然后在此处放置一个占位符
Autofocus, whoops, autofocus, and then over here a placeholder
这样它就是名字的自我描述。
so that it's self-describing of name.
好的。
All right.
然后让我继续，给自己一个提交按钮，
And then let me go ahead and give myself a submit button,
输入类型等于Submit，然后添加一个register值，
input type equals submit, and let's add a value of register,
只是为了使网站更加人性化。
just to make the website a little more user friendly.
让我继续并停止我的服务器并重新启动它
Let me go ahead and stop my server and restart it
所以我可以重新加载所有这些更改，然后让
so I can reload all of these changes, and let
我再转到该URL，瞧，我们有了表格的开头。
me go over to this URL again, and voila, we have the beginnings of a form.
它只是在问名字，所以它不存在。
It's only asking for name, so it's not quite there.
因此，我还需要参加一些运动。
So I need to ask for some sports as well.
现在有很多方法可以做到这一点，
Now there's a bunch of ways we can do this,
即使您可能还没有在CS50中看到它们，
and even though you might not have seen them all yet in CS50,
您访问网站时肯定在实际的互联网上使用了它们。
you've certainly used them on the actual internet when you visiting websites.
因此，首先让我们做一个下拉菜单。
So let's do a drop down menu initially.
让我执行所谓的“选择”菜单，因为您选择了一个选项，即名称
Let me do what's called the select menu because you select an option, the name
其中将是“运动”。
of which is going to be "sport."
如果您阅读了文档，请选择菜单
Select menus if you read the documentation
或按照在线教程进行操作，您会发现他们
or follow an online tutorial, you'll see that they
必须有被称为期权的孩子。
must have children called options.
孩子们必须有价值观。
And children must have values.
例如，让我们使用
So for instance, let's use a value of how
关于“躲避球”，这是一种常见的壁内运动。
about "dodgeball," which is a common intramural sport.
然后在选项标签中，您实际上
And then inside of the option tag, you actually
必须说，就像链接一样，人类应该看到的东西。
have to say, much like a link, what the human should see.
所以我也要在这里多余地说躲避球。
So I'm just going to redundantly say dodgeball here too.
让我继续前进，让我的生活更轻松一些。
And let me go ahead and make that my life a little easier here.
让我“做”，“做”，只是为了加快工作速度。
Let me, "to do," "to do," just to speed things up.
让我在这里做一些复制粘贴。
Let me do a little bit of copy paste here.
然后我们将其更改为旗标足球，旗标足球。
And how about we change this one to flag football, flag football.
在这里，让我们做足球。
Over here let's do, say, soccer and soccer.
同样，就像链接一样，可能存在这种双重性，相同的价值，
And again just like links there might be this duality, the same values,
但它们不必相同。
but they don't have to be the same.
但就目前而言，我们将使其保持简单。
But for now, we'll keep it simple.
这就是计算机将看到的内容。
This is what the computer will see.
这就是人类会看到的。
This is what the human will see.
然后在这里，我们将其称为终极飞盘，在这里
And then down here we'll call this ultimate Frisbee and here
同样的东西，终极飞盘。
the same thing, ultimate Frisbee.
好的，现在我有了一个正常工作的下拉菜单。
OK, so now I have a working drop down menu.
因此，让我继续并通过重新启动服务器来证明一切，
So let me go ahead and prove as much by restarting my server,
访问我的相同网址，瞧。
visiting my same URL, and voila.
用户界面有点丑陋，绝对是极简主义，
The user interface is kind of ugly, definitely very minimalist,
但是如果我现在输入我的名字David，请注意默认情况下躲避球
but if I now type in my name David, notice that by default dodgeball
之所以选择，是因为应该选择其中一个选项，但我实际上可以解决该问题。
is selected because one of those options should be, but I can actually fix that.
让我，我不喜欢我强迫所有人的方式
Let me, I don't like how I'm forcing everyone
认为他们必须做躲避球。
to think they have to do dodgeball.
让我在这里做一个选择，例如使用一个空值。
Let me do an option here with an empty value for instance.
我什至可以在这里说些什么
And I can even say something up here, for instance,
就像我们只是说它是什么，体育，所以没有价值。
like let's just say what it is, sports, so, with no value.
因此，这不是实际有效的选择。
So it's not an actual valid option.
让我继续，现在打开我的URL。
Let me go ahead and open my URL now.
好的，现在我在下拉菜单中也看到了运动。
OK, so now I see sport in the dropdown too.
David，运动，好吧，您可以注册运动有点奇怪。
So David, sport, OK, it's a little weird that you can register for sports.
那不是真的。
That's not really a thing.
因此，让我修复该问题。
So let me fix that.
事实证明，如果您阅读了有关选择菜单的文档，
And it turns out if you read the documentation for a select menu,
您实际上可以禁用该选项，也可以默认选择它。
you can actually disable the option and also, let's say, select it by default.
这些只是您的其他属性
So these are just additional attributes that you
会在文档中发现选项标签
would discover in the documentation for the option tag that
现在让我使用户界面更加健壮，以便用户
now let me make the user interface a little more robust just so that users
没有注册“体育”。
aren't registering for "sport."
让我继续做David，现在注意，默认情况下，运动是选中的，
Let me go ahead and do David, and now notice, sport is selected by default,
但它变灰了。
but it's grayed out.
它不再是有效值。
It's not a valid value anymore.
因此，对用户界面进行了较小的改进。
So minor user interface improvement.
躲避球听起来很棒。
Dodgeball sounds amazing.
那不是我今天的壁上运动，但显然是这些天。
That was not an intramural sport in my day, but it apparently is these days.
因此，让我继续进行注册。
So let me go ahead and register for this.
可以，但是当然找不到。
OK, but, of course, not found.
那为什么呢？
Well why is that?
好吧，如果我们看一下我刚到达的网址，
Well if we look at the URL I just ended up at,
我还没有实现我的斜线寄存器路由。
I've not implemented my slash register route yet.
好吧，让我们开始吧。
All right, so let's do that.
为此，我需要返回到应用程序点py，让我们继续
To do that, I need to go back into application dot py, and let's go ahead
并做一些注册骗术。
and do some registration trickery.
App点路由斜杠寄存器，我要定义
App dot routes slash register, I'm going to define
我不妨调用寄存器的功能，
a function that I might as well call register,
但我可以再次将其命名为我想要的任何东西。
but I could, again, call it anything I want.
在此功能中，让我们一开始保持简单。
And in this function let's keep it simple initially.
让我们继续并返回一个名为成功的模板
Let's just go ahead and return a template called success
并假设注册成功。
and just presume that the registration was successful.
实际上，让我继续创建一个名为
And in fact, let me go ahead and create a new file called
Frosh IMs模板目录中的成功点HTML，
success dot HTML in the Frosh IMs templates directory,
让我确保它也扩展了布局点HTML，
and let me make sure that also extends layout dot HTML,
并且它具有块体，并且在良好的情况下，还具有端块。
and that it has a block body, and, for good measure, end block.
然后在这里，我现在将其保持如此简单。
And then down here, I'm going to keep this so simple for now.
您已注册，感叹号。
You are registered, exclamation point.
没有真正为任何人注册任何东西，
Not really registering anyone for anything,
但我要宣称他们是。
but I'm going to claim that they were.
现在，如果我重新运行应用程序，然后回到此处的表单，
So now if I rerun my application, and I go back to my form here,
现在我重新注册David进行dodgeball，然后单击“注册”，呵呵。
and I now re-register David for dodgeball and click Register, huh.
现在是一个错误。
Now it's a bug.
让我在这里暂停一下，只是看看各部分是否装配在一起。
And let me pause here just to see if the pieces are fitting together.
即使我在斜线寄存器中，方法也不允许。
Method not allowed, even though I'm at slash register.
有关如何解决此问题的任何想法？
Any thoughts on how to fix this?
方法不被允许？
Method not allowed?
注意，您甚至可以在我的终端窗口中看到
And notice, you can even see in my terminal window
以红色显示错误消息，状态码405，表示不允许使用方法，
in red an error message, status code 405 which means method not allowed,
这是罕见的，但我确实搞砸了。
which is a rare one but I indeed screwed up.
是的，去圣地亚哥吗？
Yeah, over to Santiago?
圣地亚哥：是的，我认为当您定义
SANTIAGO: Yeah, I think that when you defined
用于读取或注册的应用程序点路由，[音频不清晰]
the app dot route for read, or register, [INAUDIBLE]
您未指定发布方法。
you didn't specify a methods is post.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，因此默认情况下，我的方法都是get，
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so by default my methods are all get,
但是如果出于隐私考虑，我想使用帖子，
but if I want to use post for privacy's sake,
回想一下，我只需要告诉Flask我要您支持的方法
recall that I just have to tell Flask that the methods I want you to support
这条路线是动词或方法的列表，
for this route are this list of verbs or methods,
并且该列表的大小为1，其中仅包含关键字post。
and that list is going to be of size one with just the keyword post in it.
再说一遍，当您遇到这些问题时，您绝对会
So again, when you encounter these issues, which you absolutely will
第一次进行所有这些操作时，
when doing all of this for the first time,
不必过多担心错误消息的细节，而只需担心想法。
don't worry so much about the specifics of the error message, but the ideas.
好像出了什么问题？
Like what's gone wrong?
方法。
Method.
不允许的方法。
Method not allowed.
那是什么意思呢？
What could that mean?
我们谈论的唯一方法是获取和发布，
The only methods we've talked about are get and post,
所以也许那里有一些相关的东西。
so maybe it's something related there.
好吧，有问题的路线是斜线寄存器，
Well the route in question was slash register,
所以也许这与我的报名途径有关，
so maybe it's something related to my register route,
看看这些线索是否可以引导您找到像圣地亚哥这样的解决方案
and see if those kinds of clues can lead you to a solution like Santiago
刚刚提出。
just proposed.
让我继续并重新启动服务器。
Let me go ahead and restart my server.
让我继续并重新加载表格，再次输入David，
Let me go ahead and reload my form, type in David again,
我要选择躲避球，注册，瞧，您已注册。
I'm going to select dodgeball, register, voila, you are registered.
好的。
All right.
我实际上没有注册任何东西，
I'm not actually registered for anything,
但是我觉得现在仍然有错检查错误的机会。
but I feel like there's still a missed opportunity for error checking now.
实际上，让我回到表格上，而不是键入David
In fact, let me go back to my form, not type David
而不选择dodgeball，然后单击注册。
and not select dodgeball and click Register.
好吧，这有点愚蠢。
Well this is kind of stupid.
就像它的主张一样，它说我已经注册，即使我只键入自己的名字，
Like its claim, it's saying I'm registered even if I only type my name,
没有运动，您已经注册。
no sport, you are registered.
因此，这里错过了一些进行错误检查的机会。
So there's a missed opportunity here for some error checking.
因此，至少让我们添加一下。
So let's at least go in and add this.
让我们继续做这样的事情。
Let's go ahead and do something like this.
如果不要求点形式点得到怎么办
How about if not request dot form dot get
名称或要求点形式点获得运动，否则，
name or request dot form dot get sports, or not that,
然后让我继续并返回渲染模板失败点HTML，
then let me go ahead and return render template failure dot HTML,
否则，我将返回成功点HTML。
otherwise I'll return success dot HTML.
所以，现在让我尝试一下。
So let me try this now.
让我重新运行服务器，Flask运行。
Let me rerun the server, Flask run.
让我继续并重新加载表格，不对表格进行任何更改，
Let me go ahead and reload my form, no changes to the form,
但是现在，如果我不合作，然后单击“注册”，
but now if I don't cooperate and I click Register,
好的，现在真的发生了不好的事情。
OK, now really bad things are happening.
这是这500个错误之一。
This is one of those 500 errors.
让我们看看我搞砸了。
Let's see where I screwed up.
内部服务器错误和后续段落的描述性不是很高。
Internal server error and the subsequent paragraph are not very descriptive.
但是，如果我进入终端窗口，这是我的例外
But if I go to my terminal window, here's my exception
Jinja 2例外，这是模板语言，
a Jinja 2 exception, that's the templating language,
找不到故障点HTML。
failure dot HTML is not found.
好吧，那只是因为我犯了一个愚蠢的错误，
All right, well that's just because I made a stupid mistake,
让我停止服务器。
so let me stop the server.
让我继续，现在就复制成功点HTML。
Let me go ahead and copy success dot HTML for now.
让我继续并将其粘贴到此处。
Let me go ahead and paste it in here.
我可能可以将其排除在外，但是我们
And I could probably factor this out, but we're
现在将其简化，并将此故障点称为HTML，
going to keep it simple for now and call this failure dot HTML,
将其放在Frosh IM模板中，保存。
put it in Frosh IMs templates, save it.
现在，让我重新运行服务器。
Now let me rerun my server.
现在让我回去。
Now let me go back.
让我尝试不输入任何内容，然后直接注册，好的，瞧。
Let me try not typing in anything and just registering, OK, voila.
现在，它实际上正在检查。
Now it's actually checking.
如果我回到这里，好吧，我不会输入一项运动，
And if I go back here, name, OK, I'll not type in a sport,
它仍然没有检查。
it's still not checking.
但是这里仍然存在这种黑客行为。
But there's still this kind of hack here.
您知道，您从上周回想起，如果您右键单击或控制点击
You know, you recall from last week that if you right click or control click
在任何网页上的任何内容上，您都可以对其进行检查
on anything in any web page, you can inspect it
在Chrome或您喜欢的浏览器中，
in Chrome or your preferred browser, and that
让您开始浏览HTML。
lets you start poking around the HTML.
看着这个，也许我有点不高兴
And watch this, maybe I'm a little bit upset
比方说，没有网球。
that there's no, let's say, tennis.
壁内运动项目不提供网球，但可以
Tennis is not offered by the intramural sports program, but darn it
我想注册这样的。
I want to register for such.
好吧，再次使用浏览器，没有什么可以阻止我前进，例如，
Well, again, using a browser, there's nothing stopping me from, for instance,
我不知道该怎么做，让我们将极限飞盘换成网球，
I don't know how to do this, let's change ultimate Frisbee to tennis,
并从字面上更改页面上的HTML，将其缩小，
and literally change the HTML on the page, zoom back out,
关闭检查员，哈哈，现在网球是哈佛的一项运动。
close the inspector, ha, ha, now tennis is a sport at Harvard.
所以，现在看我能做什么。
So now watch what I can do.
注册网球，输入我的名字David，voila，注册网球。
Register for tennis, type in my name David, voila, registered for tennis.
正确的？
Right?
我已经入侵了该网站。
I've hacked the website.
好吧，从某种意义上讲，我有点
All right, so in some sense I kind of sort of
这次已经入侵了该网站。
have hacked the website this time.
现在显然我对这些信息不做任何事情
Now obviously I'm not doing anything with this information
目前在服务器上。
on the server at the moment.
我只是盲目地说已注册或未注册。
I'm just blindly saying registered or not registered.
但是请注意我刚刚做了什么。
But notice what I've just done.
实际上，让我们真正注意到我做了什么。
In fact, let's really notice what I've done.
让我继续并再次检查页面，让我进入“网络”标签，
Let me go ahead and inspect the page again, let me go to my network tab,
让我重新提交此表格，然后看看这里发生了什么。
and let me resubmit this form, and watch what happens here.
让我回到这里，让我输入David，让我再次进行此快速修改，
Let me go back here, let me type in David, let me do this quick hack again,
让我继续前进，右键单击“体育”，
let me go ahead and right click on sport,
检查，让我摆脱极限飞盘并将其更改为网球
inspect, let me get rid of ultimate Frisbee and change this to tennis
再次，让我再次将其更改为网球，然后输入。
again, and let me change this to tennis again, enter.
现在，让我进入“网络”标签，从下拉菜单中选择“网球”，
Now let me go to my network tab, select tennis from the dropdown,
然后在这里，让我继续此处，然后单击“注册”。
and then down here, let me go ahead here and click Register.
注意这里发生了什么。
Notice what's going on down here.
与上周一样，您可以看到所有HTTP请求的列表。
Just like last week, you can see a list of all of the HTTP requests.
因此，让我们看一下斜杠寄存器。
So let's look at slash register.
现在让我放大所有这些内容并向下滚动到表单数据
Let me now zoom in on all of this and scroll down to the form data
上周我们没有看到，但是有职位要求。
which we didn't see last week but is there for post requests.
我已经从浏览器David和Tennis合法地发送到服务器。
I have legitimately sent from my browser David and tennis to the server.
程序员现在有责任确保自己
The onus is now on you, the programmer, to make sure
如果不是这样的话，您实际上不会让我注册网球
that you're not actually going to let me register for tennis if it is not
受支持的运动。
a supported sport.
因此，现在需要进行更多的错误检查。
So now there's more error checking necessary.
仅仅相信用户输入了姓名和运动是不够的。
It's not sufficient to just trust that the user typed in a name and a sport.
您不能只检查其中两个都不存在。
You can't just check for the absence of either of those.
现在，我们应该变得更加聪明，并确保
Now, we should really be smarter and make sure
人类浏览器发送的任何运动实际上都存在于哈佛。
that whatever sport the human's browser sent actually exists at Harvard.
您可以想象这很快就会出错，
And you could imagine this going very wrong very quickly,
如果是银行帐户，例如您要存多少钱？
if it's a bank account, like how much money do you want to deposit?
好吧，我只是修改HTML并更改金额
Well I'll just hack the HTML and change the amount of money
我正在存款或提款，对不对？
I'm depositing or withdrawing, right?
您应该无法更改服务器的数据
You should not be able to change a server's data
或数据库，只需更改一些HTML。
or database by just changing some HTML.
在这种情况下，您永远不应该信任您的用户或我自己。
You should never, ever trust your users, or myself in this case.
那么我们如何防御呢？
So how do we defend against this?
好了，这个问题有一个解决方案，实际上给了我们
Well there's a solution to this problem that actually gives us
还有其他一些功能。
some other features as well.
让我继续摆脱这种愚蠢
Let me go ahead and get rid of this silliness
我从字面上对所有这些运动进行了硬编码
where I've literally hardcoded all of these sports
在HTML中，从字面上看，我诉诸于复制和粘贴。
in the HTML, which literally I resorted to copying and pasting.
那应该是我们可能会做得更好的第一个线索。
That should have been the first clue that we can probably do better.
让我改为进入应用程序点py，然后让我进入此处，
Let me instead go into application dot py, and let me go up here,
然后让我定义一个名为Sports的全局变量。
and let me just define a global variable called Sports.
定义常量时，按照惯例将其大写。
I'll capitalize it as is the convention when defining constants.
让我继续说，运动将成为此Python列表。
And let me go ahead and say, the sports are going to be this Python list.
所以我要保持它的美观，并使用
So I'm going to keep it pretty and put it on multiple lines using
方括号，因为它是一个列表。
square brackets because it's a list.
在这里我要说躲避球是一项运动，
Here's where I'm going to say dodgeball as one sport,
旗帜足球是我们的下一个，逗号，足球是我们的第三，排球是第四，
flag football was our next, comma, soccer is our third, volleyball fourth,
最后，我们将合法的终极飞盘保留下来。
and then lastly we'll leave in ultimate Frisbee as legitimate.
这些就是我的运动。
So those are my sports.
现在如何使用该运动列表？
How do I now use that list of sports?
好吧，我可以将它们传递到我的模板中。
Well, I can just pass them into my template.
我可以这样说：体育，或其他任何x或y，
I can say something like this: Sports, or anything, x, or y,
或z，但运动更具描述性，等于运动。
or z, but sports is more descriptive, equals sports.
这就是说，我要在模板中创建
So this is to say, I'm going to create in my template
一个称为运动的变量，其值
a variable called sports, the value of which
将是相同的全局变量。
is going to be that same global variable.
需要明确的是，Flask要求您选择一个名称。
And to be clear, Flask requires that you choose a name.
您不能只参加体育运动，因为Flask只是
You can't just pass in sports because Flask just
不会知道如何处理这样的单个参数。
won't know what to do with a single argument like that.
您必须给这些东西起个名字。
You have to give these things names.
再次，它倾向于导致这种冗余
And again, it tends to lead to this redundancy
在您重复使用相同单词的地方，但右边是您的变量，
where you're reusing the same words, but one is your variable on the right,
另一个是您在左侧模板中使用的名称。
the other is the name you're using in your template on the left.
因此，现在让我们在索引点HTML中进行此操作。
So now let's do this in index dot HTML.
这是模板变得更强大的地方。
Here's where templating gets more powerful.
在Jinja这样的模板中，您不仅左右没有花括号，
In templates like Jinja, you don't just have curly braces left and right,
而且您不仅拥有带有花括号和百分号的块，
and you don't just have the blocks with the curly braces and percent signs,
您甚至有一些简单的编程结构。
you even have some simple programming constructs.
我实际上可以做这样的事情。
I can actually do something like this.
事实证明，我实际上可以做这样的事情。
It turns out I can actually do something like this.
对于运动中的运动而言，这是愚蠢的，
For sport in sports, end for, so it's a little stupid,
您从字面上说结束的语法，然后
the syntax, that you literally say end and then
刚才介词的名字，
the name of whatever the preposition was a moment ago,
但现在让我继续，生成一个价值为
but now let me go ahead and generate an option whose value is
取消引用当前运动，将其关闭，然后在此处
quote unquote the current sport, close, that and then in here
让我再说一遍运动。
let me say sport again.
完毕。
Done.
现在，我在模板中使用了for循环，其语法
Now I have used a for loop in my template, the syntax for which
看起来与Python几乎相同，这是有意为之的，Jinja的作者
looks almost identical to Python, that's deliberate, the authors of Jinja
本质上是借用了Python自己的语法，因此没有太多新信息
essentially borrowed Python's own syntax so it's not too much new information
超载。
overload.
并注意我在做什么。
And notice what I'm doing.
我正在使用这种Jinja语法来迭代Sports变量。
I'm using this Jinja syntax to iterate over that Sports variable.
这是一个for循环，所以我说的是迭代设置运动
It's a for loop, so I'm saying iteratively set sport
等于第一项运动，然后是第二项，然后是第三项，然后
equal to the first sport, then the second, then the third, then
第四，然后是第五。
the fourth, then the fifth.
然后在此块的内部，此for循环，
And then inside of this block here, this for loop,
我在用双花括号将运动插入其中，
I'm using the double curly braces to just plug in the sport there,
在那里插入运动。
plug in the sport there.
Flask的这一功能有什么令人惊奇的地方
And what's amazing about this feature of Flask
反过来，Web框架通常是现在
and in turn web frameworks in general is that now when
我运行Flask run，打开我的URL并转到此表单，瞧，它在那里。
I run Flask run, and I open up my URL and go to this form, voila, it's there.
它是为我动态生成的。
It's dynamically generated for me.
如果我在浏览器中查看页面的来源，
And if I look at my page's source in my browser,
请注意，所有这些选项的确存在。
notice that all of those options are indeed there.
但是我不必手动键入它们。
But I didn't have to type them out manually.
现在，我将其放在一个数组中，并且正在动态生成更多HTML。
I now have it in an array and I'm dynamically generating even more HTML.
节省的钱更强大的是什么
And what's more powerful about that savings
现在我可以进入我的应用程序点py了，让我们
is that now I can go into my application dot py, and let's
不只是检查此值。
not just check for this value.
因此，如果不要求以点名形式获取点名称，即表示如果没有名称，
So if not request dot form dot get name, that was saying if there is no name,
然后这部分是说如果没有运动，
and then this part here was saying if there is no sport,
我为什么不更具体地说，或者运动
why don't I more specifically say, or the sport
用户输入表单不参加体育运动。
that the user input into the form is not in sports.
因此，这是Python变得非常优雅的地方。
So here's where Python gets pretty elegant.
现在，我正在检查两个布尔表达式。
Now I'm checking two Boolean expressions.
是否没有请求点格式点获取名称的情况，
Is it the case that there is not a request dot form dot get name,
还是以用户形式进行的运动
or is it the case that the sport that was in the user's form
不是在全局变量中，运动，那么应该是失败的。
is not in the global variable, sports, then it should be failure.
这样你就可以给我发网球，可以给我发水球，
So you can send me tennis, you can send me water polo,
您可以将任何您想要的运动发送给我。
you can send me any sport you want.
我现在要拒绝它，因为我正在验证您的提交
I am now going to reject it because I am validating your submission
针对服务器端数据。
against server side data.
再说一次，这是主题。
And again, this is thematic.
不幸的是，您永远无法相信用户的输入。
Unfortunately you can never, ever trust user input.
您应该始终假设有些烦人
You should always assume that some annoying
黑客在那里或朋友或兄弟姐妹要去
hacker out there or friend or sibling is going
试图侵入您的程序或使其崩溃。
to be trying to hack into or crash your programs.
但是您可以通过以这种方式进行防御性编程来防御这种情况。
But you can defend against that by programming defensively in this way.
因此，现在举个例子，如果我继续，大卫，躲避球，注册，那行得通。
So case in point now, if I go ahead and David, dodgeball, register, that works.
但是，如果我在进入HTML的位置再次进行这种小技巧，
But if I do this little hack again where I go into my HTML,
我去了这里，例如，我改变了极限飞盘，
I go down here, I change ultimate Frisbee, for instance,
网球，也将其更改为网球，
to tennis, and also change it here to tennis,
缩小，将其关闭，选择网球，输入我的名字，大卫，瞧。
zoom out, close that, choose tennis, type in my name, David, voila.
等一下。
Wait a minute.
该死的。
Damn it.
为什么行得通？
Why did that work?
等一下。
Oh, wait.
好的。
OK.
我没有重新启动服务器。
I didn't restart the server.
它仍然在运行旧代码。
It was still running the old code.
现在我打开它。
Now I open it up.
现在，我们必须再次执行此操作。
Now we have to do this again.
好的。
OK.
现在，我将继续攻击该网站。
Now I'm going to go ahead and hack the site.
让我继续进行检查，扩大运动范围，让我们继续前进
Let me go ahead and inspect this, expand the sports, let's go ahead
并将终极飞盘改为网球。
and change ultimate Frisbee to tennis.
让我们继续将其更改为网球。
Let's go ahead and change that to tennis.
关闭窗口，将下拉菜单更改为网球，现在就可以开始了。
Close the window, change the dropdown to tennis, and now, there we go.
好的。
OK.
All right.
我感到困惑了片刻，但是再次，只是重新启动服务器，
I was confused for a moment, but again, just restart the server,
它将重新加载我们实际进行的更改。
and it will reload the changes we actually made.
非常感谢Brian，潜水到这里救了我。
And thank you so much, Brian, for diving in there to save me.
我想到了。
I figured it out.
好吧，我现在对自己的问题有任何疑问或困惑。
All right, any questions or confusion beyond my own now on what it is we've
只需完成一项操作，即可动态生成用户选择菜单选项的列表
just done by one, dynamically generating a list of user select menu options
并根据相同的数据列表在服务器上进行验证？
and also validating on the server against that same list of data?
任何问题？
Any questions?
还是Brian身上有什么？
Or anything on your end Brian?
布莱恩：什么都没有。
BRIAN: Nothing here.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right.
因此，让我快速真实地演示这些不同的用户界面
So let me just demonstrate real quickly these just different user interface
机制。
mechanisms.
可以说，我们并不太专注
And suffice it to say, we're not too focused
用于我们在用户界面设计上的目的。
for our purpose on user interface design.
使用类似Bootstrap的库，您可以使这些表单看起来更漂亮吗？
Using a library like Bootstrap can you make these forms look much prettier
只需添加更多HTML标记和CSS类，
just by adding a few more HTML tags and a few more CSS classes,
但让我继续进行一下调整
but let me go ahead and make one tweak here
因此我们可以从选择菜单更改UI
whereby we can change the UI from being the select menu
一堆不同的东西。
to a bunch of different things.
我为点HTML编制了索引，可以继续在for循环中定义，
I index dot HTML I can go ahead and define, inside of my for loop,
而不是使用“选择”菜单输入，名称等于运动，
instead of using the Select menu an input, name equals sport,
type等于单选按钮的单选，即
type equals radio for radio button, which
是您可能会在框上，网站上打勾的互斥圈子，
are the mutually exclusive circles that you might tick on a box, on a website,
然后，这项运动的价值便是这项特殊运动。
and then the value of this will be this particular sport.
然后在这里，让我继续进行单选按钮之外的操作
And then over here, let me go ahead outside of the radio button
并向人们实际显示该运动名称。
and actually display to the human that sport name.
让我重新启动服务器。
Let me restart the server.
让我重新加载我的页面，瞧，我们不再有选择菜单，
Let me reload my page, and voila, we no longer have a select menu,
但是我们有单选按钮，可以达到相同的效果，
but we have radio buttons, which achieve the same result,
但它们只是以稍微不同的方式布置。
but they're just laid out in a slightly different way.
而且它们确实像旧学校一样相互排斥
And they're indeed mutually exclusive like an old school
汽车上的收音机，您一次只能选择其中一个，
radio in a car where you can only select one of them at a time,
但是否则该网站的工作原理完全相同。
but otherwise the site works completely the same.
那么该使用哪个呢？
So which to use?
这取决于。
It depends.
如果您有100种不同的运动，那么您可能
If you've got 100 different sports you probably
如果只想要100个不同的单选按钮
don't want 100 different radio buttons if only
因为它们占用了太多空间。
because they take up so much space.
但是，如果相反，您可能想使用下拉菜单。
But if instead you might want to use a drop down menu instead.
好吧，那么我们仍然没有做的关键是什么？
All right, so what's the key thing we're still not doing?
我们有一个非常动态的用户界面，
We've got a pretty dynamic user interface,
但我只是丢掉信息
but I'm just throwing away the information
一旦用户单击注册。
once the user clicks Register.
因此，让我们开始回忆起来，就像我回去一样
So let's actually start remembering, just as I did back
在那天，谁实际注册，以便我们实际拥有
in the day, who has actually registered so that we actually have
适当的工作登记制度。
a proper working registration system.
那么我们如何去做呢？
So how can we go about doing this?
好吧，我们过去看过Python时就已经看到了
Well we've seen in our look at Python in the past
我们可以使用列表将数据存储在Python程序中，
that we can store data inside of a Python program using a list,
使用字典，使用一组。
using a dictionary, using a set.
Python提供了很多数据结构。
There's a lot of data structures that Python gives us.
因此，让我们开始简单。
So let's start simple.
让我们真正地做到这一点。
And let's actually do that.
让我们继续，将我们的注册人存储在字典中。
Let's go ahead and store our registrants maybe in a dictionary.
因此，在应用程序点py中，到目前为止，该点尚未更改，
So in application dot py, which is thus far now unchanged,
让我给自己一个全局变量，注册者，
let me give myself one other global variable, registrants,
让我将其初始化为一个空字典。
and let me initialize it to an empty dictionary.
回想一下，我们这样做是为了实施电话簿，其中
And recall that we did this to implement a phone book where
我添加了我的姓名和电话号码以及Brian的姓名和电话号码
I added my name and phone number and Brian's name and phone number
几个星期前。
a couple of weeks ago.
我们使用Python字典来存储这些键值对，名称和电话
We used a Python dictionary to store those key value pairs, name and phone
数字。
number.
在这里，让我们做类似的事情。
Here let's do something similar.
让我们存储用户名和运动
Let's store the user's name and the sport
为他们注册，以便我们然后
for which they're registered so that we then
在计算机内存中包含所有有效注册的列表。
have in the computer's memory a list of all of the valid registrations.
那么我们将如何做到这一点以及需要改变什么呢？
So how are we going to do this and what needs to change?
好吧，让我继续并将其更改回“选择”菜单
Well let me go ahead and change this back to the Select menu
只是因为它适合屏幕而不是收音机更好
just because it fits on the screen a little better instead of the radio
纽扣。
buttons.
从这里开始，我们将再次获得之前看到的用户界面。
And from here we will have again, the user interface that we saw earlier.
因此，让我继续进行Flask运行，让我继续进行
So let me go ahead and do Flask run, let me go ahead
并打开它，瞧，我们有相同的界面
and open this up, and voila, we have that same interface
和以前一样，现在的目标是当我单击“注册”时，
as before, the goal of which now is when I click Register,
我不想天真地看到您已经注册，或者您还没有注册，
I don't want to just naively see you are registered or you are not register,
我想实际注册用户。
I want to actually register the user.
所以我认为我们需要做一些工作
So I think we're going to need to do a bit of work
在应用程序点py中，实际上是
in application dot py, the file that's actually
处理用户的注册。
processing the user's registration.
因此，不只是通过检查来验证表单
So instead of just validating the form by checking
如果他们有一个名字或一项体育运动，
if they had a name or a sport that was in sports,
让我们做些不同的事情。
let's do something a little different.
所以，让我继续，从这里重新开始，
So let me go ahead and sort of start anew here,
让我做这样的事情：name等于request dot form dot get name，
and let me do something like this: name equals request dot form dot get name,
只是为了让它包含在变量中，它会更易于使用。
just so I have it in a variable, it'll be a little easier to use.
然后，让我们只说如果不是名字，那么让我们继续并返回渲染
And then let's just say if not name, then let's go ahead and return render
模板故障点HTML。
template failure dot HTML.
好吧，让我们检查一下运动。
All right, let's then check sport.
运动等于请求点形式从点开始运动，并将其存储在变量中
Sport equals request dot form dot get sport, storing it in a variable
只是这样我可以做得更干净一点。
just so I can do this a little more cleanly.
然后，如果不运动，请继续并返回渲染模板，模板，
And then if not sport, go ahead and return render template, template,
失效点HTML。
failure dot HTML.
然后再进行一次检查，但我只是
And then let's do one more check, but I'm just
这次要多一些学究。
being a little more pedantic this time.
如果运动不在运动中，那就继续吧
If sport not in sports, then let's go ahead
并返回渲染模板故障点HTML。
and return render template failure dot HTML.
但是你知道吗，这似乎有点愚蠢。
But you know what, this seems a little silly.
如果我正在做所有事情，如果我以程序员的身份知道错误是什么，
If all I'm doing, if I know as the programmer what the error is,
但我只是告诉用户您尚未注册，
but I'm just telling the user you are not registered,
那不是特别好的设计。
that's not particularly good design.
我没有告诉用户有关他们做错了什么的任何信息。
I'm not telling the user any information about what they did wrong.
因此，让我们这样做。
So let's do this instead.
让我继续创建另一个文件，而不是失败点HTML。
Instead of failure dot HTML, let me go ahead and create a different file
称为错误点HTML。
called error dot HTML.
这将在我的Frosh IMs目录中称为错误点HTML。
And this will be called error dot HTML in my Frosh IMs directory
在我的模板目录中，在这里，让我们继续
in my templates directory, and in here, let's go ahead
并实际上发出了一条错误消息，例如类似此消息的消息。
and actually put an error message, for instance, something like this message.
因此，除了占位符之外，实际上没有其他任何内容，
So there's nothing really there other than a placeholder for message,
但让我们看看这将为我们带来什么。
but let's see what this will do for us.
现在让我们回到应用程序点py。
Let's now go back to application dot py.
让我们更具体一点，而不是错误点HTML
And instead of error dot HTML, let's be a little more specific
并传递一条错误消息，例如缺少名称。
and pass in an error message like missing name.
在这里，让我们将其更改为错误点HTML
And down here, let's change this to error dot HTML
并说说缺少运动的信息。
and say a message of missing sport.
在这里，让我们将其更改为错误
And down here, let's change this to errors
点HTML，糟糕，错误，错误中的错误，无效运动的消息。
dot HTML, whoops, error, error in the error, message of invalid sport.
因此，这里有一项运动，但它不在有效运动列表中，
So there's a sport there, but it's just not in the list of valid sports,
因此我们应该相应地告诉用户。
so we should tell the user accordingly.
因此，现在让我们快速尝试一下。
So now let's just try this real quick.
让我们快速尝试一下并正确输入此数据，以便我们看到它们。
Let's try this real quick and input this data in correctly so we can see these.
让我重新运行服务器，重新加载表单，让我们什么都不打
Let me rerun the server, reload the form, let's type in nothing
然后尝试注册。
and just try to register.
好的。
OK.
姓名缺失。
Missing name.
它比仅“您尚未注册”更有用。
It's more useful than just "you are not registered."
好吧，好，让我给你我的名字，大卫。
All right, fine, let me give you my name, David.
登记。
Register.
缺少运动。
Missing sport.
好的。
OK.
现在，让我继续前进，给您一项运动。
Now let me go ahead and give you a sport.
现在，如果我注册了，我可能会遇到其他错误
And now if I registered, I'd probably get some other error
因为我还没有处理成功的结果。
because I haven't handled the successful outcome yet.
因此，让我们结束这一步。
So let's finish this up.
让我们回到我的注册路线中的应用程序点py
Let's go back to my application dot py in my register route
然后问自己，注册用户意味着什么？
and then ask ourselves, well what does it mean to register the user?
我想记住该用户已注册给定的
I want to remember that the user is registered for a given
在计算机的内存中运动。
sport in the computer's memory.
还有计算机的内存，回想一下，我正在使用
And the computer's memory, recall, I'm using
通过称为“注册人”的全局变量。
by way of this global variable called registrants.
所有的上限只是为了明确说明这是一个全局变量，
And it's all caps just to make clear that it's a global variable,
但这不是必需的。
but that's not required.
然后在这里，为什么我不这样做，注册人，名字等于体育。
And then down here, why don't I do this, registrants, name equals sport.
因此，这与我们对姓名和电话号码，键所做的操作非常相似
So this is very similar to what we did with names and phone numbers, keys
和值，其中我使用名称来索引到Python字典中，
and values, where I'm using name to index into the Python dictionary,
并且我将值设置为等于这项运动。
and I'm setting the value equal to the sport.
然后，让我们继续说说“回报”，“渲染模板”，“哎呀”
And then let's go ahead for now and say return, render template, whoops,
渲染模板，成功点HTML。
render template, success dot HTML.
因此，让我们对此进行测试。
So let's test this out.
让我们来看Frosh IM，哎呀，让我们从我的错误中学习。
Let's go over to Frosh IMs, whoops, let's learn from my mistakes.
停止服务器并重新加载。
Stop the server and reload.
让我回到浏览器。
Let me go back to the browser.
让我继续输入大卫，他将注册躲避球，然后注册。
Let me go ahead and type in David, who will register for dodgeball, register.
声称已注册。
Claims it's registered.
让我去做，布莱恩将报名参加旗杆足球比赛。
Let me do Brian will register for flag football.
挂号的。
Registered.
他已注册。
He is registered.
但是我不知道谁在注册。
But I don't know who's registered or not.
我不知道。
I don't know.
但是您知道吗，让我们在这里进行一些理智检查。
But you know what, let's do a little sanity check here.
让我只打印出注册人，对吗？
Let me just print out registrants, right?
如有疑问，请打印或打印f为您的朋友。
When in doubt, print or print f is your friend.
因此，让我们在这里做些戳记，然后再次运行Flask run。
So let's just do a little poking around here and run Flask run again.
这次让我们回到表格上，注册David，运动，躲避球，
This time let's go back to the form and register David, sport, dodgeball,
注册，行为相同。
register, same behavior.
但是在这里，请注意我们有这个。
But down here, notice we have this.
我看到你们中的几个也在注册。
And I see a couple of you are registering as well.
所以我看到卢卡斯也注册了躲避球，
So I see Lucas has registered for dodgeball as well,
Brian Y.已注册排球。
Brian Y. has registered for volleyball.
好吧，现在Harsh已经注册了排球。
So OK, now Harsh has registered for volleyball.
因此，当我们进行这些现场演示时，这就是互联网的问题，
So this is the problem with having an internet when we do these live demos,
但显然它确实有效。
but apparently it does in fact work.
所以，让我们继续做，使它更清洁一点
So let's go ahead and make this a little cleaner
在这里，让我们继续前进，而不仅仅是打印注册人
here, and instead of just printing registrants, let's go ahead
并做这样的事情。
and do something like this.
我为什么不继续前进，你知道吗，让我们这样做。
Why don't I go ahead, and you know what, let's do this.
让我们继续渲染一个称为注册人点HTML的模板。
Let's go ahead and render a template called registrants dot HTML.
我认为要实现这一目标，我需要另一条路线，
And I think to make this happen, I'm going to need another route,
但是这一点会很有趣，因为我们从来没有
but this one will be kind of interesting in that we've never
动态生成这种成功消息。
dynamically generated quite this kind of success message.
所以，让我继续前进，在这里快速地提出一些建议。
So let me go ahead and whip something up real quick here.
让我转到一个新文件，注册人点HTML，Frosh IM，模板，
Let me go to a new file, registrants dot HTML, Frosh IMs, templates,
然后在该文件夹，模板中，在这里我们要做
and then in that folder, templates, and in here we're going to do
将布局点HTML扩展到此处，块主体，结束块，
extends layout dot HTML, down here, block body, end block,
然后在这里，在这里，我要去做，这要带我
and then down here, in here, I'm going to do, this going to take me
请稍等，H1，注册人。
a moment here, H1, registrants.
然后在下面，我将给自己一个HTML表。
Then below that I'm going to give myself an HTML table.
在表格内部，我将定义什么
Inside of the table, I'm going to define what's
称为桌头，并非严格要求
called a table head, which is not strictly required
但是它有助于从可选的页脚中区分出头部和身体。
but it helps distinguish the head from the body from the optional footer.
在这里，我将创建一个表格行。
Inside of here I'm going to create a table row.
在这里，我将创建三列，
Inside of here I'm going to create three columns,
使用TH，表标题，您可能以前没有看到过。
using TH, table heading, which you might not have seen before.
通常情况下，默认情况下使内容为粗体以明确其标题。
Typically makes things bold by default to make clear it's the heading.
我要输入该人的姓名，然后再输入其运动的另一个标题
And I'm going to put the person's name and then another heading of their sport
在这里。
down here.
然后在桌头下面，我要做tbody，这是桌体，
And then below the table head I'm going to do tbody, which is the table body,
您可能以前从未见过的另一个标签，实际上只是代表
another tag you might not have seen before but just represents, indeed,
身体。
the body.
我将动态生成一堆TR。
And I'm going to generate dynamically a whole bunch of TRs.
因此，对于注册人的名字，让我们继续吧
So for name in registrants, let's go ahead
在我的模板的Jinja for循环中，并动态输出表行。
in this Jinja for loop in my template and output dynamically a table row.
在该表格行的内部，有一些表格数据，特别是该人的名字，
Inside of that table row, some table data, specifically the person's name,
然后在另一列中
and then specifically in the other column
我可以访问的人的运动，如我们将通过变量看到的那样
the person's sport, which I can access, as we'll see by way of a variable
通过名称将其编入索引，从而称为注册人。
called registrants by indexing into it via the name.
因此，注册人很快就会成为一本字典
So registrants, in a moment, is going to be a dictionary
我将其传递到模板中
that I pass into my template.
我想就是这样。
I think that's it.
键入它有点繁琐。
It's a little tedious to type it out.
但是请注意，没有数据。
But notice there's no data.
这只是HTML和模板。
It's only HTML and templating.
如果我现在回到这里，让注册人等于注册人，
If I go back here now and pass in registrants equals registrants,
就像运动变量一样，我提供了注册人模板
just like with the sports variable I'm providing my registrants template
使用一个称为“注册人”的变量，但是我又可以将其命名为x或y或z，
with a variable called registrants, but again I could call it x or y or z,
但是注册人觉得合适一点，
but registrants feels a little more appropriate,
将其设置为等于该全局变量的值，
setting it equal to the value of that global variable,
从而使我的模板可以访问该词典。
thereby giving my template access to that dictionary.
如果我现在保存文件，请重新运行Flask，请回到此处，
If I now save the file, rerun Flask, go ahead back here,
哦，让我继续，再做一次。
whoops, let me go ahead and do this once more.
让我继续并重新运行Flask。
Let me go ahead and rerun Flask.
让我继续并选择我的URL。
Let me go ahead and select my URL.
让我继续进行操作，为David注册躲避球，然后单击“注册”。
Let me go ahead and register David for dodgeball and click Register.
瞧。
Voila.
严厉，你击败了我。
Harsh, you beat me to it.
因此，Harsh注册了旗帜足球。
So Harsh is registered for flag football.
大卫已经注册了躲避球。
David has registered for dodgeball.
它不是最漂亮的用户界面，但是如果我查看页面源代码，
It's not the prettiest user interface, but if I view the page source,
您会看到我们确实有桌子头，然后是桌子主体，
you'll see that we indeed have the table head, followed by the table body,
其次是哈什（Harsh）进行国旗足球比赛，接着是戴维（David）
followed by Harsh for flag football, followed by David
躲避球，然后再注册
for dodgeball, and then after that any subsequent registrants
谁同时注册。
who are registering at the same time.
我敢说，这很酷，因为现在我们
So this is pretty cool, I dare say, in that now we
能够将所有这些注册人保存到全局变量中。
have the ability to save all of these registrants to a global variable.
但是这里有什么缺点呢？
But what's a downside here?
我们已经取得了进展。
We've made progress.
我现在向您展示已注册的用户，
I'm now showing you users who have registered,
因此，这是指负责这项运动的RA或监禁人
so that means the RA or proctor who's running the sport
知道谁注册了。
knows who's registered.
但是有一个陷阱。
But there's a catch.
这里可能出什么毛病？
What could go wrong here?
使用字典有什么不好？
What's bad about using a dictionary?
索菲亚？
Sophia?
SOPHIA：我假设每次您重新加载
SOPHIA: I'm assuming that every time you reload
您将要重置的服务器，并且您不打算保存数据？
the server you're just going to reset, and you're not going save the data?
戴维·J·马兰（David J. MALAN）：好的。
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
如果我只是使用全局变量，它将
If I'm just using a global variable, it'll
只要服务器永远运行并且IDE保持在线状态，它就可以永远工作
work forever so long as the server runs forever and the IDE stays online
并且我们不会失去权力或任何其他原因。
and we don't lose power or any other number of reasons.
但是，请问我，Web服务器一经停止，停止或关闭
But as soon as the web server, excuse me, stops or is turned off
或出现问题，我们将丢失所有这些数据。
or something goes wrong, we're going to lose all of that data.
这就是为什么几周前使用Python的原因
So this is why a couple of weeks ago with Python
我们实际上使用了CSV文件，或者最终使用了SQLite数据库。
we actually used CSV files or ultimately a SQLite database.
但是，我也要进行一次更改。
But let me make one change too.
因为我现在不喜欢的是那一刻
Because what I don't like right now is that at the moment
查看我的注册人的唯一方法是实际注册自己。
the only way to view my registrants is to actually register yourself.
如果您想要求人们先注册，那么这可能就是一个功能
And maybe that's a feature if you want to require people register before they
看看还有谁注册了，但是有不同的路线感觉很好，
see who else is registered, but it feels nice to have a different route,
可能大幅削减注册人，任何人都可以访问
maybe slash registrants, that anyone can visit
查看实际的注册者列表。
to see the actual list of registrants.
因此，让我继续进行一下调整。
So let me go ahead and make one tweak here.
让我继续在这里定义另一条路线，应用程序点路线，斜线，
Let me go ahead down here and define another route, app dot route, slash,
哎呀，注册者。
whoops, registrants.
然后定义注册人为我的职能
And then define registrants as my function
但我可以随便叫它。
but I could call it anything I want.
让我实际上将模板的呈现移到此处。
And let me actually move this rendering of template here.
你知道吗，让我变得聪明一点。
And you know what, let me be a little clever.
让我实际将用户重定向到斜线注册者。
Let me actually redirect the user to slash registrants.
因此，让我继续在这里导入另外一个功能，
So let me go ahead and import one more function up here,
从Flask库重定向。
redirect, from the Flask library.
这是一个实际上将执行这些HTTP 301之一的功能
And this is a function that will literally do one of those HTTP 301s
或一些其他状态代码，这些代码会将位置发送到浏览器，其中说：
or some other status code that will send a location to the browser that says,
嗯，改为去这里。
uh-uh, go here instead.
原因是现在很好
And the reason for this is that it's just nice now
在我的注册路线内，一旦您注册，
that inside of my register route, once you're registered,
我不需要从字面上复制并粘贴此行在两个不同的地方
I don't need to literally copy and paste this line in two different places
并实际上有多余的代码。
and actually have redundant code.
我可以说，将用户重定向到斜线注册人
I can just say, redirect the user to slash registrants
现在已经存在，以便他们可以看到自己
which already exists now so that they can see themselves
以及还有谁注册了。
and who else has registered.
因此，如果我再次执行此操作，请让我重新启动服务器。
So if I do this again, let me restart the server.
让我回到表格，输入David进行躲避球比赛，注册。
Let me go back to the form, type in David for dodgeball, register.
好吧，Harsh，这次您没有晋级，但是我们看到Break
OK, so Harsh, you didn't make the cut this year, this time, but we see Break
莫阿什（Moash）和大卫（David）现在在那瞬间注册了，
and Moash and David now registered in that split second,
令人惊讶的是，对于这些运动。
amazingly, for these sports.
但是请注意URL，这是关键。
But notice the URL, which is the key point.
现在我们是斜线注册者。
Now we're at slash registrants.
而且，如果我继续加载，此后我将继续看到所有更改。
And if I keep reloading I'll keep seeing all of the changes since then.
好的，但是Sophia提出了一个很好的观点，那就是数据已经足够了
All right, but Sophia makes a really good point in that the data is all
会迷路的。
going to be lost.
因此，我认为我们应该对此进行清理，也许在这里做一个最终版本，
So I think we should clean this up and maybe do one final version here,
我们实际将数据保存在例如SQLite数据库中的位置
where we actually save the data in, for instance, a SQLite database
甚至通过电子邮件将其发送出去，以便我们也有备份副本。
or maybe even email it out so that we have a backup copy as well.
因此，让我继续提出这一建议。
So let me go ahead and propose this.
让我继续，建议我们在这里进行一些更改，一些更改，
Let me go ahead and propose that we make a few changes here, a few changes,
从我们对SQL和Python的研究中汲取了一些灵感。
borrowing some inspiration from our look at both SQL and Python.
因此，我现在暂时不讨论其中的大部分内容。
So I'm going to leave most of this alone for now.
我要去掉这个变量。
I'm going to go ahead and get rid of this variable.
我们必须将数据存储在其他位置。
We'll have to store the data elsewhere.
相反，让我们继续使用数据库，即SQLite数据库。
And instead, let's go ahead and use a database, a SQLite database.
因此，让我继续将数据库声明为SQL。
So let me go ahead and declare a database as SQL.
SQLite，冒号斜杠，斜杠，Frosh IMs点db。
SQLite, colon slash slash slash, Frosh IMs dot db.
让我继续导入。
Let me go ahead and import this.
回想一下，这是从CS50的库（该SQL库）中获取的。
This, recall, is from CS50's library, this SQL library.
让我在窗前继续一会儿
And let me go ahead in my window for just a moment
在这里，并从我带来的示例中复制数据库
here and copy the database from an example I brought with me just so
我们也不必创建数据库
that we don't have to create the database as well
并重新整理了本周有关SQL的内容。
and sort of rehash things from our week on SQL.
让我继续在这里获取数据库，实际上，瞧，
Let me go ahead and grab the database here, and indeed, voila,
数据库已出炉。
the database is out of the oven.
现在，我的目录中有一个本地文件，称为Frosh IMs dot db。
And we now have a local file in my directory called Frosh IMs dot db.
因此，让我们继续来看一下Frosh IMs dot db的SQLite数据库
So let's go ahead and first look at this database, SQLite of Frosh IMs dot db
点模式，输入。
dot schema, enter.
这是我预先创建的数据库表，因此我们
Here is the database table that I created in advance just so we
无需重新发明轮子。
wouldn't have to reinvent the wheel.
我正在创建一个名为ID列，名称列的名为registrants的表，
I'm creating a table called registrants with an ID column, with a name column,
和体育专栏。
and a sport column.
主键将是该ID。
The primary key is going to be that ID.
文本字段不应为null，运动项不应为null。
The textfield should not be null and the sport should not be null.
但是实际上在过去的几周中，我们已经看到了所有这些语法。
But we've seen all of this syntax actually in past weeks.
因此，这只是一个简单的表格，可为我提供每个注册人的ID，姓名，
So it's just a simple table to give me an ID for every registrant, a name,
和一项运动。
and a sport.
但是我现在将在Python中执行此操作。
But I'm going to do this in Python now.
所以让我继续前进，回到我的身边，让我回到我的应用程序点
So let me go ahead and go back into my, let me go back into my application dot
py，让我们继续执行此操作。
py, and let's go ahead and do this.
当我想实际注册用户时，
When I want to actually register the user,
让我们像以前一样验证它们，确保
let's validate them as before, making sure
他们给了我们他们的名字和运动，
that they've given us their name and their sport,
现在我们只使用一些SQL。
and now let's just use a little SQL.
与其将其保存到全局变量中，不如让它
Instead of saving it into what was a global variable let's
执行db dot并在注册人中插入名称和一项运动，
do db dot execute, insert into registrants a name and a sport,
我不需要ID，它会自动为我递增
I don't need the ID, it will auto increment for me
作为主键，还有两个值，问号和问号。
as the primary key, and two values, question mark and question mark.
再次提防SQL注入攻击，让我来谈谈名字和运动。
Again, beware SQL injection attacks, and let me pass in name and sport.
我认为这就是我所需要的。
And I think that's all I need.
我现在要在Python中使用一点SQL
I'm now going to use a little bit of SQL in my Python
为了将这个名字和体育项目插入数据库，
in order to insert that name and sport into the database,
之后，我认为我很好。
and after that, I think I'm fine.
但是我确实需要更改注册人，因为这里的变量没有
But I do need to change registrants because this variable down here no
不再存在。
longer exists.
但这没关系，因为回想起Python中的SQL，
But that's OK, because recall from our look at SQL in Python,
我可以做这样的事情：注册人等于db dot
I can do something like this: registrants equals db dot
执行，从注册人中选择星号。
execute, select star from registrants.
确实，简单的查询似乎可以让我访问
Indeed that simple query would seem to give me access
到目前为止的所有注册人，现在我可以这样通过。
to all of the registrants thus far, and now I can just pass that in like that.
再次，您的模板中变量的名称看起来有点奇怪
Again, it looks a little weird that the name of your variable in your template
与此变量的名称相同。
is the same as the name of this variable.
但这又是因为右边是变量，左边是
But again, that's because on the right is the variable, on the left
是您要在模板中使用的名称，
is the name you want to use in your template,
但您可以随便叫它。
but you could call it anything you want.
好吧，像往常一样，在这里，让我用手指交叉。
All right, here, as always, let me cross my fingers.
烧瓶运行起来，好的，让我继续打开我的URL。
Flask run, all right, let me go ahead and open up my URL.
让我继续输入大卫，躲避球，注册，好吧，有趣。
Let me go ahead and type in David, dodgeball, register, OK, interesting.
因此，Harsh和Naveen很快就进入了那里，
So Harsh and Naveen got in there real fast,
同样，您只是在等待“提交”按钮。
again, you're just kind of waiting with the Submit button.
但这是一团糟。
But this is a mess.
现在出现了明显的错误，我看到的是奇怪的字典语法。
Something is clearly wrong now, I'm seeing like weird dictionary syntax.
但这是因为我尚未调整模板。
But that's because I haven't adjusted my template.
因此，让我进入注册人点HTML并回想一下
So let me go into registrants dot HTML and recall
当我从注册人中选择星号进行选择时，
that when I select with select star from registrants,
这就像返回行。
this is like getting back rows.
我只是将其重命名为注册人，但实际上我正在找回排行。
I just renamed it to registrants, but I'm really getting back rows.
行只是字典，每一行都是字典
And rows are just dictionary, each row is a dictionary
列及其所在的值。
of columns and the values they're in.
所以我认为我的语法只需要对我的注册人进行一些更改
So I think my syntax just needs to change a little bit in my registrants
点HTML。
dot HTML.
我真的应该把这当作注册人中的注册人，
I should really think of this as for registrant in registrants,
然后让我继续输出注册人的姓名。
and let me go ahead and output the registrant's name.
下面让我输出注册人的运动。
And down here let me output the registrant's sport.
再一次，这与我们花在SQL和Python上的时间更相似
So again, this is more similar to the time we spent on SQL and Python
比现在的HTML和CSS要多。
than it is to HTML and CSS right now.
现在，我要遍历所有行。
Now I'm iterating over all of the rows.
而且，如果您愿意，我们甚至可以更改语义。
And if you prefer, let's change even the semantics.
让我们回到这里。
Let's go back over here.
就像几周前一样，让我们来做。
Let's do it just like we did a couple of weeks ago.
让我们返回一堆行，将这些行传递到我的模板中，
Let's just get back a bunch of rows, pass in those rows to my template,
现在遍历这些行。
and now iterate over those rows.
每行都有一个名称字段，每行都有一个运动字段。
And each row has a name field, and each row has a sport field.
因此，这也将是等效的。
So that too would be equivalent.
但是，一旦您了解了差异，就让我们
But once you understand the difference, let's
称其为真实名称，而不是更通用的行，
call it what they really are instead of this more generic row,
所以让我还原一下。
so let me revert that.
现在，让我继续并重新运行代码。
Now let me go ahead and rerun the code.
让我试着击败其他所有人，输入David进行躲避球，
Let me try to beat everyone else to the punch, type in David for dodgeball,
还有，哦，天哪，好多人。
and, Oh my god, OK, lot of people.
好，新的更好的苛刻，好吧，所以您的工作真的很快
OK, new and better Harsh, all right, so you're working really quickly
它应该看起来。
it should seem.
所以现在我们看到了所有相同的结果。
So now we see all of the same results.
现在数据库真的跳了。
The database is really hopping now.
我对进一步滚动感到有些紧张，
I'm a little nervous about scrolling any further,
所以我要把它留在那里。
so I'm going to leave it there.
但是老实说，我们现在有一个完整的Web应用程序
But we now have a full fledged web application honestly
现在，它更能代表现实世界的网站。
that is now much more representative of real world websites.
我们使用SQL拥有自己的数据库，我们动态地拥有自己的模板
We have our own database using SQL, we have our own templates dynamically
生成这张表，即使目前很丑陋，
generating this table even though it's ugly at the moment,
但我当然可以通过一些CSS或一些Bootstrap来美化它
but I could certainly beautify it with some CSS or some Bootstrap
特别是。
in particular.
但是，我们现在拥有一个功能全面的网站。
But we now have a fully functioning website.
蛋糕上的糖霜是什么？
What would be the icing on the cake?
你知道吗？
You know what?
即使我们认为是理所当然的，它也很酷
It's pretty cool, even though we take it for granted
网站通过电子邮件向您发送确认消息时。
when a website emails you a confirmation.
如果像我几年前一样添加一项最终功能该怎么办
What if we add one final feature just like I actually did years ago
您通过电子邮件向注册人或您自己报告
whereby you email the registrant or yourself to report
有人实际注册过吗？
that someone has actually registered?
那么我们如何去做呢？
So how can we go about doing this?
好吧，让我在这里回到我的代码中。
Well, let me go back into my code here.
最后，让我补充一句。
And let me add one final flourish.
我要滚动到此处的顶部，然后
I'm going to scroll up to the top here, and I'm
要导入另一个库。
going to import another library.
从Flask邮件导入邮件和消息。
From Flask mail import mail and message.
再说一次，您只会从课堂上知道要做这些事情，
And again, you would only know to do these things from a class,
从文档，从教程等。
from the documentation, from a tutorial or the like.
我提前查了一下，看看该怎么做。
I looked it up in advance to see how to do this.
然后，根据文档，我必须
And then I have to, according to the documentation,
需要一堆初始化步骤
there's a bunch of initialization steps required
当您想编写Python代码以编程方式生成电子邮件时。
when you want to write Python code to generate emails programmatically.
您必须知道您的用户名，密码，
You've got to know your username, your password,
以及许多其他设置。
and a bunch of other settings.
因此，让我继续进行配置。
So let me go ahead and configure those now.
应用程序点配置，引用不加引号，邮件默认发件人为1。
App dot config, quote unquote, mail default sender is one.
我将继续将其设置为os
And I'm going to go ahead and set that equal to os
点获取邮件默认发件人的环境。
dot get env of mail default sender.
因此，默认发件人是指默认电子邮件地址。
So default sender refers to a default email address.
例如，如果我希望所有这些电子邮件都来自我，
So for instance, if I wanted all these emails to come from me,
我可以做这样的事情。
I could do something like that.
但是相反，我将它们存储在其他位置的变量中，因为我
But instead I'm going to store them in variables elsewhere because I
预先预先配置了我的ID，因此没有人可以看到我的用户名
pre-configured my ID in advance so that no one could see my username
和密码。
and password.
因此，我将从所谓的环境中获取其中一些价值。
So I'm just going to grab some of those values from the so-called environment.
您不会经常使用此功能，但我们会
You won't use this feature too often but we'll
在下一个问题集中向您展示。
show it to you in the next problem set.
这是一种访问变量的方式
It's a way of getting access to a variable that's
在您的IDE或Linux系统中的其他地方定义
been defined elsewhere in your IDE or in your Linux system
或Mac或PC。
or Mac or PC more generally.
好吧，我需要再定义其中一些。
All right, I need to define a few more of these.
让我继续，做一些样板，
Let me go ahead and just do some boilerplate,
即使这看起来像是一个小复制粘贴，
even though this looks like a little copy paste, which it is,
实际上这是必要的，因为邮件服务器有很多设置。
it is in fact necessary because there's a lot of settings for a mail server.
所以让我一次做一个。
So let me do them one at a time.
邮件密码，我也不希望您看到该密码，
Mail password, I don't want you to see that either,
因此，我将继续从我的环境中获取该密码，即邮件密码。
so I'm going to go ahead and grab that from my environment, mail password.
让我们看一下，我需要一个邮件端口，邮件端口，所以将是587。
Let's see, I need a mail port, mail port, so that's going to be 587.
原来我要使用Gmail和Gmail
It turns out I'm going to use Gmail, and Gmail
使您可以在TCP端口587上发送电子邮件，因此我在文档中进行了查询
lets you send email on TCP port 587, so I looked that up in the documentation
也。
too.
邮件服务器实际上将是SMTP点gmail.com。
Mail server in fact will be SMTP dot gmail.com.
我在Google的文档中发现了这一点。
I found that on Google's documentation.
邮件使用TLS（一种加密类型），
Mail use TLS, which is a type of encryption,
让我继续并将其实现为真实。
let me go ahead and enable that as true.
然后最后发送用户名，我不要
And then lastly mail username, I don't want
您知道我正在使用什么用户名，但是我在
you to know what username I'm using, but I'm
将继续从我的环境（用户名）中获取该信息。
going to go ahead and grab this from my environment, username.
这实际上是故意的。
And this is actually deliberate.
虽然我说的是脸颊上的舌头，
Though I'm sort of saying it tongue in cheek,
输入用户名，密码或其他任何东西都是不好的做法
it is bad, bad practice to type in usernames, passwords, or anything
远程私有或保护到您的代码中。
remotely private or secure into your code.
因为想像您是否键入了自己的Gmail用户名或密码
Because imagine if you did type your own Gmail username or password
进入该程序只是为了从字面上尝试
into this program just to try it out literally
现在在家，然后您可以提交50或支票50，您猜怎么着？
right now at home and then you can submit50 or check50, guess what?
您是将用户名和密码发送给我们，工作人员，
You're sending your username and password to us, the staff,
更不用说GitHub和整个互联网了，
not to mention GitHub and the whole internet,
通过将其包含在您的源代码中。
by including it in your source code.
因此，虽然我在这里做的事情很有趣，
So while I'm sort of making fun at what I'm doing here,
这些环境变量中的私有信息存储
this storing of private information in these environment variables
实际上是最佳做法，因为这意味着它不在我的代码中，
is actually best practice because it means it's not in my code,
我不会无意间将其复制并粘贴到其他位置。
I'm not going to accidentally copy and paste it elsewhere.
好吧，我需要导入另一件事，这将解释所有这些
All right, I need to import one other thing which will explain all of these
红色的X。
red X's.
我还需要导入操作系统。
I need to also import OS.
因此，导入整个操作系统有点大胆的主张，
So it's kind of a bold claim to import a whole operating system,
但确实有Python随附的程式库
but there's indeed a library that comes with Python
称为OS，可让您访问这些环境变量之类的内容
called OS which gives you access to things like these environment variables
和别的。
and others.
喔。
Whoo.
好的。
OK.
太多了，我需要最后一行代码，
That was a lot, and I need one last line of code,
一个等于通过我的烧瓶的邮件变量
a mail variable equal to passing my Flask
应用程序称为邮件的功能。
application to a function called mail.
好的。
All right.
我认为所有这些错误很快就会消失，
I think all of those errors will soon go away,
我觉得这对我来说有点慢。
I think it's just being a little slow on me.
现在开始实际发送邮件。
Let's go ahead now and actually send mail.
确实，红色错误已消失。
Indeed the red errors are gone.
让我向下滚动，然后再将用户重定向到斜杠注册者
Let me scroll down, and before I redirect the user to slash registrants
但是在注册他们之后，让我继续执行此操作。
but after registering them, let me go ahead and do this.
让我定义一个等于大写消息的消息变量，它
Let me define a message variable equal to capital message, which
是我从该库导入的功能，
is the feature I imported from that library,
让我创建您已注册的主题行！
and let me create a subject line of You are registered!
让我继续吧。
And let me go ahead and, huh.
哦，我实际上不知道将其发送给谁，所以可以。
Oh, I don't actually know who to send this to, so that's OK.
让我们继续并在此处进行更改。
Let's go ahead and change something here.
让我们继续，让用户不要问他们的名字，
Let's go ahead and have the user ask not for their name,
让我们现在向用户询问他们的电子邮件。
let's ask the user for their email now.
因此，我将更改我的实际表格，以要求他们发送电子邮件。
So I'm going to change my actual form to ask for their email instead.
现在让我回到这里，让我回到这里
And now let me go back over here, and let me go back in here
并设置收件人的第二个参数等于电子邮件。
and set a second argument of recipients equals email.
让我在这里更改此设置。
And let me change this here.
让我继续，从表单中获取用户的电子邮件。
Let me go ahead and get the user's email from the form.
如果没有电子邮件，我们对他们大喊大叫并说出丢失的电子邮件。
If there is no email let's yell at them and say missing email.
运动保持不变。
Sport is unchanged.
让我们继续并插入注册人。
Let's go ahead and insert into registrants.
您知道什么，让我们不必费心地将其实际插入数据库中。
You know what, let's not bother inserting into the database actually.
让我们保持这个超级简单。
Let's keep this super simple.
让我们摆脱SQL的东西。
Let's get rid of the SQL stuff.
让我们发送确认电子邮件。
Let's just have it send a confirmation email.
因此，它甚至更简单。
So it's even simpler.
在这里，我们将重点完全放在电子邮件上。
We'll keep the focus entirely on email here.
因此，我创建了带有主题行和
So I've created the message with a subject line and the
可以说是通过接收者排队的。
to line, so to speak, via the recipients.
现在，我将继续发送邮件点发送消息。
Now I'm going to go ahead and send mail dot send message.
救。
Save.
这是我将一如既往地手指交叉的地方。
Here's where I'm going to cross my fingers as always.
我现在要继续运行该程序。
I'm going to go ahead now and run this program.
我要重新启动，在这里重新加载我的表格。
I'm going to restart, reload my form here.
确实是在要求我发送电子邮件。
It's indeed asking me for email.
让我继续输入，比如说约翰·哈佛在这里的地址。
Let me go ahead and type in, let's say John Harvard's address here.
像我一样，约翰·哈佛（John Harvard）将注册躲避球，
John Harvard, like me, will register for dodgeball,
让我走，然后单击注册。
and let me go and click Register.
现在该网站将要说内部服务器错误，这很令人惊讶
Now the website is about to say internal server error, which comes as a surprise
对我来说，但让我看看为什么。
to me, but let me see why.
哦，我不小心还在使用数据库。
Oh I accidentally am still using the database.
所以让我解决这个问题。
So let me fix this.
让我继续，由于我们不再使用数据库，
Let me go ahead and, since we're not using the database anymore,
让我继续并返回到我们更简单的return渲染模板
let me go ahead and revert to our simpler return render template
成功点HTML。
success dot HTML.
好的。
All right.
用户错误。
User error.
让我继续并重新启动服务器。
Let me go ahead and restart the server.
好的，网关不好，还有其他问题，我们开始吧。 jharvard @ cs50。
OK, bad gateway, whole other problem, here we go. jharvard@cs50.
现在让我继续注册躲避球。
Let me go ahead now and register for dodgeball.
登记。
Register.
交叉我的手指。
Crossing my fingers.
我已经注册，确实，让我们转到其他浏览器
I am registered, and indeed, let's go over to my other browser
在这里打开Gmail。
here where I have Gmail open.
我目前在这里假扮成John Harvard在Gmail中。
I am currently masquerading as John Harvard in Gmail here.
让我继续刷新收件箱，哦，我的天哪，CS50发出的消息
Let me go ahead and refresh my inbox, and oh my god, a message from the CS50
我确实已注册的Bot。
bot that I am indeed registered.
因此，现在我们有了一种发送电子邮件的程序化方式。
So now we have a programmatic way of sending emails.
我打了两次，所以这次我收到了两封电子邮件。
I hit it twice, so I got two emails this time.
但是确实，我现在也已经动态生成了电子邮件。
But indeed I've now dynamically generated emails as well.
很多。
A lot.
但是这些想法实际上只是基于模板
But the ideas really are just based on templates
以及将控制器逻辑和应用程序点py放入其中的想法
and the idea of sort of putting our controller logic and application dot py
以及所有用户的审美观和我们所谓的观点，
and all of the user aesthetics and our so-called views,
现在我们有了数据库或某种程度上的电子邮件后端，
and now that we've had a database or in some sense an email backend,
现在我们也有了一个模型的概念，在该模型中实际存储了数据
now we also have the notion of a model where the data is actually being stored
或在这种情况下，发送。
or in this case, sent.
任何疑问或困惑或澄清
Any questions or confusion or clarifications
有关使用SQLite或电子邮件或Frosh IM的任何功能的信息？
here on the use of SQLites or email or any of these Frosh IMs features?
好的。
All right.
那么，为什么在舞台上有一个装有饼干的购物车呢？
So why is there a shopping cart with cookies on the stage?
好吧，让我们休息最后的五分钟。
Well for that let's take our final five minute break.
我们会回来，谈论称为会议的事情，
We'll come back, talk about something called sessions,
并构建更复杂的Web应用程序。
and build even more sophisticated web apps.
回到五。
Back in five.
好吧，我们回来了，有一个我们还没有真正实现的功能
All right, we're back, and there's one feature that we haven't really
从根本上涉及网络编程，
fundamentally touched on at all when it comes to web programming,
这是你我每天都理所当然的事情，
and it's one that you and I take for granted every day,
每当我们登录某个网站，在线购买商品或进行互动时
any time we log into some website, buy something online, or generally interact
动态网站。
with dynamic websites.
这是通常称为会话的功能。
And that's a feature that's generally known as sessions.
Web应用程序内置了一种机制，无论它们是否
There is a mechanism built into web applications, whether they're
以Flask或其他框架或语言实施
implemented in Flask or in other frameworks or languages that
让网络服务器记住一些关于您的信息。
allow the web servers to remember a little something about you.
这对于当今的网络工作非常重要，
And this is super important to how the web today works,
因为没有它，您将无法登录Gmail或任何其他网站
because without it you wouldn't be able to log in to Gmail or to any other site
并让网站记住您已登录。
and have the website remember that you are logged in.
毕竟，考虑一下，当您登录Gmail时，
Consider, after all, when you log in to Gmail,
您输入您的用户名，密码，或者您的两因素身份验证
you type your username, your password, maybe your two-factor authentication
代码，然后您会看到您的收件箱。
code, and then you see your inbox.
从那里，下次打开时，系统不会提示您再次登录
And from there, you're not prompted to log in again the next time you open
一封电子邮件，然后下次您打开一封电子邮件时，
an email and then the next time you open an email,
您会保持登录状态数分钟或数小时，甚至几天
you stay logged in for some number of minutes or hours or even days
在你的电脑。
on your computer.
即使关闭浏览器标签，即使关闭计算机，
Even if you close the browser tab, even if you shut down your computer,
当您经常返回Gmail时，您仍处于登录状态，
when you come back to Gmail quite often, you're still logged in,
并从某种意义上记住您已经登录。
and it remembers in some sense that you have been logged in.
好吧，这实际上如何工作？
Well, how does this actually work?
在幕后，无论何时您访问gmail.com，
Well underneath the hood, anytime you visit gmail.com,
您的浏览器正在发送像这样的斜杠请求，默认
your browser is sending a request like this for slash, the default
gmail.com的路线，希望您可以看到自己的收件箱，
route of gmail.com, and hopefully you're going to either see your inbox,
或者，如果您尚未登录，则将看到该登录屏幕。
or if you're not yet logged in, you're going to see that login screen.
确实，反应可能会回来
Indeed, the response is probably going to come back
大约200 OK，文本HTML的内容类型，
along the lines of 200 OK, content type of text HTML,
这就是您看到登录表单或收件箱的时间。
and that's when you see the login form or your inbox.
但是回想一下上周还有其他HTTP标头
But recall from last week there's other HTTP headers
可以藏在那个虚拟信封里面
that can be tucked inside of that virtual envelope that
向浏览器和服务器提供有关它们应如何互操作的提示。
provide hints to the browser and server as to how they should interoperate.
确实，这就是HTTP的全部意义。
That's indeed what HTTP is all about.
这是一组协议的约定，用于控制浏览器和服务器的方式
It's a protocol set of conventions that govern how browsers and servers should
互操作。
interoperate.
事实证明，有时此服务器返回称为cookie的东西。
And it turns out that sometimes this server returns what are called cookies.
而且您听说过Cookie的可能性很高。
And odds are you've heard of cookies.
奇怪的是，您对Cookie有所了解
Odds are you have some sense that cookies
是有害或危险的，但也有必要，确实，所有这些都是正确的。
are bad or dangerous but also necessary, and indeed, all of that is true.
Cookies本质上是数据甚至文件
Cookies are essentially pieces of data or even files
安装在您的计算机或手机上的
that are planted on your computer or your phone
由帮助他们记住您曾经去过的服务器的服务器。
by a server that help them remember that you've been there before.
从某种意义上讲，它们可以帮助您记住自己，甚至是网站
In some sense, they help remember who you are, but even websites
您没有登录到手机上的情况很常见，
that you're not logging into very often put cookies onto your phone,
或您的笔记本电脑或台式机
or your laptop or desktop which essentially might
是一个只有您才能得到的大随机数，即使他们不知道
be a big random number that only you are given so that even if they don't know
是Maggie访问过该网站，Ryan，Nicole或其他人，
that it's Maggie who's visited the site, or Ryan, or Nicole, or someone else,
他们知道以前已经看到过唯一标识符。
they know that unique identifier has been seen before.
因此，他们可以跟踪您的行为。
And they can therefore track your behavior.
因此，如果您听说过跟踪Cookie一词，仅此而已。
So if you've heard the term tracking cookies, that's all it is.
这是一些数据，是一个很大的随机数
It's some piece of data, a big random number that's
已安装在您的浏览器上，然后您的浏览器便会记住它。
been installed on your browser that your browser then remembers.
机制很简单：HTTP标头之一
And the mechanism is as simple as this: one of the HTTP headers
从服务器到浏览器的字面意思
that comes from server to browser literally
设置为破折号cookie，冒号，然后是cookie的名称（例如会话），
is set dash cookie, colon, then the name of a cookie, for instance session,
然后是值，该值可能是那个大随机数。
and then value, and the value might be that big random number.
同样由于HTTP，这是一个协议
And because of HTTP, again, it's a protocol
浏览器和服务器一起说话，
that browsers and servers speak together,
浏览器旨在将Cookie发送回每个后续页面
the browsers are designed to send that cookie back to every subsequent page
您访问gmail.com或您所使用的任何服务器。
you visit on gmail.com or whatever server you're on.
换句话说，当您访问gmail.com之后的一个小时之后，
In other words, when you visit gmail.com then an hour from now,
甚至在关闭标签后，甚至在睡觉后的明天，
even after closing your tabs, or even tomorrow after going to sleep,
您的浏览器不仅会发送这些标头，如果您
your browser is not only sending these headers, if you
之前已从gmail.com获得cookie，那么您的浏览器会发送
have been given a cookie from gmail.com before, your browser sends
一个相似的标题，但没有设置单词，它表示cookie，冒号，
a similar header but without the word set, it says cookie, colon,
会话等于值。
session equals value.
令您不为所知的是，您的浏览器会不断提醒服务器
So unbeknownst to you, your browser is constantly reminding the server
你以前去过那里。
that you've been there before.
当您身处其中时，这类似于现实世界，
And this is similar to the real world when you're perhaps in,
当您进入俱乐部，酒吧或游乐园时
when you go into a club or a bar or an amusement park
然后你穿过大门，通常
and you go through the gates, you typically
可以盖上您的手以使其返回。
are allowed back in by having your hand stamped.
这样，他们不必再次检查您的票
And this way they don't have to check your tickets again
或您的身份证之类的东西，他们只是在盖您的手
or your ID or the like, they just stamp your hand
这有点提醒您您曾经去过那里。
which is a little reminder that you have been there before.
因此，实际上，在这里，我有一张小邮票。
And so in fact, here, I've got a little stamp here.
如果我访问一个网站，就好像我的手被盖在这里，
If I visit a website, it's like my hand is being stamped here,
和我的浏览器，通过HTTP的设计应该
and my browser, by design of HTTP is supposed
到，每次我访问另一个页面时，单击另一个链接，
to, every time I visit another page, click another link,
就像你要回去一样代表我的手
represent my hand just like you're going back
进入酒吧，俱乐部或游乐园
into the bar or the club or the amusement park
提醒门口的那个人，保镖，你以前去过那里
to remind the person at the door, the bouncer, that you've been there before
并让您通过而不是提示您重新登录。
and to let you through rather than prompting you to log in again.
这就是cookie。
So that's what a cookie is.
就像贴在计算机上的虚拟手戳一样，
It is like this virtual hand stamp that's put on your computer,
但是您的计算机被设计为一次又一次地显示它。
but your computer is designed to present it again and again.
因此，如果您曾经想过有时会在一个网站上购物的话
So if you've ever wondered how sometimes you go shopping on one website
然后突然，令人毛骨悚然的是，您正在使用Facebook或其他工具，
and then all of a sudden, creepily you're on Facebook or something else,
而且您看到的是您在其他网站上没有买到的东西的广告，
and you're seeing ads for the very thing you didn't buy on this other website,
所有这些都来自Cookie。
that all derives from cookies.
长话短说，有广告公司
Long story short, there's advertising companies
Facebook和Google以及其他合作伙伴
that Facebook and Google and others partner with that
在网站上放置少量图像或JavaScript文件或其他此类文件，
put little images on the website or JavaScript files or other such files,
并且由于这些广告位于不同的网站上，因此共享了Cookie
and because those ads are on different websites the cookies are shared
在某种意义上跨多个网站。
across multiple websites in some sense.
因此，就像您不断展示您的手一样
So it's like you are constantly presenting your hand
给所有这些不同的第三方公司盖章，
stamp to all these different third party companies,
这就是他们向您宣传甚至在最坏的情况下跟踪您的方式。
and this is how they're advertising to you or even tracking you at worst.
顺便说一句，当您在浏览器中使用隐身模式或私有模式时，
As an aside, when you use incognito mode or private mode on your browser,
您所有的Cookie都会被暂时丢弃。
all of your cookies are temporarily thrown away.
您会得到一个空的饼干罐，可以这么说，
You get an empty cookie jar, so to speak,
这样看来您确实已登出。
so that you do appear to be logged out.
实际上，即使在上课时，我也使用了隐身模式
And in fact, even in class, I've used incognito mode
几次，因为我想重新开始而不是
a few times because I want to start fresh and not
让我有任何先前的点击或我们的先前演示弄乱了未来的演示。
have any of my prior clicks or our prior demos messing up future demos.
但是我这样做的原因仅仅是为了摆脱所有cookie
But the reason I was doing that was just to get rid of all cookies
因此，所有州。
and therefore all states.
因此，一方面，Cookie是非常重要且功能强大的
So on the one hand, cookies are an incredibly important and powerful
机制，但就可以说了，而且在此过程中还有更多，
mechanism, but suffice it to say, and more on this down the road,
它们可能会被滥用，尤其是在涉及到个人隐私或安全性时。
they can be misused, certainly when it comes to one's privacy or security.
因此，让我们专注于cookie的主要部分
So with that said, let's focus on the good part of cookies
考虑典型的网站如何记住您的登录信息。
and consider how a typical website remembers that you're logged in.
让我们采取一个非常简单的想法，并弄清楚
Let's take that very simple idea and make it clear
现在，有了代码，一切都在您的能力范围内。
that it's all within your power now with code to do this.
因此，让我们开始如下。
So let's start as follows.
我创建了一个名为login的新目录。
I've created a new directory called login
只是为了演示一个可以使人们登录的程序。
just to demonstrate a program that logs people in.
我的布局与以前相同，并且还添加了一个标签。
I've got my same layout as before, and I've added one more tag.
最好的做法是告诉浏览器您
It tends to be best practice to tell the browser that you're
本质上使用Unicode。
using essentially Unicode.
这样，我可以在HTML中包含表情符号和其他字符。
This way I can have emojis and other characters in my HTML.
因此，我添加了这五行内容，您将在Bootstrap的文档中看到该行
So I've added this line five which you'll see on Bootstrap's documentation
和其他网站，所以现在我对该页面有了一个很好的起点。
and other sites, so now I have sort of a good starting point for this page.
但是实际上没有内容，这里只定义了一个块，
But there's really no content, there's just a block being defined here,
阻止身体。
block body.
所以那只是我和以前一样的布局。
So that's just my same layout as before.
确实，如果我输入ls，您将看到一个应用程序
And indeed if I type ls you'll see an application
点py和模板文件夹。
dot py and a templates folder.
现在，在该模板文件夹中仅是布局点HTML。
In that templates folder for now is just layout dot HTML.
因此，让我们继续前进，开始编写一个以生活为目的的快速应用程序
So let's go ahead and start writing a quick application whose purpose in life
只是向用户提供一个表单，他们可以通过该表单登录
is just to present the user with a form via which they can log in
然后记住他们已登录。
and then remember that they are logged in.
因此，让我从Flask导入Flask。
So from Flask let me import Flask.
我还要导入重定向功能，渲染模板功能，
Let me also import the redirect function, the render template function,
请求变量，现在是会话变量。
the request variable, and now a session variable.
这是新事物。
This is something new.
然后在Flask会议上，让我继续
And then from Flask session, let me go ahead
并导入会话，然后在这里让我做应用程序来获取Flask，
and import session, and then down here let me do app gets Flask,
下划线，下划线，名称。
underscore, underscore, name.
现在，我需要文档中的其他几行代码。
And now I need a few more lines of code from documentation.
应用程式点设定，右方括号，工作阶段永久性为false，
App dot config, open bracket, session permanent equals false,
再次，这仅特定于称为Flask会话的库
and again, this is specific only to the library called Flask session
我正在使用的那个图书馆正在
that I'm using, and that library is going
从本质上来说，可以为我的应用启用手印。
to enable hand stamps, essentially, for my application.
我将对其进行配置以使用字面上的文件系统，
And I'm going to configure it to use literally the file system,
因此会话类型等于文件系统和文件系统
so session type equals file system, and file system
只是想说一下硬盘驱动器或我自己的IDE帐户，
is just fancy speak for the hard drive or my own IDE account,
这是使用数据库之类的替代方法
and this is an alternative to using a database or something
像这样，然后是会话应用。
else like that, and then session app.
所以这只是样板，我从字面上复制了
So this is just boilerplate, I literally copied
该库文档中的这三行内容。
these three lines from the documentation for this library.
但是要使用这个库，这也是
But to use this library, and this was also
刚才的邮件库是真的，
true of the mail library a moment ago, there's
我应该指出的另一个文件。
another file I should point out.
所以当我在这里时，我应该再创建一个我前面提到的文件
So when I am here, I should create one other file that I mentioned earlier
但是我们还没有创建自己，这次称为需求点文本。
but we haven't created ourselves, this time called requirements dot text.
然后将其放入我的登录目录中，
And I'm going to put this into my login directory,
我将需要Flask用于此应用程序，
and I'm going to require Flask for this application,
而且我还将需要一个名为Flask session的库。
and I'm also going to require a library called Flask session.
再次重申，我之前在幻灯片上声称
So again, I claimed before on the slide that requirements
点文本只是需求的简单列表，您可以使用的库
dot text is just a simple list of the requirements, the libraries you
想要使用。
want to use.
还有一些您将在命令行中使用的命令
And there are commands you will use at the command line
安装这些要求。
to install those requirements.
对于问题集，您通常不需要这样做，
You won't typically need to do this for the problem set,
但是，如果您要安装，就这样您已经看过了
but just so you've seen it, if you want to install
Python应用程序的要求，
the requirements for a Python application,
您通常执行这样的命令。
you typically do a command like this.
点安装破折号r，要求点文本。
Pip install dash r, requirements dot text.
而且我不会这样做，因为我事先做了，
And I'm not going to do because I did it in advance,
但要知道，为了安装库，在Python中要容易得多
but just know that in order to install libraries, it's much easier in Python
比起C语言，他们倾向于
than it was, for instance, in C. They tend
通过称为“
to be more easily packageable via this technology called
点和类似的东西。
pip and things like it.
好吧，让我们继续，并创建一些路线。
All right, let's go ahead and create a couple of routes.
应用程式路线斜线def索引，因此就像以前一样，
App route slash def index, so just boilerplate as before,
让我们继续，简单地返回索引点的渲染模板
and let's just go ahead and simply return render template of index dot
默认情况下是HTML，然后让我们继续创建另一条路线，
HTML by default, and then let's go ahead and create one other route,
应用程序点路由斜杠登录，而在我的登录路由中，
app dot route slash login, and in my login route, which
将由登录功能控制，让我继续
will be governed by a login function, let me go ahead
并返回渲染模板登录。
and return render template login.
因此，让我们暂时保持简单。
So let's keep it simple for the moment.
现在让我继续实施此表格。
And now let me go ahead and implement this form.
因此，让我继续创建一个名为
So let me go ahead and create a file called
登录点HTML，其目的是拥有我的登录表单，
login dot HTML, whose purpose in life is just going to have my login form,
我在该登录表单中想要的只是用户名的空格。
and what I want in that login form is just a space for the user's name.
在现实世界中，我肯定会
In the real world, I would most certainly
进行用户名和密码之类的操作，
do something like a username and a password,
但是我们将保持简单，只关注思想的实质，
but we're going to keep it simple, focus only on the essence of the idea,
并执行类似用户名的操作。
and do something like just the user's name.
因此，在登录点HTML中，我将像以前一样扩展布局点HTML。
So, in login dot HTML, I'm going to extend layout dot HTML as before.
我将拥有我的积木，并且我将拥有我的结局标签，
I'm going to have my block body, and I'm going to have my end block tag,
然后在这里，我将有一个表单，该表单的动作
and then inside of here I'm going to have a form, the action for which
将是斜杠登录，将发布其方法。
will be slash login, the method for which will be post.
我将在此处执行最佳做法，我不希望我的用户名和密码
I'll do best practices here, I don't want my username and password
在现实世界中存储在人们的自动完成历史中。
in the real world being stored in people's autocomplete histories.
我来输入一下，自动填充等于正确测量，自动对焦
Let me do input, autocomplete equals off for good measure, autofocus
为了方便起见，名称等于用户的名称，
for convenience, name equals the user's name,
占位符，如前所述等于名称，然后键入等于文本。
placeholder as before equals name, and then type equals text.
然后在这里，输入类型等于提交。
And then down here, input type equals submit.
因此，这与我们以前的注册表格几乎相同
So this is almost the same to our previous forms for registering
等等，但是现在我将使用它进行登录。
and so forth, but now I'm going to use it for login purposes.
因此，让我们快速检查一下。
So let's do a quick check.
让我回到我的应用程序，运行Flask，
Let me go back to my application, do Flask run,
我将继续打开我的URL，首先看到的是错误，
I'm going to go ahead and open up my URL, and first error, let's see,
找不到模板。
template not found.
好的，这实际上是可以预期的。
OK, so that's actually expected.
我知道我没有创建索引点HTML，
I kind of knew I didn't create index dot HTML,
所以现在我可以确定该错误了。
so I'm OK with that error for now.
让我继续放大，因为我故意
Let me go ahead and zoom out though, because I deliberately
想去我的斜线登录路线，因为我想先测试一下。
wanted to go to my slash login route because I wanted to test that first.
那似乎行得通。
That seems to be working.
现在，让我们继续创建不存在的文件，
Now let's go ahead and create the file that doesn't exist,
索引点HTML，因此将索引点HTML放在模板的我的登录文件夹中，
index dot HTML, so index dot HTML, put this in my login folder in templates,
我将非常类似地执行此操作。
and I'm going to do this one pretty similarly.
我将继续复制粘贴内容只是为了节省一些击键，
I'm going to go ahead and copy paste just to save a bit of keystrokes,
但在这里我要说的是，您尚未登录，因为我确实
but here I'm going to say, you are not logged in because I literally
尚未实现该功能。
haven't implemented that feature yet.
这是很合理的。
So that's pretty reasonable.
让我继续并重新启动Flask。
Let me go ahead and restart Flask.
让我进入索引，我确实应该看到您尚未登录。
Let me go to my index, and I should see, indeed, you are not logged in.
但是，如果我要登录，则会看到我的登录表单。
But if I go to login, I see my login form.
因此，让它更具交互性。
So let's make this a little more interactive.
让我在这里进入索引点HTML并说：
Let me go into index dot HTML here and say,
您尚未登录，请使用href斜杠登录，登录和有效期。
you are not logged in, a href slash login, log in, period.
让我们创建一个更好的用户界面。
Let's create a better user interface.
因此，让我重新运行Flask，让我回到我的网页，点击reload，
So let me rerun Flask, let me go back to my web page, hit reload,
现在我有了用户界面的起点，
and now I have the beginnings of user interface,
超级简单，但是非常类似于网站
super simple, but very similar to a website
如果显示网页，则表明您未登录，
where if you're presented with the web page, you're not logged in,
系统会为您提供一个链接或一个按钮或用于登录的内容。
you're given a link or a button or something to log in.
如果我单击此按钮，这很简单
And if I click this, it's just a simple get
请求（这是链接的默认设置）以减少登录。
request, which is the default for links, to slash login.
所以我们快到了。
So we're almost there.
我们几乎有能力登录。
We almost have the ability to log in.
让我们对信息进行一些处理。
Let's do something with the information.
因此，让我回到应用程序点py，当用户登录时，
So let me go back to application dot py, and when the user logs in,
我到底想发生什么？
what is it I want to have happen exactly?
好吧，如果他们登录，首先，我想支持多个，
Well if they log in, first of all, I want to support multiple,
我想在这里支持帖子。
I want to support post here.
因此，为了隐私起见，请允许我这样做。
So let me do that for privacy's sake.
然后让我继续执行此操作。
And then let me go ahead and do this.
如果请求点方法等于发布，则与以前一样，
If request dot method equals post, as before,
让我们继续，并记住该用户已登录。
let's go ahead and remember that user logged in.
然后将用户重定向到斜线。
And then redirect user to slash.
否则，让我们继续呈现登录表单。
Else let's go ahead and render the login form.
所以我还没有完成。
So I'm not done yet.
但这是关键思想。
But this is the key idea.
我需要以某种方式记住该用户已登录。
I need to somehow remember that the user logged in.
那我该怎么做呢？
So how can I do this?
好吧，一个，我可以从请求点形式获取用户名。
Well, one, I can get the user's name from request dot form dot get name.
我应该假设是的，没关系，我们暂时不会对此进行验证。
And I should assume that, yeah, that's OK, we won't validate that for now.
我要如何处理用户名？
And what do I want to do with the user's name?
我想将其存储在会话中。
I want to store it in the session.
那么会话到底是什么？
So what exactly is the session?
事实证明，只要您拥有此手印，就像
Well it turns out that as soon as you have this hand stamp, it's like,
它也有点像大衣检查。
it's kind of like a coat check too.
我的意思不是在这里添加太多的隐喻，
I don't mean to add too many metaphors here,
但是在高档餐厅，如果您喜欢将外套递给某人，
but in a fancy restaurant if you like hand your coat to someone,
他们经常把它放在壁橱里，然后
they'll often put it in the closet and then
给你一个数字，从某种意义上讲
hand you back a number, which in some sense
有点像这样的线索，一点印章
is a little clue like this, a little hand stamp
这样他们就可以排队。
so that they can line you up.
它可能不应该只是一张笑脸，否则所有人
It probably shouldn't just be a smiley face because otherwise everyone
会得到相同的外套，但是它们给您某种标识符，
would get the same coat back, but they give you some kind of identifier,
他们把你的外套放在衣架，水桶或壁橱里的某个地方。
and they put your coat into some hanger, a bucket, or some space in that closet.
那么为什么这在这里有意义呢？
So why is this relevant here?
Web浏览器世界也发生了同样的情况。
Well the same is happening in the world of web browsers.
当您获得一个独特的cookie时，这将为您提供一个独特的衣架。
When you get a unique cookie, that's giving you a unique hanger.
我真的应该早就想到这个比喻了，
I really should have thought this metaphor through before,
但是您会得到一个独特的衣架，可以放所有物品，
but you're given a unique hanger where all of your stuff can go,
包括你的外套，但在这种情况下，包括任何变量
including your coat, but in this case, including any variables
你想记住。
you want to remember.
因此，感谢Flask，
So with that said, what I have access to thanks to Flask,
但实际上要感谢HTTP，这个特殊的变量称为session。
but really thanks to HTTP, is this special variable called session.
这是一个特殊的变量，一方面
That is a special variable in that it's at the one hand,
一方面是全球性的，这意味着我可以在任何地方使用它，
on the one hand global, which means I can use it everywhere,
但花哨的东西，它绑定到当前用户。
but fancy enough, it's tied to the current user.
因此，即使我们所有人现在都使用Zoom来访问我的网址，
So even if all of us on Zoom right now visit my URL,
无论如何，我们每个人
as is kind of happening anyway, each of us
正在获取我们自己的名为session的变量的副本。
is getting our own copy of a variable called session.
它是通过cookie机制在幕后实现的。
And it's implemented underneath the hood by way of this cookie mechanism.
当您访问我的应用程序时，我们每个人都会获得不同的Cookie值。
Each of us when you visit my application are getting a different cookie value.
该cookie值就像映射到壁橱中的另一个衣架一样
That cookie value is like mapping to a different hanger in the closet
这样我的数据就会放在这个挂架上，您的数据就会放在那个挂架上，
so that my data will go on this hanger, your data will go on that hanger,
等等。
and so forth.
现在，我为这个行之有效的隐喻感到自豪。
And now I'm actually kind of proud of this metaphor that's working out OK.
衣架将是存储我们所有个人数据的地方。
The hanger is going to be where all of our individual data is stored.
我们要存储什么？
What do we want to store?
这很简单，我们只存储用户名，
This is simple, let's just store the user's name,
从而记住我已经登录，或者Brian已登录，
thereby remembering that I've logged in, or Brian's logged in,
或Sophia已登录，或Ryan已登录，或其他任何人。
or Sophia's logged in, or Ryan's logged in, or anyone else.
但是我在这里的会话全局变量
But the session global variable here that I've
在第一行中突出显示的内容将由Flask为我们实施
highlighted in this very first line is going to be implemented by Flask for us
以使我们每个用户都获得自己的版本的方式。
in such a way that each of us as users get our own version thereof.
因此，我将非常简单地将其用作Python中的字典。
So I'm going to quite simply use this as a dictionary in Python.
我要继续并将用户名添加到此处的会话中。
I'm going to go ahead and add to the session here the user's name as name.
而且我现在甚至不需要此变量。
And I don't even need this variable now.
让我将其收紧一点。
Let me tighten this up just a little bit.
让我继续，然后将其存储在会话中
Let me go ahead and just store in the session, which
就像这样的衣架，名称的键和用户登录的值
is like this hanger, the key of name and the value of whatever the user logged
在作为。
in as.
并重定向我知道该怎么做。
And redirects I know how to do.
让我继续并返回重定向斜杠，让我摆脱我的伪代码，
Let me go ahead and return redirect slash, let me get rid of my pseudocode,
我想就是这样。
and I think that's it.
对不起，请记住用户已登录。
That is sufficient, excuse me, to remember that a user has logged in.
您在会议中加入了他们的名字，
You sort of put their name in the session,
但这是我们需要检查该值的理由。
but then it stands to reason that we need to check for this value.
现在，让我们改进索引点HTML，目前
So now let's improve index dot HTML, which at the moment
只是盲目地说总是，您尚未登录。
just blindly says always, you are not logged in.
好吧，让我们真正做出决定，而不仅仅是硬编码。
Well let's actually make that decision, not just hard code that.
因此，让我们这样做。
So let's do this.
如果不是会话点获取名称，这是语法
If not session dot get name, this is the syntax
说如果会话中没有名字，
for saying if there's no name in the session,
然后继续并返回重定向斜杠登录。
then go ahead and return redirect slash login.
因此，如果会话中没有名字，那
So if there's no name in the session, that
表示您还没有告诉我您的名字。
means you haven't given me your name yet.
让我通过发送斜线登录来强迫您使用。
Let me force you to by sending you to slash login.
否则，继续渲染模板。
Otherwise go ahead and render the template.
好吧，那么我现在还能做些什么？
All right, well what more might I do now?
好吧，让我在这里进入我的索引文件。
Well let me go into my index file here.
而且，不仅要天真地对其进行硬编码，还请注意我现在能做什么。
And instead of just naively hard coding this, watch what I can now do.
我可以在这里说，用Jinja语法，而不是花括号，而不是块语法，
I can in here say, in Jinja syntax, not the curly braces, not the block syntax,
不是for循环，也可以使用if条件。
not the for loop, you can also use if conditions.
如果会话点名称存在，那么我可以这样说：
If session dot name exists, then I can say something like,
您以会话点名称，句点登录。
you are logged in as session dot name, period.
然后，我可能会有类似href等于斜杠注销的内容。
Then I might have something like a href equals slash logout.
还不存在，但是我们可以返回到该位置，然后注销。
Doesn't exist yet, but we can come back to that, log out.
否则，如果没有会话名称，那么我们假设
Else if there is no session name, then let's assume
用户确实没有登录，然后说您尚未登录，
that the user is indeed not logged in and then say, you are not logged in,
登录。
log in.
因此，如果我做对了，让我继续并在此处停止服务器。
So if I did this right, let me go ahead and stop the server here.
让我继续并重新运行Flask run，重新加载我的表格，
Let me go ahead and rerun Flask run, reload my form,
我仍然看到，确定，错误的URL。
I still see, OK, wrong URL.
让我去索引。
Let me go to index.
哦，不，这是对的。
Oh no, this is right.
我使用斜线登录，方法不允许，
I'm on slash login, method's not allowed,
我认为圣地亚哥已经指出了我之前犯的错误，
I think Santiago already pointed out what mistake I made earlier,
我刚才重复了。
which I just repeated.
让我进入应用程序点py。
Let me go to application dot py.
我需要在这里支持多种方法。
I need to support multiple methods here.
我还想支持get，以便我可以根据需要实际渲染我的模板。
I also want to support get so that I can actually render my template as needed.
因此，让我继续并重新运行该服务器。
So let me go ahead and rerun this server.
在这里，我们使用斜杠登录。
Here we go it's slash login.
并注意会发生什么。
And notice what happens.
让我放大一下。
Let me zoom in on this.
让我摆脱登录名，直接去斜线，
Let me get rid of the login and just go to slash,
请注意，我立即被重定向。
notice that I'm immediately redirected.
让我们做我们上周所做的事情。
Let's do what we did last week.
让我们打开检查器。
Let's open up the inspector.
让我们转到“网络”选项卡。
Let's go to the Network tab.
让我们再次访问slash并按Enter，瞧，注意会发生什么。
Let's again visit slash and hit Enter, voila, notice what happens.
如果我访问该请求，请放大Chrome的“网络”标签，
If I visit that request, zoom in on Chrome's network tab,
向下滚动到响应标题，请注意，我们得到了302，
scroll down to response headers, notice that we get a 302, found,
这是一个类似301的重定向代码，而该位置实际上是
which is a redirect code like 301, and the location is actually,
如果您在这里查看，请使用斜线登录。
if you look over here, slash login.
因此，HTTP的所有机制都重新发挥了作用。
So all the mechanics of HTTP are coming back into play.
好的，让我继续并以David的身份登录，单击Submit，太棒了。
All right let me go ahead and log in as David, click Submit, amazing.
您以David身份登录。
You are logged in as David.
注意发生了什么。
Notice what's going on.
我现在在斜线。
I'm now at the slash route.
的确如此，因此这并不适用，因此我实际上看到的是索引点HTML。
This is true, so this does not apply, so I'm actually seeing index dot HTML.
并注意我不小心单击了注销，让我们对其进行修复。
And notice I accidentally clicked log out, let's fix that.
让我们给我们我们的登出路线。
Let's give us our logout route.
所以我们开始。
So here we go.
应用程序点路由斜线注销，def注销，然后在这里我
App dot route slash logout, def log out, and then in here I
只需要忘记用户已经登录即可。
need to just forget that the user has logged in.
有几种不同的方法可以做到这一点。
And there's a few different ways to do this.
现在让我做最简单的事情。
Let me do it the simplest for now.
会话名称不等于。
Session name equals none.
让我们将您的名字改成我的名字，或者改成我的名字，
Let's just change whatever your name is or my name is to none,
然后让我们将重定向返回到斜杠。
then let's return redirect back to slash.
因此，让我们看看现在会发生什么。
So let's see what happens now.
让我重新启动服务器。
Let me restart the server.
让我回到索引页面。
Let me go back to my index page.
因为我仍然在这里登录，所以我将继续注销。
Because I'm still logged in here, I'm going to go ahead and log out.
好的，让我继续并以Brian的身份登录，例如，提交。
OK, let me go ahead and log in as Brian, for instance, submit.
您以Brian身份登录。
You are logged in as Brian.
并注意我可以重新加载，可以关闭选项卡，也可以重新打开选项卡。
And notice I can reload, I can close the tab, I can reopen the tab.
多亏了我的浏览器代表cookie，所有这些都被记住了。
It's all being remembered thanks to my browser representing the cookie.
实际上，您可以看到。
And in fact, you can see that.
让我去检查，让我去网络标签，
Let me go to inspect, let me go to the Network tab,
然后让我重新加载同一页面。
and let me reload this same page.
重新加载。
Reload.
请在此处注意此响应。
Notice this response here.
在200中，请注意，如果我在此处向下滚动到请求标题，请注意
In 200, notice that if I scroll down here to the request headers, notice
我的浏览器正在请求，哎呀，对不起，
that my browser is requesting, oops, sorry,
请注意，我的浏览器正在请求斜杠，但请注意，如果我向下滚动，
notice that my browser is requesting slash, but notice if I scroll down,
下来，下来，没有，我们走了，下来，下来，下来，注意，我不知道
down, down, nope, there we go, down, down, down, notice, unbeknownst to me
也许一直以来你都不知道，
and unbeknownst to you perhaps all this time,
我的浏览器还显示了手戳并说出了我的cookie值
my browser is also presenting the hand stamp and saying my cookie value
会话等于35456点，点，点。
is session equals 35456 dot, dot, dot.
一般来说，告诉别人您的会话很不好，因为现在
Generally speaking it's bad to tell other people your sessions because now
你们都可以假装自己来劫持我的会话，
you could all hijack my session by pretending to be me,
但当然，此应用程序不会执行任何操作。
but of course this application doesn't do anything.
但是，请勿使用您关心的帐户执行此操作。
But don't do this with accounts that you care about.
没有人应该看到您的cookie值。
No one should be seeing your cookie values.
所以我们实际上在那里看到了cookie，它来自服务器
So we actually see the cookie there, and it came from the server
我第一次来。
the very first time I visited.
好吧，那里有什么问题吗？
All right, any questions on that there?
布莱恩：饼干是否永远存在，
BRIAN: Does the cookie just exist forever,
还是有一段时间消失？
or is there a time when it disappears?
DAVID J. MALAN：好问题。
DAVID J. MALAN: Good question.
Cookie会永远存在还是有时间限制？
Does the cookie live forever or is there a time limit?
这取决于您如何配置它。
It depends on how you configure it.
因此，此Cookie将具有默认时间限制
So this cookie will have a default time limit
数分钟，数小时或数天的时间，此时间将到期
of some number of minutes or hours or days, after which it will expire
除非服务器为我刷新它。
unless the server refreshes it for me.
不过，您可以设置永久保存的Cookie，
You can, though, set cookies that do last forever,
您可能不想为登录的概念做任何事情，因为赔率
which you probably don't want to do for the notion of logging in because odds
是我们所有人不小心走开了吗
are all of us have accidentally walked away
像实验室计算机或朋友的计算机一样，却忘记了注销。
from like a lab computer or a friend's computer, forgotten to log out.
很高兴知道我最终会
It's at least nice to know that eventually I'll
从该站点自动注销，
be logged out automatically from this site,
这就是所谓的会话cookie，它最终会过期。
and that's what's called a session cookie, one that eventually expires.
但是当您访问网站时，它也很有用，
But it's also useful when you visit websites,
您会注意到某些网站上的按钮会说“记住我”，
you notice that some websites have those buttons that say remember me,
或类似的东西。
or something like that.
好吧，您实际上可以设置永久性Cookie，而不仅仅是
Well you can actually set permanent cookies that don't just
在您的计算机上存储一些随机值，
store some random value on your computer,
他们实际上存储了一些信息
they actually store some piece of information
随后将其预先填充到表单中。
that gets prefilled into forms subsequently.
这对于记住您首选的网站设置很有用
And this is useful to remember your preferred settings for a website
如果您已自定义某项内容，如果您
if you've customized something, if you're
在夜间或白天模式之类的情况下，
in night mode or day mode or something like that,
它可以记住这些设置。
it can remember those kinds of settings.
甚至CS50的网站都会记住您的选择。
And even CS50's website remembers what your selection was.
当您登录CS50的某些网站时，
When you log in to some of CS50's websites,
您有时会看到哈佛或耶鲁大学的登录提示。
you'll sometimes see a login prompt for Harvard or Yale.
如果您从未注意到，我对此表示遗憾，因为我们付出了很多努力
And if you've never noticed, I regret this because we put a lot of effort
记住这一点，它会记住您上次使用哈佛大学时
into this, it remembers if you used Harvard last time
或上次使用耶鲁，这样您就不必不断互动
or used Yale last time so you don't have to constantly interact
通过下拉菜单，它只会记住您的隐含偏好。
with the dropdown, it just remembers your implied preference.
我们使用cookie来做到这一点。
We do that using cookies.
因此，如果有兴趣在家中锻炼，一定要真正开始
And so as an at home exercise if of interest, truly do start
打开浏览器的“网络”标签，开始查看这些标题，
opening the browser's network tab, start looking at those headers,
然后您就可以推断出当今所有网站的工作方式。
and you can begin to infer how all of today's websites work.
实际上，它正成为越来越多的挑战
And in fact it's becoming increasingly a challenge
使用Cookie来实现功能，因为长话短说，很多浏览器
to implement things with cookies because long story short, a lot of the browser
制造商终于开始禁用所谓的第三方
manufacturers are finally starting to disable what are called third party
Cookie，即来自其他服务器的广告风格的Cookie，
cookies, those sort of advertising style cookies that come from other servers,
不是gmail.com，不是Facebook.com，而是其他经常使用的服务器
not gmail.com, not Facebook.com, but other servers that are all too often
用来追踪人。
used to track people.
但是最近，尤其是在欧盟，现在在美国，
But recently, especially in the EU and now more recently in the US,
如果您曾经必须点击说我接受Cookie的框，
if you've ever had to click boxes saying I accept cookies,
我接受必要的cookie，依此类推，老实说，
I accept the necessary cookies, and so forth, honestly this
这是一个不错的主意，但在其中也有点傻
is sort of a nice idea, but it's also a little silly in
现在世界只是在限制您和我不断地点击
that now the world is just conditioning you and me to just constantly click
这些盒子没有真正考虑它。
these boxes without really thinking of it.
但是，您真正要做的是授予权限
But what you're really doing is granting permission
当您单击这些框以允许您的手被盖章时。
when you click those boxes to allow your hand to be stamped.
好的，关于Cookie的任何问题，
All right, any questions then on cookies,
或关于我们如何实现这种登录机制？
or on how we've gone about implementing this login mechanism?
看到您的任何东西Brian？
Seeing anything on your end Brian?
布莱恩：这里没别的了。
BRIAN: Nothing else here.
戴维·J·马兰（David J. MALAN）：好吧，让我继续前进。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right, well let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续，准备一个例子，我们
Let me go ahead and get ready an example that we
预先制作，将使我们能够探索
made in advance that will allow us to explore
一个成熟的电子商务网站，某种形式的商店。
a full-fledged e-commerce website, a store of some sort.
我们称其为字面上的商店，这次
And we'll call this literally Store and this time
而不是从头开始写东西，让我继续
rather than write things from scratch, let me go ahead
然后从名为store的目录在浏览器中打开内容。
and open things in my browser from a directory called store.
因此，可以在课程的网站上一如既往地使用它。
So this is available as always on the course's website.
让我继续在这里进入商店，让我继续
And let me go ahead here and into store, let me go ahead
并打开应用程序点py，要求
and open up application dot py, requirements
点文本和我的模板，包括布局，书籍和购物车。
dot text, and my templates, including layout, books, and cart.
所以这是诚实阅读的好习惯
So this is a good exercise in honestly reading
别人的大量代码。
someone else's sizable amount of code.
这是几个文件。
It's a few files.
下载这样的程序后，您什至开始学习，
How do you even begin when you've downloaded a program like this,
当您下载了CS50或其他课程的分发代码后，
when you've downloaded distribution code for CS50 or any other course,
您如何开始围绕它进行思考？
how do you begin to wrap your mind around it?
再说一次，如果您了解角色是什么
Well again, if you understand what the roles are
由这些不同的文件播放，应用程序点py是您的控制器，
played by these different files, application dot py is your controller,
以点HTML和模板结尾的任何内容都是一个视图，
anything ending in dot HTML and templates is a view,
您可以开始跟随面包屑了
you can begin to sort of follow the breadcrumbs
并找出这些文件中的内容。
and figure out what does what in these files.
因此，让我们从应用程序点py开始。
So let's start with application dot py.
请注意，我正在导入CS50的库，一堆Flask功能，
Notice I'm importing CS50's library, a bunch of Flask functionality,
包括会话支持。
including session support.
在此之下，我将像以前一样初始化应用程序，
Below that I'm initializing the application as I've done before,
在下面，我正在连接到一个数据库
and below that I'm connecting to a database which
在商店中包含一大堆产品，在这种情况下为书籍。
contains a whole bunch of products in a store, books in this case.
然后，我配置会话，我们就这样做了，
I then configure sessions, and we just did that,
因此该代码与以前相同。
so that code is the same as before.
而且我认为我们可以开始推断该网站将要做什么。
And I think we can begin to infer what this website's going to do.
因此，我的默认斜线路由具有索引功能，
So my default slash route has an index function,
看起来该数据库中有一个名为books的表，
and it looks like there's a table in that database called books,
所以我要从书本中选明星，以使我得到所有书本。
so I'm selecting star from books to get me all the books.
然后看起来好像我正在渲染一个名为books dot HTML的模板，
And then it looks like I'm rendering a template called books dot HTML,
而且我正在传递那些书。
and I'm passing in those books.
因此，让我们跟随此处的面包屑，进入点HTML的书中。
So let's follow the breadcrumbs here and go into books dot HTML.
看起来书籍点HTML扩展了布局点HTML。
It looks like books dot HTML extends layout dot HTML.
好吧，让我们看一下布局点HTML。
All right, let's look at layout dot HTML.
那里没有什么有趣的事情，只是样板占位符
Nothing really interesting going on there, just the boilerplate placeholder
我们以前见过的代码。
code that we've seen before.
因此，我将结束并假定它并不有趣。
So I'm going to close that and assume that it's not interesting.
去过也做过。
Been there, done that.
但是，如果我们继续下去的话，点点HTML的书可能会有些麻烦。
But books dot HTML, if we continue further, is a little juicy.
我们的块体位于第3行和第14行之间。
We've got my block body between lines 3 and 14.
在这里，我有一个H1标签，只是在页面顶部说书。
In there I've got a H1 tag just saying books at the top of the page.
然后我的模板中有一个for循环，
And then I've got a for loop in my template,
再次使用Jinja语法，其下方的H2显然与
again using Jinja syntax, that has below that an H2 with apparently
书名，然后是书名，
the title of a book, and then below that, a form,
而且我以前没有看过所有这些功能，
and I haven't seen all of these features before,
就像我不确定隐藏的含义是什么，但是请注意，我确实可以识别“提交”
like I'm not sure yet what hidden means, but notice that I do recognize a Submit
具有添加到购物车值的按钮。
button that has a value of add to cart.
听起来好像我们正在为amazon.com实施购物目录
So it sounds like we're implementing a shopping catalog for like an amazon.com
或某种在线书店。
or some kind of bookstore online.
好吧，现在让我们回到应用程序点py，
All right, so now let's go back to application dot py,
让我们看看购物车。
and let's look in cart.
看起来购物车同时支持get和post，
It looks like cart supports both get and post, all right,
所以也许我正在使用相同的路线来处理两种不同的事情，
so maybe I'm using the same route to handle two different things,
而且我们之前已经看到过。
and we've seen that before.
该功能称为购物车，这很有意义。
The function is called cart, which makes sense.
这个事情，让我们回到这个问题，只是为了初始化我们的会话，
This thing, let's come back to this, just to initialize our session,
我们将回到这一点。
we'll come back to that.
而且看起来该程序没有更多的功能了。
And it looks like there's not much more to this program.
如果get是动词，让我们集中在底部
If get is the verb, let's focus on the bottom
首先，让我们忽略if条件，我在做什么？
first, so let's ignore the if condition, what am I doing?
从书籍ID在此书籍清单中的书籍中选取星号。
Selecting star from books where the ID of the book is in this list of books.
那么，这本书的清单是从哪里来的？
Well, where is this list of books coming from?
会话，引用取消引用，购物车。
Session, quote unquote, cart.
因此，在上一个示例中，我使用了会话来存储您的姓名和我的姓名
So in the last example I used the session to store your name and my name
以及每个用户的每个人的名字。
and everyone's name on a per user basis.
现在，我用它来存储我们称为购物车的东西。
Now I'm using it to store what we'll call a shopping cart.
的确，这就是为什么有购物车的原因，
And indeed, this is the reason why there's a shopping cart,
多亏了我们在剧院的朋友们在舞台上
thanks to our friends at the theater, on stage.
这就是购物车的实现方式
This is how shopping carts are implemented
在网站上，通过引擎盖下的cookie
on websites, via cookies underneath the hood
给你错觉的用户特定的变量，字典
to give you the illusion of user specific variables, dictionaries
您可以在其中存储任何想要的东西。
that you can store anything you want in there.
所以看起来我的会话购物车钥匙要走了
So it looks like my session cart key is going
其值等于整本书的ID。
to have a value equal to the IDs of a whole bunch of books.
我不知道他们现在在那里，但让我们假设
I don't know how they're there yet, but let's assume
这就是我要解释的。
that's what I'm interpreting.
然后在这里，我只是渲染一个称为购物车HTML的模板，
And then down here, I'm just rendering a template called cart dot HTML,
从数据库中传递书籍。
passing in the books from the database.
那么他们如何进入会议的呢？
So how do they get into the session?
好吧，如果用户将表单提交到购物车，
Well, if the user submits the form to the cart,
我认为这段代码是相关的。
I think this code is now relevant.
如果用户张贴到斜杠购物车，它看起来
If the user posts to slash cart, it looks
就像我要获取他们输入的ID一样？
like I'm going to get the ID that they've typed in maybe?
可能是？
Maybe?
如果实际上有一个ID，但不是一个ID，
And if there is in fact an ID, and it's not none,
这不是默认值none，我要
it's not the default value of none, I'm going
继续并将该书的ID附加到购物车中，
to go ahead and append to the cart the ID of that book,
然后将用户重定向到购物车。
and then I'm going to redirect the user to cart.
所以我认为这已经足够复杂了
So I think that's enough complexity that I think it's time
看看实际发生了什么。
to look at what's actually going on.
所以，让我继续做下去。
So let me go ahead and do exactly that.
让我向上滚动并运行Flask run。
Let me scroll up and run Flask run.
让我继续打开我的URL。
Let me go ahead and open my URL.
好吧，这不是最漂亮的网站，但是
OK, it's not the prettiest of website, but it
好像我的数据库中有所有七本《哈利·波特》书，
looks like my database has like all seven Harry Potter books in it,
并注意每个按钮都有一个按钮，添加到购物车，添加到购物车，
and notice that each of them has a button, add to cart, add to cart,
添加到购物车。
add to cart.
让我们看一下HTML源代码，看看有什么
Let's look at the HTML source to see what
我的书生成了HTML模板。
my books dot HTML template generated.
有点有趣。
Kind of interesting.
因此，H1排在最前面。
So there's that H1 books at the top.
这是我的第一本H2书，带有书名。
Here's the first of my H2s with the title of the book.
请注意，这里有一个时髦的符号，因为它就像一个弯引号一样，
Notice that there is this funky symbol here because it's like a curly quote,
这是允许您输出符号的HTML实体之一
so this is one of those HTML entities that lets you output symbols
您无法轻易在键盘上输入。
that you couldn't type easily on your keyboard.
这是我动态输出的第一个表格。
Here's my first form that I dynamically outputted.
我早些时候声称我不知道隐藏的是什么，
And I claimed earlier that I didn't know what hidden was,
但是它确实做到了。
but it does what it says.
它允许您以某种形式提交数据
It allows you to submit a piece of data in a form that
对用户而言是视觉上隐藏的。
is visually hidden from the user.
他们没有可以输入的文本框，但它在那里。
It's not a text box that they can type into but it is there.
最酷的是，通知我给它设置了1。
And what's cool about this is that notice I gave it a value of 1.
但是我以这种形式给了那个隐藏的领域
But in this form I gave that hidden field
值为2，这里为3。
a value of 2, down here a value of 3.
好吧，为什么呢？
Well, why is that?
让我进入IDE片刻，让我在商店dot db上运行SQLite，
Let me go into my IDE for just a moment, let me run SQLite on my store dot db,
让我用点模式向您展示该数据库内部
let me show you with dot schema that inside of this database
是一个工作表，每个工作表都有一个ID，一个标题，仅此而已。
is a books table, each of which has an ID, a title, and that's it.
让我使用SQLite 3和voila从书籍中选择星号，
Let me do select star from books using SQLite 3, and voila,
您不仅看到书籍的标题，
you see not only the titles of the books,
但是唯一的ID会根据其出现的顺序恰当地编号，
but a unique ID numbered aptly according to the order in which they came out,
作为巧合，但是故意的。
as a coincidence, but intentional.
所以现在在这里，让我继续前进，将终端向下移动一点
And so now down here, let me go ahead and move my terminal down a little bit
这里。
here.
让我继续并重新运行Flask run，如果我现在提交以下表格之一，
Let me go ahead and rerun Flask run, and if I now submit one of these forms,
让我们看看发生了什么。
let's see what happens.
加入购物车第一本书。
Add to cart the first book.
有趣的。
Interesting.
我已被重定向到斜杠购物车，注意我有一个有序列表，
I've been redirected to slash cart, and notice I have an ordered list,
第一本书看来是OL标签。
an OL tag, it would seem, with that first book.
让我回到目录。
Let me go back to the catalog.
阿兹卡班的囚徒还不错。
Prisoner of Azkaban was pretty good.
让我们将其添加到购物车中。
Let's add that to cart.
现在我在这里看到了。
Now I see this here.
请注意，如果我重新加载，重新加载，我不会
And notice this, if I reload, reload, I don't
知道为什么我举起我的手，因为我显然在用另一只手，
know why I'm holding up my hand because I'm clearly using my other hand,
但我一次又一次地重新加载页面，
but I'm reloading the page again and again,
它向我确切显示了我的购物车中的内容。
and it's showing me exactly what is in my cart.
那么，这是哪里来的呢？
So where is this coming from?
好吧，如果我们返回到代码，则在后置条件下，此逻辑在这里
Well, if we go back to our code, this logic here under the post condition
正在将ID（一号书，三号书）添加到我的会话的购物车钥匙中。
is adding the ID, book number one, book number three, to my session's cart key.
现在那个购物车钥匙是从哪里来的？
Now where did that cart key come from?
这是我提出的唯一的另一篇文章。
This is the only other piece I proposed we come back to.
我只需要代码顶部的某种方式即可初始化购物车。
I just need some way at the top of my code to initialize the cart.
长话短说，会议中不会有一个叫做购物车的钥匙
And long story short, there's not going to be a key called cart in the session
除非您将其放在此处，例如Flask不会附带名称或购物车。
unless you put it there, like Flask doesn't come with name or cart.
你必须把它放在那里。
You have to put it there.
因此，请注意，如果购物车中没有用引号引起来的报价，
So notice if cart, quote unquote, is not yet in my session,
我只是将其初始化为一个空的Python列表。
I'm just initializing it to an empty Python list.
我可以使用一个集合，我可以使用一个字典，
And I could use a set, I could use a dictionary,
我可以使用任何我想要的东西。
I could use anything I want.
我选择通过列表来保持简单，但这就是
I chose to keep it simple with a list, but that's
我如何记住购物车中的内容。
how I'm remembering what's in my cart.
而且与我们之前的所有示例不同，因为我看到很多人
And unlike all of our previous examples, because I see a bunch of you
现在正在尝试将商品添加到您自己的购物车中，我们每个人
are now trying to add things to your own cart, each of us
看到了不同的购物车。
is seeing different shopping carts.
我们的购物车中都有不同的东西。
We all have different things in our shopping cart.
如果我一直在重新加载图书，那么有多少人尝试添加图书都没关系
If I keep reloading, doesn't matter how many of you are trying to add books
到购物车中，您只是将它们原样添加到购物车中
to your cart, you're only adding them literally to your cart
而不是我的，因为我们手上都有不同的邮票。
and not mine because we all have different stamps on our hand.
好吧，所以在这里，我也鼓励你，下次，你
All right, so here too I would encourage you when you, next time you
在亚马逊上，向购物车中添加一些东西，
go on Amazon and add some things to your cart,
就像从字面上看，这就是引擎盖下发生的所有事情。
like literally, that is all that's happening underneath the hood.
亚马逊肯定还有其他功能，您
And Amazon surely has other features, you
可以更改数量，这很好，您可以将商品添加到愿望清单中，
can change quantities, which is kind of nice, you can add things to wish lists,
很好，但是所有这些，如果您开始查看HTML，
which is nice, but all of that, if you start looking at the HTML,
然后您查看来回的网络请求，所有这些
and you look at the network request going back and forth, all of those
这些天，我们认为理所当然的功能仅仅是
features that we just take for granted these days are just
建立在非常简单，很好，相对简单的HTML上
built on very simple, well, relatively simple HTML
表单，这些输入，这些按钮以及服务器上的这些会话。
forms and these inputs and these buttons and on the server, these sessions.
亚马逊可能会使用不同的语言，不同的框架，
And Amazon might be using a different language, a different framework,
但是所有这些想法都是相同的。
but all of these ideas are the same.
因此，本周确实不是要教你几年的Flask
And so indeed this week is not about teaching you Flask which in a few years
时间可能无关紧要。
time will probably be irrelevant.
这是关于教授这些HTTP请求的思想和原理的
It's about teaching these ideas and principles of these HTTP requests
和响应，这些Cookie，这些会话以及功能
and responses, these cookies, these sessions, and the features
因此我们可以在它们之上建立。
that we can therefore build on top of them.
好吧，我认为我们有时间提出一个最后的例子，
All right, I think we have time for one final example that
现在将从上周带回我们的老朋友JavaScript。
will now bring back our old friend JavaScript from last week.
到目前为止，我们一直在服务器上使用Python
Up until now, we have been using Python on the server
来动态生成HTML，即使我今天的设计
to generate dynamically HTML, and even though my designs today
太可怕了，您当然可以想象向它们添加CSS
have been hideous, you could certainly imagine adding CSS to them
一些类，一些Bootstrap，只是一些漂亮的东西，例如
some, classes, some Bootstrap, just a pretty things up like
尤其是表格，但这与上周相比没有什么新意。
the forms especially, but that's not anything new versus last week.
但是上周我们确实将JavaScript作为一种编程语言，
But last week we did have JavaScript as a programming language,
但这是一种客户端编程语言，
but it was a client side programming language,
至少在我们的使用中。
at least in our usage thereof.
这是获取用户浏览器的一种方式
It was a way of getting the user's browsers
在浏览器上运行代码，条件，函数和循环等
to run code, conditions, and functions, and loops, and so forth on the browser
不在服务器上。
not on the server.
今天，我们再次引入了Python，因此我们现在具备了
Today, we've introduced Python again, so we have now the ability
在服务器上做某事，以及网络在哪里
to do something on the server, and where the web gets
这些日子真正有趣的是当我们结婚时
really interesting these days is when we marry
用户看到的所谓的前端
the so-called front end that the user sees
后端是服务器。
and the backend which is the server.
前端是您和我互动的用户界面
The front end is the user interface you and I interact
使用，后端是Python代码，SQL代码
with, the backend is the Python code, the SQL code
人类永远看不到，但是程序员（程序员）才能看见。
that the humans never see but you, the programmer, see.
那么，我们到底要怎么做才能将这两个组成部分结合起来，
So what can we do to combine these two components, ultimately,
前端和后端？
front end and backend?
好吧，让我们做这样的事情。
Well let's do something like this.
让我们带回旧的节目数据库，让我继续
Let's bring back our old database of shows, and let me go ahead
并在此处快速显示此文件夹中的内容。
and show you quickly what's in this folder here.
在显示中，我们有SQLite 3，显示了点db，它是一个较小的版本
In shows we have SQLite 3 shows dot db, a smaller version
几周前我们玩过的游戏
of what we played with a few weeks back.
我只是为了尺寸而将其削减了
I've whittled this down just for size's sake
只包含电视节目的名称，ID和电视节目的标题
to have only the names, only the IDs of TV shows and the titles of TV shows
就是这样。
and that's it.
我丢掉了收视率，作家和导演等
I threw away the ratings and the writers and the directors and all of that
只是为了只关注标题
just to keep the focus only on the titles
因为现在我们将开始来回发送大量数据
because now we're going to start sending a lot of data back and forth
在互联网上使用Python和JavaScript。
over the internet using Python and JavaScript.
好吧，让我现在继续进行，并提前打开这个示例。
Well let me go ahead now and open up this example as made in advance.
这是在节目中。
And this is in shows.
我们将在这里看到一些文件，应用程序
And we'll see a few files here, application
点py，要求点文字和我的模板，
dot py, requirements dot text, and my templates,
分别是索引，布局和搜索。
which are index and layout and search.
好的，那么一堆，但不超过我们之前真正见过的。
All right, so a bunch but not more than we've really seen before.
让我们继续吧，我早些时候被骗了。
And let's go ahead and, I kind of cheated earlier.
我没有看需求。
I didn't look at requirements.
但我不妨考虑一下良好措施的要求。
But I might as well look at requirements for good measure.
这只是需求点文本中可能还包含其他内容的示例：
Here's just an example of what else might be in requirements dot text:
CS50库和Flask。
CS50 library and Flask.
再说一次，这些是预先安装在IDE中的，
And again, those are preinstalled in the IDE,
但是我们这样做是为了让您如果喜欢冒险并尝试
but we do this so that if you get adventurous and try
在您自己的Mac或PC上运行这些东西，您已经完成了所有配置
running these things on your own Mac or PC, you have all of the configuration
您需要的。
that you need.
好吧，让我们像以前一样从应用程序点py开始，
Well let's start as before with applications dot py,
让我继续先做。
and let me go ahead and do this first.
让我先运行此东西，以便我们实际上可以看到该应用程序的运行情况
Let me run this thing first so we can actually see the app in motion
然后了解它是如何工作的。
and then understand how it works.
因此，如果我访问此站点，请继续输入办公内容。
So if I visit this, let me go ahead and type in office.
好吧，什么都没有发生。
All right, nothing happens yet.
让我单击“搜索”。
Let me click Search.
好的。
OK.
然后，我看到所有提及办公室的节目的大项目符号列表，所以没有
I then see a big bulleted list of all shows that mention office, so not
办公室本身，但一个办公室。
The Office per se, but an office.
让我继续放大此处并查看URL。
And let me go ahead and zoom out here and look at the URLs.
让我回到这里。
Let me go back here.
我要指出的是，我们处在斜线路线上。
Let me point out that we're at the slash route.
同样，斜线在那里，只是Chrome
Again, the slash is there, it's just Chrome
这些天默认情况下将其隐藏。
is hiding it by default these days.
当我搜索诸如office之类的内容并按Enter键时，
And when I search for something like office and hit Enter,
请注意，我最终以斜杠搜索，问号，q等于办公室。
notice that I end up at slash search, question mark, q equals office.
所以我从Google那里借鉴了一些灵感，对吗？
So I borrowed some inspiration from Google, right?
上周我有点被骗，我真的只是
I kind of cheated last week where I really only
实现了Google的前端，HTML表单，
implemented the front end to Google, the HTML form,
然后让Google找到我一些猫和狗等等。
and then I let Google find me some cats and some dogs and so forth.
但是现在，有了Python，您现在可以
But now as, with Python, you now have the ability
实现该应用程序的双方。
to implement both sides of that application.
因此，如果我在这里查看源代码，请注意
So if I look at the source code here, notice
我似乎要返回一个非常大的无序列表项列表，
that I seem to be returning a really big unordered list of list items that
再次代表与办公室有关的展览的所有标题。
represent, again, all the titles of office related shows.
好吧，这很好，但是这
All right, this is fine and good, but this
就像老式的Web编程一样，您可以在其中填写
is of like old school web programming where you fill out
表单，您按Enter键，然后开始繁荣。
a form, you hit Enter, and boom.
但是这些日子大多数时候回想起您每次访问网站时，
But these days recall most any time you visit a website,
一次发生了很多事情。
lots is happening at once.
您在这里进行了一些自动填充，
You've got some autocomplete going on here,
您会在此处弹出聊天消息，
you've got chat messages popping up here,
您在这里有一张正在自动移动的地图
you've got a map over here that's automatically moving
Uber的一辆小汽车同时在行驶。
and a little car for Uber is moving around at the same time.
与当今的网络一样，如果您愿意的话，可以使用Web 2.0，
Like the web of today, web 2.0 if you will,
这不是一个专业术语，而只是一个流行词，
which is not a technical term as much as it is a buzzword,
指的是越来越动态的网络互动
refers to just increasingly dynamic web interactions
在用户和计算机之间。
between users and computers.
借助JavaScript和您自己的后端，
And with JavaScript and with your own backend,
无论是Python还是其他东西，您现在都可以
be it Python or something else, you can now
也开始构建这些更动态的界面。
begin to build these more dynamic interfaces as well.
当我开始输入OFFICE时，这不是很酷吗？
Wouldn't it be cool if when I start typing O F F I C E,
我们实际上立即看到了结果。
we actually immediately saw the results.
我们已经看到了这一点。
And we've seen this already.
上周，记得我开始搜寻
Last week, remember that I started searching
对于所有以A开头的单词，我使用了一个非常大的字典
for all words that start with A, and I used a really large dictionary
从p集合5开始，那是140,000个单词，但仅仅是个单词。
from p set 5, but that was 140,000 words but just words.
这个标题数据库大几兆字节。
This database of titles is several megabytes large.
而且我不一定要发送整个数据库
And I don't necessarily want to send the entire database
到浏览器中的电影数量之一，由于性能和尺寸的原因，
of movies to the browser, one, because of performance and size,
还有两个，知识产权。
and maybe two, intellectual property.
我真的不希望向每个用户发送我的整个数据库。
I don't really want to send every user my entire database.
您可以想象要对您的数据保持更多控制
You can imagine wanting to keep a little more control over the data you're
提供，要求用户登录或为您的服务等付款。
providing, requiring users to log in or pay for your service or the like.
因此，您可能希望浏览器与服务器对话是有原因的
So there's reasons where you might want the browser to talk to the server
并且仅获取用户正在搜索的数据，而不是全部。
and only get the data the user is searching for, not the whole thing.
因此，让我们做到这一点。
So let's do that.
让我们以这种方式增强该节目的应用程序
Let's enhance this show's application in such a way
它实际上可以更动态地执行任务，
that it actually does things more dynamically,
但首先让我们了解一下它是如何工作的。
but let's first understand how it works.
所以我在这里有几个库，CS50和Flask。
So I have a couple of libraries here, CS50's and Flask.
我在这里配置Flask。
I'm configuring Flask here.
然后，我在这里配置数据库。
I'm then configuring my database here.
在这里，我只有一条非常简单的路线
Down here, I just have a very simple route
呈现索引点HTML，显然，让我们看一下
that renders index dot HTML, which apparently, let's take a look,
具有这样的形式，非常简单，与上周非常相似，
has that form, very simple, very similar to last week,
与今天非常相似，到目前为止，我们已经完成了所有表格。
very similar to today, all of the forms we've done thus far.
这里的名字等于q，其他所有的东西都是样板。
Here's that name equals q, and everything else is pretty boilerplate.
因此，让我们现在删除该文件。
So let's get rid of that file now.
布局也很漂亮，看起来像过去。
The layout, also pretty boilerplate, it looks like things in the past.
因此，让我们也关闭它，然后返回到索引，应用程序点py。
So let's close that one as well and go back to index, application dot py.
因此，多汁的部分似乎是搜索路线。
So the juicy part seems to be the search route.
这是上周我们改用Google时缺少的部分
And this was the piece we were missing last week when we used Google instead
找我们一些猫和狗。
to find us some cats and some dogs.
这里我有一条叫做斜线搜索的路由，一个函数
Here I have a route called slash search, a function
被称为该路线的搜索，
called search that will be called for that route,
这是SQL和Python的完美结合。
and here is kind of a nice amalgam of SQL and Python.
我要给自己一个变量，叫做
I'm going to give myself a variable called
显示，这将是所有行的结果
shows, which is going to be the result of all of the rows
当我执行此命令时会回来。
that come back when I execute this.
从标题类似于该占位符问号的节目中选择星号。
Select star from shows where title is like this placeholder question mark.
现在我要插入什么插件？
Now what am I going to plug-in?
请注意，乍一看有点神秘，
Notice it's a little cryptic at first glance,
但我似乎是从请求中获取用户的输入q
but I seem to be taking the user's input, q, from request
dot args dot get，显然是因为args这个词，所以使用了get，
dot args dot get, so that's using get apparently because of the word args,
现在还没有形成，它是请求点参数。
and it's not form now, it's request dot args.
所以我得到了用户的q值，在我的情况下就是办公室，而
So I'm getting the user's q value, which was office in my case, and just
快速检查一下，百分比是多少
as a quick check, what's with the percent
在左边和右边的迹象？
signs on the left and the right?
因为今天我们已经看到了很多百分号，但是它们是不同的。
Because we've seen a lot of percent signs today, but these are different.
也许在聊天中？
Perhaps in the chat?
在这种情况下，这些百分号代表什么？
What do these percent signs represent in this context?
布莱恩，您想回应共识吗？
Brian, you want to echo the consensus?
布莱恩：是的，有人说他们是SQL占位符。
BRIAN: Yeah, people are saying they're SQL placeholders.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，所以是SQL通配符占位符。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so SQL wildcard placeholders.
这意味着左侧为零个或多个字符，右侧为零个或多个字符。
That means zero or more characters to the left, zero or more to the right.
这就是为什么我一开始会与Office进行比赛的原因，
This is why I was getting matches with office at the beginning of the word,
办公室在最后，办公室在中间。
office at the end, and office in the middle.
如果我真的想成为肛门我可以摆脱百分号
If I really wanted to be anal I could get rid of the percent signs
只需要一个完美的搭配，但这不是我的目标
and require only a perfect match, but that's not my goal
通过这种特定的实现。
with this particular implementation.
一旦我取回所有这些，哎呀，一旦我取回所有这些行
Once I get back all of, whoops, once I get back all of these rows
我在这里一行，返回渲染模板，搜索点HTML，
I have here a line, return render template, search dot HTML,
传递所有这些节目。
passing in all of those shows.
因此，最后要看的是搜索点HTML。
So the last thing to look at is search dot HTML.
这非常简单，而且肯定像一个小时前一样
It's pretty simple, and surely like an hour ago
这看起来超级神秘。
this would have looked super cryptic.
坦率地说，它看起来仍然很神秘。
It frankly might very well still look cryptic.
但是一旦您自己开始使用此语法
But once you start using this syntax yourself
您会看到，哦，这只是一个模板
you'll see that, oh, this is just a template that
允许我动态输出LI标签的无序列表，每个标签
is allowing me to dynamically output an unordered list of LI tags, each
其中代表已传递到此模板中的节目的标题。
of which represents the title of a show that's been passed into this template.
好的。
All right.
所以现在，最后的繁荣。
So now then the final flourish.
让我们着手增强此应用程序，以使它不存在任何形式
Let's go about enhancing this application so that there is no form
以相同的方式提交，但是所有逻辑
to submit in the same way, but instead all of the logic
实际上发生在JavaScript和后端之间。
actually happens between JavaScript and the backend.
我将继续进行，并首先执行此操作。
I'm going to go ahead and do this first.
我将在这里回到应用程序点py，而不是在这里，
I'm going to go back to application dot py here, and instead of this here,
我要继续执行以下操作：我要继续进行
I'm going to go ahead and do the following: I'm going to go ahead
而不是渲染模板，我要
and instead of rendering a template, I'm going
使用称为jsonify的新功能。
to use a new function called jsonify.
这是一个有趣的名字，我必须在这里导入它。
It's kind of a funny name, and I have to import it up here.
因此，让我导入jsonify。
So let me import jsonify.
事实证明，jsonify或json表示JavaScript对象表示法。
It turns out that jsonify, or json, means JavaScript Object Notation.
一会儿，我们将看到它的外观。
And we'll see what it looks like in a moment.
但是世界在几年前就在格式上进行了标准化
But the world years ago standardized on a format
用于在服务器和浏览器之间传输数据
for transmitting data between servers and browsers
使用非常轻量级的文本格式Jason或JSON JavaScript对象
using a very lightweight text format, Jason, or json, JavaScript Object
符号。
Notation.
Jsonify是一个Flask函数，需要一个Python列表或一个Python字典
Jsonify is a Flask function that takes a Python list or a Python dictionary
并将其转换为json格式。
and converts it into json format.
因此，我们稍后将看到这一点。
So we'll see this in just a moment.
所以请注意，我现在正在返回节目的jsonification
So notice that I'm now returning the jsonification of the show's
变量，它只是从数据库点执行返回的行。
variable, which recall is just the rows that came back from db dot execute.
因此，让我们看看实际情况。
So let's see this in action.
我实际上要去我的，让我继续
I'm actually going to go to my, let me go ahead
并重新启动服务器，因为我做了一些更改。
and restart the server because I've made some changes.
让我继续，现在转到服务器斜杠搜索，问号，
Let me go ahead and now go to the server slash search, question mark,
q等于办公室。
q equals office.
因此，我将手动访问此URL，然后按Enter。
So I'm going to manually visit this URL and hit Enter.
注意回来了。
Notice what comes back.
乍一看，这有点神秘。
It's kind of cryptic at first glance here.
但是请注意，这确实是所谓的JavaScript对象表示法。
But notice this is indeed what's called JavaScript Object Notation.
左上方有一个方括号。
There's a square bracket over here at top left.
这意味着，嘿，浏览器，这里是列表。
This means, hey browser, here comes a list.
大括号，这意味着浏览器
There's a curly brace, which means, hey browser
这是一个字典，在JavaScript中也称为对象。
here comes a dictionary, otherwise known as an object in JavaScript.
引用取消引用ID是此词典中的关键字。
Quote unquote ID is the key in this dictionary.
108878是该密钥的值。
108878 is the value of that key.
这是第二个键，引用引号标题，其值
Here comes the second key, quote unquote title, the value of which
是办公室里美好的一天，引用unquote。
is nice day at the office, quote unquote.
然后有一个闭合的花括号，这是
Then there's a closed curly brace, which is
字典结尾或对象结尾，逗号，
end of the dictionary or end of the object, a comma,
然后还有一堆其他的字典。
and then there's a whole bunch of these other dictionaries.
简而言之，我们在这里看到的只是一个非常原始的文本
So in short, all we're looking at here is a very raw text
基于Python字典的格式再次转换为
based format of a Python dictionary converted to again,
称为json，JavaScript对象表示法，
something called json, JavaScript Object Notation,
从字面上看，这就是它。
which literally, this is about it.
Json使用双引号，冒号，花括号和方括号，
Json uses double quotes, colons, curly braces, and square brackets,
就是这样，代表信息。
and that's about it, to represent information.
所以这太好了。
So this is great.
但这是一个可怕的用户界面，如果用户看到了
But this is a horrible, horrible user interface if what the user sees
这是一团糟吗？
is this mess.
但这不是重点。
But that's not the point.
现在的要点是让我们的后端返回搜索结果的json数组
The point now is to have our backend return a json array of search results
并让浏览器将其转换为HTML。
and let the browser convert it into HTML.
回想一下上周我声称使用JavaScript的情况
Recall from last week I claimed that with JavaScript you
可以变异或更改您的dom，文档
can mutate or change your dom, the document
对象模型，内存中的树。
object model, the tree in memory.
尤其是JavaScript可以做什么
And what you can do in particular with JavaScript
是将更多节点添加到该树。
is add more nodes to that tree.
您可以将更多的东西添加到该家族树中，例如结构。
You can add more things to that family tree like structure.
是的，你好。
So yes, hello.
我们刚刚通过get得到了，嗨，大卫，嗨，大卫，嗨，大卫。
We just got, Hi, David, Hi, David, Hi, David via get.
非常感谢你。
Thank you very much.
好的。
OK.
所以，让我最小化它，让我现在打开，而不是
So let me minimize that, and let me open up now, not
搜索点HTML，我们将不再使用它，
search dot HTML which we're not going to bother using anymore,
而是索引点HTML。
but instead index dot HTML.
还有索引点HTML，我要去
And index dot HTML, you know what, I'm going
继续并在这里借用一些代码。
to go ahead and borrow some code here.
我将继续开放索引点HTML，
I'm going to go ahead and open up index dot HTML,
我将简化此过程。
and I'm going to simplify this.
让我停止服务器。
Let me stop the server.
我要去掉我的布局模板，
I'm going to go ahead and get rid of my layout template,
我将摆脱我的搜索模板
and I'm going to get rid of my search template
因为我不再需要它们了。
because I just don't need them anymore.
因此，我将简化该程序，现在将重点完全放在索引点上。
So I'm going to simplify this program and focus entirely now on index dot
HTML。
HTML.
那我想在这里做什么？
So what do I want to do in here?
我现在需要使用一些JavaScript。
I need to involve some JavaScript now.
那么我该怎么做呢？
So how am I going to go about doing this?
首先，我需要继续使用一个名为jQuery的库，
Well first I need to go ahead and use a library called jQuery,
jQuery的普及程度有所下降，
and jQuery is something that's a little decreasing in popularity,
但Bootstrap仍在使用它，因此我们将
but it's still used by Bootstrap, and so we'll
继续使用它，因为实际上您已经在使用它，
continue using it because you're already including it in fact,
对于您的其他一些示例，但我们需要其他版本。
for some of your other examples, but we need a different version of it.
因此，我将快速浏览Google jQuery CDN，然后转到该网站，
So I'm going to quickly Google jQuery CDN, I'm going to go to this website,
长话短说，有很多图书馆
and long story short, there's a lot of libraries
只需抓住他们的脚本标签就可以使用
out there that you can use by just grabbing their script tag
并在自己的内部使用它。
and using it inside of your own.
所以我要在这里继续，让我来清理标签
So I'm going to go ahead here, and let me just clean up the tag
所以这很长，即使很丑陋，但是可以通过复制和粘贴来完成
so it's all in one long, if ugly, line, but via copying and pasting
该行，我们通常会在分发的问题集中为您完成
that line, which we'll typically do for you in the problem sets in distribution
代码，我将继续将该库复制到我的文件中
code, I'm going to go ahead and copy that library into my file
这样它就在我可以使用的库中。
so that it's among the libraries I can use.
现在，我要像上周一样继续前进，
And now I'm going to go ahead, just as we did last week,
我将在自己的页面头部内添加一个脚本标签，
and I'm going to add a script tag inside of my own pages head,
然后在这里，让我们看看我想在哪里做？
and then down here, let's see, where do I want to do this?
其实你知道吗？
Actually, you know what?
让我继续进行一些不同的操作，只是为了保持一致性
Let me go ahead and do this a little differently just for consistency
与您在网上看到的内容一样。
with what you'll see online.
我要去做，在我身上做这一切
I'm going to go ahead and do this all in my body
因此我们不必担心事情会混乱。
so we don't have to worry about things being out of order.
我们确实会将其全部保留在页面的正文中。
We'll indeed keep it all inside of the page's body.
我要做的就是给我自己：
And what I'm going to do is give myself this:
输入，自动完成功能等于取消引用引用，
an input, autocomplete equals quote unquote off,
自动对焦，然后我将给它一个查询占位符
autofocus, and then I'm going to give it a placeholder of query
然后是一种文字。
and then a type of text.
所以我要在那里有一个非常简单的搜索框
So I'm going to have a very simple search box there
而且我将有一个无序列表，里面什么也没有。
and I'm going to have an unordered list with nothing in it.
这是刻意的。
And that's deliberate for now.
然后，我将导入jQuery库。
Then I'm going to import this, the jQuery library.
然后在我自己的脚本标签内，
And then down here, inside of my own script tags,
这是我要编写实际代码的地方。
this is where I'm going to write the actual code.
我要让输入等于文档点，
I'm going to do let input equals document dot,
让我们像上周一样执行查询选择器，让我继续
let's do query selector just like last week, and let me go ahead
然后选择我的输入标签
and select my input tag.
这行得通。
This works.
我不需要ID或任何课程，因为目前我只有一个输入，
I don't need an ID or any class because at the moment I only have one input,
因此，引用取消引用输入的查询选择器将专门为我提供该标签。
so query selector of quote unquote input will give me that tag specifically.
现在让我继续并添加到该输入中
Let me go ahead now and add to that input
一个事件侦听器，用于侦听key up事件。
an event listener that listens for the key up event.
回想一下上周我们对事件的讨论并提出建议，
Recall from last week our discussion of events, and key up,
就像用户触摸并放开键一样
like the user touching and letting go of the key
是您可以听的事件之一。
is one of the events you can listen for.
每当用户这样做时，我都想调用以下函数，
And any time the user does that, I want to call the following function,
这是我们上周也看到的匿名函数。
and it's an anonymous function which we saw last week too.
在匿名函数中，我要做的是以下内容。
And what I'm going to do inside of this anonymous function is the following.
我要调用一个新函数，这是当今唯一的新JavaScript函数，
I'm going to call a new function, the only new JavaScript function today,
叫美元符号下划线得到。
called dollar sign underscore get.
这是jQuery dot get的简写形式，
This is shorthand notation for jQuery dot get,
但是，抱歉，美元符号dot get是jQuery dot get的简写。
but, sorry, dollar sign dot get is shorthand for jQuery dot get.
我将继续进行以下操作。
And I'm going to go ahead and get the following.
我将获得一个带有问号的斜杠搜索URL，后跟q等于，
I'm going to get a slash search URL with a question mark followed by q equals,
然后我将继续输入输入点的值
and then I'm going to go ahead and put input dot value.
因此请注意这一行代码，这个JavaScript字符串，
So notice with this line of code, this JavaScript string,
我有点用JavaScript代码动态构建
I'm kind of dynamically constructing in JavaScript code
我要请求的URL显示为斜杠搜索问题
the URL that I want to request shows from, slash search question
不论输入框的值是多少，标记q都等于
mark q equals, whatever the value of the input box
是用户输入了一些内容。
was that the user typed something into.
这个美元符号点获取功能的工作方式
And the way this dollar sign dot get function works
它支持所谓的回调。
is it supports what's called a callback.
回调是一个最终将成为
A callback is a function that will eventually be
在有您的答案时调用。
called when it has an answer for you.
这在网络上很重要。
And this is important on the web.
互联网有时可能很慢，而您
The internet can sometimes be slow, and you
可能想编写与另一台服务器联系的代码
might want to write code that contacts another server
就像我现在要去做。
like I'm about to do now.
该服务器可能很慢，或者互联网连接可能很慢，
And that server might be slow or the internet connection might be slow,
如果整个浏览器冻结，那将很烦人
and it would be annoying if your entire browser froze
当您等待并等待服务器的响应返回时。
while you waited and waited and waited for the server's response to come back.
如果您可以说，有了数据，那就更好了。
It's a lot nicer if you can say, when you have the data,
回电话，可以这么说，在电话上有点隐喻，
call me back, so to speak, sort of metaphorically on the phone,
通过调用此函数给我回电。
call me back by calling this function.
那我要调用什么功能呢？
So what function do I want it to call?
我希望它调用这个匿名函数
I want it to call this anonymous function that's
将一个名为shows的参数作为输入，
going to take as input an argument called shows,
但是我可以随便叫那个，我要去做。
but I could call that anything I want, and I'm going to do this.
我将创建一个HTML字符串
I'm going to create an HTML string that's
最初什么都没有，引用不带引号。
initially nothing, quote unquote.
然后，我将执行此操作，这是JavaScript中的for循环
I'm then going to do this, a for loop in JavaScript
让一个名为ID的变量等于显示中的任何ID
letting a variable called ID equal to whatever ID is in the shows that just
回到我身边，现在在这个for循环中，
came back to me, and now inside of this for loop,
让我继续并在此for循环内
let me go ahead and inside of this for loop
创建一个与show相同的标题，这也是
create a title that's equal to shows, which is again,
返回的数据是通过该回调返回的，因此
the data that came back on the, came back via that callback so
会说出点号，点号和分号，
to speak, shows dot ID dot title, and semicolon,
然后我要做HTML加等于引号取消引用列表项加标题
then I'm going to do HTML plus equals quote unquote list item plus title
加上报价取消报价的封闭列表项目。
plus quote unquote closed list item.
然后在这里，最后，我要做文档点查询选择器，引用
Then down here, lastly, I'm going to do document dot query selector, quote
取消引号ul，点内HTML即可获取HTML。
unquote ul, dot inner HTML gets HTML.
好吧，这绝对是最疯狂的事情
All right, this is definitely the craziest thing
到目前为止，我们已经完成了这项工作
we've done thus far today, and it's tying together
这么多不同的想法，更不用说新的语法了，在所有示例中，
so many different ideas, not to mention new syntax, so of all the examples,
如果一次过很多，不要太担心。
don't worry too much if this is just a lot at once.
现在的真正目的不是要介绍您
The goal really now is not to introduce you
该语法，以便您明天可以重复，但是
to this syntax so that you can repeat it tomorrow, but rather
我们在做什么的想法。
the idea of what we're doing.
那我们在做什么呢？
So what are we doing?
我们有一个带有文本输入的简单网页。
We have a simple web page with a text input.
我们有一个简单的网页，其中有一个无序列表，当前为空。
We've got a simple web page with an unordered list that's currently empty.
在此之下，我们包括了名为jQuery的第三方JavaScript库，
Below that, we're including this third party JavaScript library called jQuery,
哪一个Bootstrap也恰好用于其某些图形组件。
which Bootstrap also happens to use for some of its graphical components.
然后我首先有自己的JavaScript代码
Then I have my own JavaScript code that first
声明一个变量，该变量使我可以访问自己网页上的输入标签
declares a variable that gives me access to the input tag on my own webpage
上面几行。
a few lines above.
然后，我要使用这个花哨的功能美元符号
I'm then using this fancy function dollar sign
开始执行所谓的AJAX调用。
get to do what's called an AJAX call.
AJAX是指网页的功能
AJAX refers to the ability for a web page
以编程方式向服务器发出其他HTTP请求。
to make additional HTTP requests programmatically to a server.
允许的，这就是今天所有网站的方式
It is allowing, this is how all websites today
如果朋友刚刚在某个平台上给您发消息，则可以获取您的聊天消息。
get your chat messages if a friend just messaged you on some platform.
这就是您输入地址的方式，
It's how when you're typing in your address,
它可以根据全球范围内的地址自动填写您的地址
it can autocomplete your address based on the entire globe's
值得的地址。
worth of addresses.
这也是Google搜索自动完成功能的工作方式。
It's how Google search autocomplete works as well.
美元符号点get是jQuery内置的一个函数
Dollar sign dot get is a function built into jQuery that's
使用一些标准的JavaScript功能
using some standard JavaScript functionality that's
将允许我访问以斜杠搜索结尾的URL
going to allow me to visit the URL that ends with slash search
问号q等于人类输入的任何东西，
question mark q equals whatever the human typed in,
当响应准备就绪时，此匿名函数
and when the response is ready, this anonymous function
将被回电，并将被输入，
is going to get called back, and it's going to be handed an input,
一个叫做show的参数将等于这个东西。
an argument called shows that is going to equal this stuff.
这就是我的JavaScript函数将通过shows参数接收的内容。
This is what my JavaScript function is going to receive as its shows argument.
注意，它是一个列表或数组
And notice, it's a list or an array, inside
其中是带有两个键（ID和标题）的字典或对象的列表。
of which is a list of dictionaries or objects with two keys, ID, and title.
让我规定，这恰好是JavaScript中的语法
This, let me stipulate, happens to be the syntax in JavaScript
为了迭代这样的数据结构，
for iterating over such a data structure,
这恰好是JavaScript中的语法
and this happens to be the syntax in JavaScript
允许我创建一个接一个的行，另一个LI，另一个LI，
for allowing me to create one line after another, another LI, another LI,
使用串联将其附加到称为HTML的变量。
appending it using concatenation to this variable called HTML.
这最后一行代码对浏览器说，
And this very last line of code says to the browser,
去选择我那个UL并插入其内部HTML
go select me that UL and plug into its inner HTML
它的内容，我的变量的值。
the contents of it, the value of my variable.
现在，我的手指没有从句法上拧紧，让我继续
And now crossing my fingers I did not screw up syntactically, let me go ahead
并进行Flask运行，我仍然需要运行Flask，因为我在这里有一个后端。
and do Flask run, I still need to run Flask because I do have a backend here.
让我回到浏览器并重新加载斜线路由。
Let me go back to my browser and reload the slash route.
让我现在继续输入，O，F，该死。
Let me go ahead now and type in O, F, dammit.
哦，等等，那太慢了。
Oh wait, it was just slow.
所以请注意，到目前为止我输入的所有内容或到目前为止我所看到的所有内容
So notice, everything I've typed thus far or everything I'm seeing thus far
匹配单词off。
matches the word off.
如果我继续这个，办公室，让它搜索
And if I continue this, office, and let it search
让互联网做自己的事情，现在确实如此，
and let the internet do its thing, now indeed,
它被缩小为办公室比赛的清单。
it's been whittled down to a list of office matches.
再次注意，如果我转到“检查”标签，
And notice again if I go to the inspect tab,
打开“检查”下的“网络”标签，让我继续并输入Office，
open the network tab under inspect, let me go ahead and type in office,
请注意，在这里，我键入的每个击键都会触发，要执行的OFFICE，
notice here that every keystroke I typed triggered, O F F I C E to be executed,
触发了AJAX调用，即对服务器的HTTP调用。
triggered an AJAX call, that is an HTTP call to the server.
并请注意，如果我单击那里的最后一个，请向下滚动，
And notice that if I click on the last one there, scroll down,
我不仅会看到我的要求和回应，
I will see not only my request and my response,
但是如果我点击响应，我确实会看到这个大json
but if I click on the response, I'll indeed see this big json
所有数据的数组。
array of all of the data.
其实很不幸，它很慢，
And it's actually rather fortuitous that it was slow,
因为我们将以一个演示结尾。
because we were going to end with one demo.
例如，如果我好奇地知道，在室内
For instance, if I was curious to know, being indoors
一整天，天气如何，也许
all day, what the weather is like, I might maybe
在这儿打电话给布莱恩。
call Brian up on this here telephone.
[电话铃声]
[PHONE RINGING]
布莱恩：你好？
BRIAN: Hello?
DAVID J. MALAN：嗨，Brian，你知道今天外面的天气如何吗？
DAVID J. MALAN: Hi, Brian, do you know what the weather is like outside today?
布莱恩：我没来过一会儿，但我可以检查一下，
BRIAN: I haven't been outside in a little bit, but I can check,
我会给您回电。
and I will call you back.
DAVID J. MALAN：好的。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK.
并且请注意，如果我必须等他的电话会很烦
And notice it would be annoying if I had to wait on the phone for him
到外面去。
to go outside.
所以我要挂断电话，然后等他给我回电，
So I'm going to hang up, and I'm just going to wait for him to call me back,
这正是我的代码中正在发生的事情。
and that's exactly what's happening in my code.
当我将此匿名函数传递给此get函数时，
When I pass this anonymous function to this get function,
他们到达这里意味着HTTP获取，这是在告诉浏览器，
and they get here means HTTP get, this is telling the browser,
找到答案后，请调用此函数，
call this function once you have the answer,
就像希望布赖恩（Brian）即将回拨，甚至是回拨一样。
much like hopefully Brian's about to have the, and indeed, the call back.
你好。
Hello.
布莱恩：嗨。
BRIAN: Hi.
我抬头看天气。
I looked up the weather.
看来今天将是个轻快的秋天。
It looks like it's going to be a brisk fall day today.
DAVID J. MALAN：很好，非常感谢。
DAVID J. MALAN: Wonderful, well thank you so much.
CS50就是这样。
And that is it for CS50.
下次见。
We will see you all next time.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]